[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的。
This is CS50.
这是 CS50。
And this is already Week 8.
现在已经是第八周了。
But this is a CS50 bingo board from one of your classmates at Yale, Shoshannah,
但这是你耶鲁大学同学 Shoshannah 送来的一个 CS50 宾果盘，
kindly sent this to us.
她好心地把它寄给了我们。
And she's apparently been taking close notice of certain expressions
而且她显然一直密切关注着我经常说的某些表达方式，
that I apparently tend to say quite a bit.
有些我意识到了，但不是所有。
Some of which I'm aware of, but not all of them.
其中一些我意识到了，但不是所有。
And the idea here as she described it is that if and when
她描述的想法是，如果我
I say any of these expressions on the screen,
在屏幕上说了这些表达中的任何一个，
you can draw a line through that box.
你就可以在那格上画一条线。
And if you get five in a row, you win a fabulous prize.
如果你连续得到五个，你就会获得一个很棒的奖品。
It seems only fair, then, if we maybe give away some cookies today
这样看来，如果我今天连续说了五次，那我们也许应该送点饼干
if and when I actually do say five such things in a row.
如果我今天连续说了五次，那我们也许应该送点饼干。
Perhaps it'll be all the more motivation to keep a rapt ear against everything
也许这会更有动力让我们专心聆听今天我们要谈论的一切。
we're talking about today.
So if and when that happens, feel free to just yell out bingo.
所以，如果真的发生了，请随意喊出宾果。
And then please see Carter during the break or after class for adjudication.
然后请在下课或课后找卡特进行判定。
All right.
好的。
So today, ultimately though, Week 8 is about the internet and, in turn,
所以，今天，虽然说到底，第八周是关于互联网，并且反过来，
how it works and, in fact, how we can start building software on top of it.
是关于它是如何工作的，事实上，是关于我们如何开始在其之上构建软件。
So up until now, of course, we've experimented with Scratch,
当然，到目前为止，我们一直在用 Scratch 实验，
spent quite a bit of time with C, only really
花了不少时间学习 C，只是真正地
spent a week plus so far on Python, and about the same on SQL.
花了不止一周的时间学习 Python，在 SQL 上也花了差不多时间。
But ultimately, we're going to come full circle next week
但说到底，我们将在下周回到起点
and tie all of those languages together.
并将所有这些语言联系在一起。
But we're going to do it in the context of the web.
但我们将在 web 的背景下进行。
And in fact to do that, we're going to introduce
实际上，为了做到这一点，我们将介绍
three different languages today, but only one of which
三种不同的语言，但其中只有一种
is a proper programming language.
是真正的编程语言。
The other two are more about presentation, markup languages,
另外两种更多的是关于演示，标记语言，
so to speak.
可以这么说。
And those languages are HTML and CSS, commonly used in conjunction.
这些语言是 HTML 和 CSS，它们通常一起使用。
Some of you might have done this middle school, high school even, if you ever
你们中有些人可能在中学，甚至高中做过，如果你曾经
made a personal website of sorts.
制作过一个个人网站。
And JavaScript, a programming language that
还有 JavaScript，一种编程语言，它
is very commonly used in the context of browsers
在浏览器的环境中非常常见地被使用
to make interfaces that are all the more interactive.
来制作更具交互性的界面。
But it can also be used server side.
但它也可以用在服务器端。
And what you'll find that is our goal this week,
你会发现，这是我们这周的目标，
like last week, like two weeks ago is really to teach you ultimately
就像上周，就像两周前一样，真正地教你们
how to program, how to program procedurally
如何编程，如何进行过程式编程，
and also with elements of what we'll call functional
以及我们所说的函数式编程的元素，
programming, object-oriented programming,
面向对象编程，
concepts that you'll explore more if you pursue more programming or higher level
这些概念，如果你继续学习更多编程或更高层次
classes.
的课程，就会进一步探索。
But at the end of the day, you will exit this class
但说到底，你们将会走出这堂课
having learned how to program, particularly
已经学会了如何编程，尤其是在
in a context that's very much in vogue nowadays, be it for the web
当今非常流行的语境中，无论是 web
or be it for mobile devices.
还是移动设备。
And all of the ideas thus far will be applicable as we now
到目前为止，所有这些想法都将适用，因为我们现在
begin to build on top of the internet.
开始在互联网的基础上进行构建。
So what is it?
那么，它是什么呢？
So back in the late '60s and 1970s, it wasn't much of anything.
所以，早在 60 年代后期和 70 年代，它并没有什么特别之处。
This is an early diagram depicting a few access points
这是一张早期图表，描绘了美国西海岸的一些接入点，
on the West Coast of the United States, which represents
代表了最初被称为 ARPANET 的东西。
what was originally called ARPANET.
And this was a project from the US Department of Defense
这是一个来自美国国防部的项目，
to begin to internetwork computers by enabling
开始将计算机互联起来，方法是使它们能够
them to exchange data using what's now known as packets,
通过使用现在被称为数据包的方式交换数据，
packets of information back and forth.
来回传递信息包。
It wasn't too long before East Coast was eventually connected
不久之后，东海岸也最终连接了起来，
through MIT, Harvard, and others.
通过麻省理工学院、哈佛大学等。
And nowadays, fast forward to present day,
而现在，快进到今天，
just a few decades later, everything, it would seem,
仅仅几十年后，一切似乎
is somehow interconnected, either with wires or wirelessly.
都以某种方式相互连接，无论是通过有线还是无线。
But how do you actually get data from any of these points
但是，你如何真正地从这些点中的任何一个
to any of these other points or all of the points that now exist?
传输到这些其他点中的任何一个或现在存在的所有点呢？
Well, let me stipulate, for today's purposes,
好吧，为了今天目的，
that the world nowadays is filled with routers,
我要说明的是，当今世界充满了路由器，
simply computers, servers whose purpose in life is to route information from
仅仅是电脑，服务器，它们存在的目的就是从
left to right, top to bottom, geographically,
左到右，从上到下，在地理位置上，
so to speak, to just get data from point A to point B.
可以这么说，只是将数据从 A 点传输到 B 点。
But typically, you're not going to have a direct connection between points A
但通常情况下，你不会在 A 点和 B 点之间有直接连接。你可能会有 C、D、E。换句话说，
and B. You might have C, D, E. In other words,
你可能会有 C、D、E。换句话说，
you might have many different servers between you and someone else.
你可能会有许多不同的服务器在你和其他人之间。
So if you have a friend at Stanford University
所以，如果你有一个朋友在斯坦福大学，
and you simply send them an email, well, odds
而你只是给他们发送了一封电子邮件，那么，很有可能
are that email is going to be put inside what we're soon going to call a packet.
这封电子邮件将被放置在一个我们很快就会称之为数据包的东西里面。
And that packet might actually pass through the hands, so to speak,
而这个数据包实际上可能会经过，可以这么说，
of any number of routers, typically more than one or two,
任何数量的路由器，通常不止一个或两个，
but typically fewer than 30 such routers.
但通常少于 30 个这样的路由器。
And it's up to the IT administrators of the world to figure out how
而如何在这个服务器之间传输数据，这是全球 IT 管理员需要解决的问题。
to route data between these servers.
And we have software nowadays that dynamically figures out the best path.
现在我们拥有软件，可以动态地找出最佳路径。
It's not necessarily a straight line, as it
它不一定是直线，就像
might be in the world of mathematics.
数学领域一样。
But hopefully, it's the fastest way to get data from point A to point B.
但希望这是从 A 点到 B 点传输数据最快的方式。
So the teaching fellows, thanks to Zoom, kindly put together in years
所以，助教们，由于 Zoom 的帮助，在过去的几年里，他们好心地把这个演示放在一起。
past a demonstration of this whereby each of the teaching fellows or TAs
that you see on the screen here consider representing a router, that
你在这里屏幕上看到的每个人都代表一个路由器，也就是说
is a device on the internet that its purpose in life
它是互联网上的一种设备，它存在于世上的目的
is to get data, North, South.
就是接收数据，从北到南，从南到北。
East, or West, between two points ultimately.
无论东西，最终都只是两点之间。
And if we assume that Phyllis, for instance,
如果我们假设，比如，菲利斯
wants to send a packet of information to Brian up here at top left,
想要把一包信息发送给位于左上角的布莱恩，
from bottom right, it turns out that by design the internet can send that data
从右下角开始，结果表明，互联网可以通过设计将这些数据
over any number of routes.
通过任意数量的路线发送。
It can go up and to the left.
它可以向上再向左走。
It can go left and then up.
它可以先向左再向上走。
It can double back a little bit.
它可以稍微回退一点。
Again, it's not necessarily a straight line.
再说一次，它不一定是一条直线。
And this is a feature, not a bug.
而这是一种特性，而不是错误。
The intent of the internet early on was to be
互联网的最初目标是
able to route around downed servers.
能够绕过宕机的服务器。
So if one router is overwhelmed, or if one router is offline,
所以如果一台路由器超负荷，或者一台路由器离线，
the internet can still adapt dynamically and just route it some other direction.
互联网仍然可以动态地调整，并将其路由到其他方向。
So here, for instance, is one representative route
所以这里，例如，是一条我们的数据包可能经过的典型路线
that our packets might take.
我们的数据包可能会经过。
Thanks to the team.
感谢团队。
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[古典音乐播放]
So my thanks to the team.
所以我要感谢团队。
And if you've ever used Zoom before, you know
如果你曾经使用过 Zoom，你会知道
that you don't often see exactly the same layout that someone else sees.
你不会经常看到与其他人看到的完全相同的布局。
So it took us forever to actually get that right.
所以我们花了很长时间才真正做到这一点。
Because no one actually knew to whom they were necessarily passing it.
因为没有人真正知道他们是在把信息传递给谁。
But if all of those TFs and TAs represent routers, well, what is it
但如果所有这些 TF 和 TA 代表路由器，那么，他们传递的是什么呢？
they were handing?
他们传递的是什么呢？
What is it that Phyllis wanted to send to Brian?
菲利斯想要发送给布莱恩的是什么呢？
Well, I've called it generically a packet.
好吧，我把它通俗地称为数据包。
And a packet is a generic term for some amount of information.
数据包是一个泛指，指一定量的信息。
But it's kind of analogous to an envelope in the real world.
但这有点类似于现实世界中的信封。
If you're still in the habit of sending letters or postal mail,
如果你仍然习惯于发送信件或邮政邮件，
you typically put your information inside of an envelope such as this.
你通常会把你的信息放在这样的信封里。
And then you hand it off to the mail carrier,
然后你把它交给邮递员，
or you drop it into the mail box.
或者你把它扔进邮箱。
And then humans, in the case of the Postal Service,
然后人类，以邮政服务为例，
actually get it from point A to point B.
实际上把它从 A 点送到 B 点。
But odds are it goes through different cities, different countries, even.
但很有可能它会经过不同的城市，甚至不同的国家。
So you can think of that as roughly analogous to these things called
所以你可以把这看作大致类似于这些被称为
routers.
路由器的东西。
But the technical term for what it is the TFs were just doing
但是 TF 们所做的事情的技术术语是
is they were implementing a protocol that we know as TCP/IP.
他们正在实现一个我们所知的协议，叫做 TCP/IP。
And this is actually probably a pair of acronyms
这实际上可能是一对首字母缩略词
that you've probably seen, maybe on your Mac, PC, or phone,
你可能在你的 Mac、PC 或手机上见过，
even if you haven't really thought much about it.
即使你没有真正想过它。
But this is actually a pair of protocols, two protocols
但这实际上是一对协议，两个协议
that the internet generally uses nowadays and has
互联网目前通常使用，并且已经
for some time to get data from point A to point B.
使用了一段时间来将数据从 A 点传送到 B 点。
And let's consider each of these halves so you
让我们考虑这两个部分中的每一个，以便你
have a sense of what it is the internet is doing when you do send an email
了解互联网在你发送电子邮件时所做的事情
or do anything else.
或者做其他事情。
Well, first, IP stands for internet protocol.
首先，IP 代表互联网协议。
And you've probably even heard this in popular media, since a lot of humans
你可能甚至在流行媒体中听到过这个词，因为很多人类
are indeed familiar with this notion of IP.
确实熟悉 IP 这个概念。
And they associate it typically with IP addresses, as you might.
他们通常将其与 IP 地址联系起来，就像你一样。
So I'll stipulate for today that every computer, every internet work
因此，今天我将规定，世界上每台电脑，每个互联网工作
device in the world has an IP address, an internet protocol
设备都有一个 IP 地址，一个互联网协议
address similar in spirit to buildings in the physical world.
地址，类似于现实世界中的建筑物。
Here we are at 45 Quincy Street, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 02138, USA.
我们位于美国马萨诸塞州剑桥市昆西街 45 号。
That is a unique string, theoretically, that uniquely identifies this building.
理论上，这是一个独特的字符串，它唯一地标识了这栋建筑。
Similarly, in the world of computers, we use a simpler mechanism, just
类似地，在计算机的世界里，我们使用一个更简单的机制，只是
numbers of this format that uniquely represent computers.
这种格式的数字，它们唯一地代表了计算机。
Now that's a bit of a white lie.
现在，这有点像善意的谎言。
Because there's actually a way to share IP addresses.
因为实际上有一种方法可以共享 IP 地址。
And within your home, often within your dorm, or your apartment,
在你家，通常是在你的宿舍或你的公寓里，
you'll actually have what appears to be the same IP address as your roommates
你实际上会有看起来与你的室友一样的 IP 地址
or family members.
或家人。
But for now, let's keep things simple and assume
但现在，让我们保持简单，并假设
that every Mac, PC, and phone in the world
世界上每台 Mac、PC 和手机
has a unique IP address that's formatted like this, number dot number
都有一个唯一的 IP 地址，格式是这样的：数字点数字
dot number dot number.
点数字点数字。
Each of these number signs represents a value between 0 and 255.
这些数字符号中的每一个都代表 0 到 255 之间的值。
And even though we haven't played around with this kind of arithmetic
即使我们有一段时间没有玩过这种算术
in some time, if each of these placeholders is 0 through 255,
有一段时间了，如果这些占位符中的每一个都是 0 到 255，
how many bits are being used to represent each number?
每个数字要用多少位来表示？
Think back to Week 0, Week 1.
回顾一下第 0 周、第 1 周。
Yeah, so 8, in fact.
是的，实际上是 8。
8 bits in total, or 1 byte.
总共 8 位，或 1 字节。
So IP addresses are generally 4 bytes or 32 bits.
所以 IP 地址通常是 4 字节或 32 位。
And the other math we kept doing early on is if you've got 4 bytes or 32 bits,
而我们早期一直在做的另一个数学问题是，如果你有 4 字节或 32 位，
that's a maximum of 2 to the 32nd power total number of values.
那么，最大值的数量就是 2 的 32 次方。
How many IP addresses can you have, it would seem, maximally in the world?
似乎，世界上最多可以有多少个 IP 地址？
Enough.
足够了。
Actually, not enough would be a better answer nowadays.
实际上，现在不够才是更好的答案。
But roughly, 4 billion was the rough math that we typically
但粗略地说，40 亿是我们通常
did anytime 2 to the 32 was involved.
在涉及 2 的 32 次方时所做的粗略计算。
But it turns out with all of the humans, and all of the devices, servers,
但事实证明，随着所有的人类，以及所有设备，服务器，
clients, PCs, Macs, phones, and everything else,
客户端、PC、Mac、手机以及其他一切，
internet of things devices nowadays, even 4 billion is not quite enough.
如今，即使是 40 亿也不够。
So the world is gradually in the process of transitioning
所以，世界正在逐步过渡
from this format, which is technically IPv4, version 4, to IPv6.
从这种格式，即技术上称为 IPv4，版本 4，到 IPv6。
And in the world of IPv6, we've actually bumped things up from 32 bits
在 IPv6 的世界里，我们实际上已经从 32 位
to 128 bits, which is a crazy number of possible permutations, 2 to the 128.
增加到了 128 位，这是一种可能的排列方式的疯狂数量，2 的 128 次方。
So you'll gradually see that over time.
所以，随着时间的推移，你会逐渐看到这种情况。
But those are a lot messier of a format because there's so much larger.
但是，这些格式要混乱得多，因为它们要大得多。
So we'll use the more commonplace ones IPv4.
因此，我们将使用更常见的 IPv4。
Now just to get into the weeds briefly, this is some ASCII art.
现在，为了简要地深入探讨，这是一些 ASCII 艺术。
That is, someone wrote this up decades ago in a text
也就是说，几十年前有人用文本
file to represent the layout of one of these packets.
文件来表示这些数据包之一的布局。
So think of this as, like, the digital representation of this here envelope.
所以把它想象成，比如，这个信封的数字表示。
And even though we won't get into the weeds of what this represents,
虽然我们不会深入探讨其代表的含义，
up here you just have some values saying that this is byte 0.
这里只是一些值，表示这是字节 0。
This is byte 10.
这是字节 10。
This is byte 20.
这是字节 20。
And this is byte 32, but 0 indexed.
这是字节 32，但从 0 开始索引。
So that is to say that this is just kind of an artist's rendition of a grid
也就是说，这只是艺术家对网格的演绎
of bits, top to bottom, left to right.
由比特组成，从上到下，从左到右。
And what's going to be interesting for us today is not most of these fields.
而今天对我们来说有趣的是，不是这些字段中的大多数。
There's a whole bunch of information that's encapsulated inside
在这些数据包的内部封装了大量的信息。
of any one of these packets.
But we'll focus initially on these two, source address and destination address.
但我们最初将关注这两个，源地址和目标地址。
Maybe the most important thing IP does is
也许 IP 做的最重要的事情是
it standardizes what you put, so to speak,
它规范了你在这些信封上放什么，可以说是
on the outside of these envelopes.
在这些信封的外面。
It says that every computer is going to have a unique address of that form,
它说每台电脑都将拥有这种形式的唯一地址，
something dot something dot something dot something.
某某某某。
And so just like in the real world, if I want
所以就像在现实世界中，如果我想
to send this packet from Phyllis to Brian,
将这个数据包从菲利斯发送给布莱恩，
and suppose that Brian's IP address is a number,
假设布莱恩的 IP 地址是一个数字，
like, very simply 1.2.3.4, what Phyllis would do
比如，非常简单的 1.2.3.4，菲利斯会怎么做
is put that IP address in the middle of this envelope,
就是把那个 IP 地址放到这个信封的中间，
just like you would address a letter in the real world.
就像你在现实世界中写信一样。
But so that Brian could reply to her, if only to confirm receipt,
但为了让布莱恩能回复她，即使只是确认收到，
she's also going to put in the top left of this envelope,
她还要在这个信封的左上角放上，
virtually, her own IP address, which for the sake of discussion
虚拟地，她自己的 IP 地址，为了讨论，
is maybe 5.6.7.8.
可能是 5.6.7.8。
In practice, they won't be as pretty as that.
实际上，它们不会像那样漂亮。
But it's the general idea.
但这是基本的想法。
So you have a source address from which it's coming and a destination |
所以，你有一个来源地址，它来自这里，还有一个目标地址，
to which it's going.
它要到那里去。
And that's what IP does.
这就是 IP 做的事情。
It sort of standardizes, in addition to a bunch of other numbers and values
除了这些信封里必须有的其他数字和值外，它还规范了
that need to be in this envelope, too.
这些信封里必须有的其他数字和值外，它还规范了
It really just mandates that computers on the internet minimally
它实际上只是要求互联网上的电脑至少
provide a source address and a destination
提供源地址和目标地址
address so that the envelope can get from point A to point B.
地址，以便这个信封可以从 A 点到达 B 点。
But that's not quite enough.
但这还不够。
Because it turns out, and if you saw the bloopers from the TFs' Zoom
事实证明，如果你看到了 TFs 的 Zoom
session there, you would see that it's very common not only for humans
会议上的花絮，你会发现，不仅对于人类来说
to physically drop an envelope like that,
实际上丢掉这样的信封是很常见的，
and frankly, even in the real world, for mail carriers
而且坦白地说，即使在现实世界中，对于邮递员来说
to lose mail occasionally, undelivered to recipients.
偶尔丢失邮件，无法送达收件人也是很常见的。
And so it turns out that IP alone is not enough to guarantee delivery
事实证明，仅仅 IP 还不够保证投递成功
because sometimes the packet just might not get to its destination.
因为有时数据包可能无法到达目的地。
More technically, that might happen because the router is overwhelmed.
更准确地说，这可能是因为路由器不堪重负。
It only has so much memory.
它的内存有限。
It only has so fast a CPU.
它的 CPU 速度也有限。
And if it's receiving way too many packets
如果它接收到的数据包太多
because so many people are on the internet at some moment in time,
因为在某个时间点有太多人上网，
well, it might just kind of get overwhelmed and metaphorically
那么，它可能会不堪重负，从比喻意义上说
drop certain packets in the sense that there's just not
丢弃一些数据包，因为它的内存不足以跟上流量。
enough room in its memory to keep up with the traffic.
So the effect for the sender is that the packet just doesn't get through.
所以，对于发送者来说，数据包就无法通过了。
And so there's this other protocol, TCP, that humans typically
因此，就有了另一种协议，TCP，人类通常
use in conjunction with IP via their Macs,
通过他们的 Mac、
PCs, and phones that does a couple of other things for us.
PC 和手机与 IP 结合使用，为我们做了一些其他事情。
One, it guarantees delivery, or really "guarantees" delivery.
第一，它保证投递，或者说是“保证”投递。
And it does that actually by doing this.
它实际上是通过这样做来实现的。
It does that by having Phyllis write on the outside of the envelope not
它让菲利斯在信封外面写上
just the source address and destination address,
不仅仅是源地址和目标地址，
but also what we'll call a sequence number.
还有我们将要称之为的序列号。
So, for instance, this would be packet one of two
例如，这将是菲利斯可能发送给布莱恩的两个数据包中的第一个。
that she might be sending to Brian.
So maybe in, like, the memo field, she could write one of two.
所以，也许在备忘录栏里，她可以写上“两个中的一个”。
And then, if she happens to send a second packet to Brian,
然后，如果她碰巧向布莱恩发送了第二个数据包，
she might write similarly a source address and destination address.
她可能会类似地写上源地址和目标地址。
But she might write two out of two.
但她可能会写上“两个中的两个”。
Because now, logically, if Brian only gets one of these,
因为现在，逻辑上，如果布莱恩只收到其中一个，
that sequence number is enough information for him
这个序列号对他来说就足够了
to know wait a minute, I need to ask Phyllis to resend
他知道，等等，我需要请菲利斯重新发送
number one, or maybe resend number two.
第一个，或者可能重新发送第二个。
If both of them don't get through, I mean, honestly,
如果这两个都没有通过，我的意思是，说真的，
that's probably when Phyllis hits reload or resends the email.
那可能是菲利斯点击重新加载或重新发送电子邮件的时候。
But in general, these sequence numbers help with guaranteeing delivery.
但总的来说，这些序列号有助于保证投递成功。
But if Phyllis and Brian are each representing computers in this story,
但如果菲利斯和布莱恩在故事中分别代表电脑，
they can be doing different things.
他们可以做不同的事情。
They can be doing email, chat, video conferencing, direct messaging,
他们可以发邮件、聊天、视频会议、直接消息，
or any number of services on the internet nowadays.
或者现在互联网上的任何服务。
So TCP gives us one other feature, namely port numbers.
所以 TCP 给我们提供了另一个功能，即端口号。
Because when Brian receives that envelope, assuming he's
因为当布莱恩收到那个信封时，假设他确实是一台电脑，
indeed a computer, how does he know that what's
确实是一台电脑，他怎么知道那个信封里的东西
inside of that envelope is indeed an email, versus a direct message,
是不是一封电子邮件，而不是一条直接消息，
versus a little bit of video, versus sound, versus any other type of media.
而不是一段视频，而不是一段声音，而不是其他任何类型的媒体。
Ideally, the outside of the envelope would have a bit of a clue for him
理想情况下，信封外面应该有一些线索告诉他
that indicates this is the type of data herein.
这表明这里面的数据类型是什么。
Or more specifically, this is the program, really,
或者更确切地说，这才是真正应该打开这个信封的程序，电子邮件程序，视频会议程序
that should open this envelope, the email program, the video conferencing
应该打开这个信封的程序，电子邮件程序，视频会议程序
program, or whatever else.
或任何其他程序。
So what Phyllis would typically do on the outside of this envelope lastly,
所以，菲利斯通常会在信封外面最后写上
in addition to the source address, destination address,
除了源地址，目的地址
and the memo field, the sequence number, she would also write a port number.
以及备忘录字段，序列号，她还会写一个端口号。
And it turns out two of the most common port numbers in the world of TCP
事实证明，在 TCP 世界中，两个最常见的端口号是
are these two, 80, which represents the web.
这两个：80，代表网络。
That is to say, something called HTTP, more on that today,
也就是说，某种叫做 HTTP 的东西，今天我们会详细了解它，
or HTTPS, which most everyone nowadays probably knows means secure,
或者 HTTPS，如今几乎所有人都知道它意味着安全，
so it's some kind of secure version of HTTP.
所以它是一种安全版的 HTTP。
And that number happens to be 443.
而那个数字恰好是 443。
There's no mathematical significance of these.
这些数字之间没有数学上的意义。
They're just kind of arbitrary.
它们只是任意选定的。
But humans decades ago decided to standardize on these numbers.
但几十年前的人们决定将这些数字标准化。
So what it means for Phyllis is that on the outside of her envelope,
所以，对于菲利斯来说，这意味着，在她信封的外面
she should generally put a colon after the destination
她通常应该在目的地后面加一个冒号
address and then the number of the port that she wants to receive this packet.
地址，然后是她想要接收这个数据包的端口号。
So if she's actually not sending an email, but maybe making a web request,
所以，如果她实际上不是在发送电子邮件，而是在发起一个网络请求，
and Brian is a web server and Phyllis is a web browser,
而布莱恩是一个 Web 服务器，菲利斯是一个 Web 浏览器，
she would write colon 80.
她就会写冒号 80。
Or if she's using HTTPS securely, we would change that 80 to a 443.
或者，如果她使用的是安全的 HTTPS，我们就会把 80 改成 443。
There's other stuff on the outside of that envelope.
信封外面还有其他东西。
In fact, just like with IP, there might be fields that look like this.
事实上，就像 IP 一样，可能会有看起来像这样的字段。
But just to give you a sense of this, which is a TCP packet,
但为了让你对这个 TCP 数据包有一个概念
you'll see that indeed sequence numbers are actually really big.
你会发现，序列号实际上非常大。
They use all 32 bits of this part of the picture, which
它们使用了图片中这部分的全部 32 位，这意味着
is to say that generally computers are sending way
一般来说，计算机发送的不仅仅是一个或两个数据包。
more than one packet or two.
它们可能发送数十个、数百个、甚至数千个数据包
They might be sending dozens, hundreds, thousands
取决于数据的大小。
even, depending on the size of the data in question.
其中还有一些其他功能，包括
And there's some other features therein, including
源端口和目标端口。
source port and destination port.
目标端口就是我之前提到的 80 或 443。
Destination port is the 80 or the 443 that I mentioned earlier.
但长话短说，菲利斯也可以选择一个源端口，以唯一地
But long story short, Phyllis also gets to pick a source port to uniquely
识别这个特定的请求。
identify this particular request.
但我们下次再谈这个。
But more on that another time.
现在，只需要知道 TCP 是互联网用来从 A 点
For now, just know that TCP is the pair of protocols
到 B 点获取数据的两套协议。IP 标准化了地址的工作方式。
that the internet uses to get data from point A
而 TCP 使用那些序列号保证数据传送
to point B. IP standardizes how the addresses work.
并帮助服务器同时完成多个任务，帮助它们进行多路复用
And TCP guarantees delivery with those sequence numbers
可以这么说，在电子邮件、网络、视频会议中
and also helps the servers do more than one thing, helps them multiplex,
通过使用那些端口号。
so to speak, among email, web, video conferencing
所以，归根结底，即使现在，课程已经进行了几周，
by using those port numbers.
一切都归结为 0 和 1，或者换句话说，数字，
So at the end of the day, everything, even now, weeks into the class,
就像我们在这个例子中所考虑的那样。
it all boils down somehow to zeros and ones, or in turn, numbers,
关于这些构成要素，你们有什么问题吗？
as we might think of them in this case.
有什么问题吗？
Questions on any of these building blocks thus far?
没有？
Questions on any of these?
好的。
No?
信封外面只是一些任意的数字，1，2，
All right.
3，4，5，6，7，8。
Well, on the outside of this envelope are just some arbitrary numbers, 1, 2,
很明显，这并不是你和我在平时习惯输入的东西。
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
比如，当我们实际访问网站时，我和你
That's obviously not what you and I are in the habit of typing.
通常会习惯输入 harvard.edu，或 yale.edu，
When we actually visit websites, for instance, you and I
或 google.com，或类似的东西，也就是所谓的域名。
are generally in the habit of typing harvard.edu, or yale.edu,
但你的 Mac，你的 PC，最终必须
or google.com, or the like, otherwise known as domain names.
用实际的 IP 地址来识别那些虚拟信封，也就是数据包。
But your Mac, your PC has to, at the end of the day,
在那些我们屏幕上显示的图片中，没有空间存放单词、英语字母。
address those virtual envelopes, AKA packets, with actual IP addresses.
它只有 32 位，这里也有 32 位。
There is no room for words, letters of the English alphabet in those pictures
所以，在互联网上，还有另一种类型的服务器。
that we showed on the screen.
这种服务器不像路由器，路由器负责将信息从 A 点路由到 B 点，
It's just 32 bits, here 32 bits here.
还有另一种类型的服务器，它们遍布各个地方，坦率地说，
So it turns out, on the internet, there's another type of server.
在你家、校园、互联网上的公司
That, unlike routers, which route information from point A to point B,
更广义地说，在互联网上被称为 DNS 服务器，域名系统服务器。
there's another type of server that are all over the place, frankly,
那么这些东西是做什么的呢？
in your home, on campus, in a company on the internet
这只是互联网上的一种服务器类型，其生命中的目标
more broadly, known as DNS servers, domain name system servers.
就是回答以下形式的问题：这个域名的 IP 地址是什么？
So what do these things do?
例如，如果你打开你的浏览器
This is just a type of server on the internet whose purpose in life
在你的 Mac、PC 或手机上，输入
is to answer questions of the form, what is the IP address for this domain name.
harvard.edu 然后按下回车，你的设备的设计目的
So for instance, if you do pull up your browser
就是向校园里、你的移动运营商网络里、你的公寓或宿舍网络里的某个本地 DNS 服务器询问：
on your Mac or PC or your phone, you type
harvard.edu 或者 yale.edu 的 IP 地址是什么？
in harvard.edu and hit Enter, what your device is designed to do
无论你实际输入了什么，希望附近有一个 DNS 服务器能够用以下形式的数字地址进行回复
is to ask some local DNS server on campus, on your mobile carrier's
something dot something dot something dot something。
network, on your apartment or dorm's network, what is the IP
这就是你的计算机、你的设备实际上将在虚拟信封外面使用的数字。
address of harvard.edu, or yale.edu?
所以，你可以将 DNS 服务器视为
Whatever you actually typed in, hopefully there
符合我们一直坚持的模型，这个模型就是字典的概念，
is a nearby DNS server that will respond with a numeric address of the form
或者更确切地说，是哈希表的概念，在 DNS 服务器内部
something dot something dot something dot something.
本质上就是一个字典，一个两列的电子表格或数据库表格，
And that's the number that your computer,
如果你愿意的话。
your device will actually use on the outside of that virtual envelope.
在一列中是域名，harvard.edu、yale.edu、google.com。
So you can think of DNS servers, honestly,
在右边一列，也就是右边的列
as fitting the model that we keep coming back to, this notion of a dictionary,
只是相应的 IP 地址。
or a hash table, more specifically, whereby inside of a DNS server
就是这样。
is essentially a dictionary, a two column spreadsheet or database table,
技术上来说，它们通常不只是被称为域名，
if you will.
而是被称为域名系统，
And in one column are domain names, harvard.edu, yale.edu, google.com.
也就是 DNS 服务器，它们
On the right-hand side, right-hand column
通常会存储域名，
are just the corresponding IP addresses.
以便在网络中使用。
And that's it.
这就是 DNS 服务器的作用。
To be technical, if they're not generally called just domain names,
它们将域名映射到对应的 IP 地址，
they're called domain name system servers, or DNS servers.
反之亦然。
That's the technical name.
这就是 DNS 服务器的用处。
But I think you'll agree, these two columns,
所以，这些 DNS 服务器的作用就是存储这些映射关系。
what they're doing really is storing this mapping,
对于大多数互联网用户来说，他们并不知道这些服务器的存在，
and for most internet users, they don't know they're even there.
但实际上，它们一直在后台运行，
But they're actually running behind the scenes,
并且对于我们能够访问互联网来说至关重要。
and they're critical to us being able to visit websites.
这就是 DNS 服务器背后的机制。
That's the mechanism behind DNS servers.
谢谢大家。
Thanks, everyone.
technically, it's a fully qualified domain name.
从技术上来说，它是一个完全限定的域名。
More on that another time.
我们下次再聊这个。
But domain names as we know them, generally have different parts.
但我们所知的域名通常包含不同的部分。
And we'll soon see how to tease them apart beyond the usual.
我们很快就会看到如何将它们拆开，而不是像往常那样。
Questions though, on what DNS server's purpose in life is
不过，我想问一下，DNS 服务器的职责是什么
or how this might work?
或者它是如何工作的？
No.
没有。
All right.
好的。
So how does your Mac, how does your PC, how does your phone
那么你的 Mac，你的 PC，你的手机是如何
know what these IP addresses are?
知道这些 IP 地址的呢？
Well, they don't come from the manufacturer this way.
嗯，它们不是以这种方式从制造商那里获得的。
And there's this whole hierarchy in the world of DNS servers
在 DNS 服务器的世界里存在着一个完整的层次结构
such that your phone, your Mac, your PC, will generally
使得你的手机，你的 Mac，你的 PC 通常会
ask the nearest DNS server, which is usually owned by your internet service
询问最近的 DNS 服务器，该服务器通常归你的互联网服务提供商所有
provider at home, in your apartment, or by your university or by your company.
在家，在你的公寓里，或者在你的大学或公司里。
But it's a hierarchical system.
但这是一个分层系统。
And it's kind of a recursive design.
它是一种递归设计。
In that if that local DNS server does not have the answer,
如果该本地 DNS 服务器没有答案，
it's going to ask someone bigger, more important than it.
它就会询问比它更大，更重要的其他人。
If that one doesn't know, it might ask someone, again, recursively for it.
如果那个人也不知道，它可能会递归地询问另一个人。
And throughout the world, there's a finite number
在全世界范围内，有一个有限的数字
of what are called root servers that essentially know about all the dot
被称为根服务器，它们基本上知道所有点
coms in the world, all of the dot edus in the world, all
coms 在世界上，所有 dot edus 在世界上，所有
of the dot whatever is in the world.
dot whatever 在世界上。
And so someone, at the end of the day, knows about those systems.
所以最终，有人会了解这些系统。
And in fact, if you've ever bought, or in the future might buy a domain name,
事实上，如果你曾经购买过，或者将来可能会购买域名，
part of that process is paying someone to associate an IP address for you
该过程的一部分是付钱给某人，将一个 IP 地址与你将实际使用的服务器关联起来
with the actual server that you're going to actually be using.
与你将实际使用的服务器关联起来。
So your final projects, for instance, in CS50, it's sometimes common for folks
例如，在 CS50 中，你的最终项目，人们有时会
to actually buy for personal use their own domain name
为了个人使用而购买自己的域名
for a few dollars a year, typically.
通常每年只需几美元。
So you're sort of renting it more than you're buying it.
所以你更像是租用它，而不是购买它。
But among the steps you'll go through if you ever
但是，如果你曾经
do that is to essentially inform the world what will be the IP address or IP
这样做，你本质上是在通知全世界，你的 IP 地址或 IP 地址将是什么
addresses of your particular domain name that you've
你所购买的特定域名的 IP 地址，
bought for, say, that calendar year.
比如说，是在那一历年。
All right.
好的。
So how does all this get started?
那么这一切是如何开始的呢？
Well, back in the day, when you arrived on campus here at Yale, anyone,
嗯，在过去，当你在耶鲁大学的校园里时，任何人，
or in the world, you would actually configure your Mac or PC
或者在世界上，你实际上会配置你的 Mac 或 PC
to know the IP addresses of your nearest router, of your nearest DNS server.
以了解你最近的路由器和 DNS 服务器的 IP 地址。
So literally, someone would come to your home
所以实际上，过去，当人们注册互联网服务时，有人会来到你家
back in the day when signing up for internet service
来到你家
and configure your Mac or PC for you.
为你配置你的 Mac 或 PC。
Of course, nowadays I don't remember anyone really touching my computer
当然，现在我记不清有人真正碰过我的电脑了
recently to configure it for me.
最近来为我配置它。
It all seems to happen automatically.
这一切似乎都是自动发生的。
And indeed, there's this other type of server now in the world,
事实上，现在世界上还有另一种类型的服务器，
another solution to a human made problem known as DHCP.
另一个解决人为问题的方案被称为 DHCP。
And I think this is among the remaining acronyms for today, dynamic host
我认为这属于今天的剩余缩略词，动态主机
configuration protocol.
配置协议。
And it's not that intellectually interesting to memorize that.
记住它并没有那么有趣。
But what DHCP servers do is answer questions
但是 DHCP 服务器的作用是回答问题
of the form "what should be my DNS server and router," quote, unquote.
诸如“我的 DNS 服务器和路由器应该是什么”之类的问答。
So nowadays, when you turn on your phone in the morning,
所以现在，当你早上打开手机时，
if you actually powered it off, if you open
如果你真的关机了，如果你打开
your laptop lid for the first day of classes or the like, your Mac, your PC,
你的笔记本电脑盖子，开始上课，你的 Mac，你的 PC，
your phone is essentially broadcasting a Hello, World message,
你的手机本质上是在广播一条“Hello, World”消息，
unbeknownst to you, that's just asking the local network, hey,
你不知道的是，它只是在询问本地网络，嘿，
what IP address should I use for my DNS server and for my router.
我的 DNS 服务器和路由器应该使用什么 IP 地址。
And hopefully, Harvard or Yale or your apartment or your home more
希望哈佛或耶鲁，或者你的公寓，或者你家更
generally has a DHCP server nearby whose purpose in life
普遍地，会有一个 DHCP 服务器在附近，它的职责是
is just to hand out answers to that question.
仅仅是回答这个问题。
And what these DHCP servers also do is they
这些 DHCP 服务器还做的另一件事是，它们
tell your Mac, your PC, your phone, what IP
告诉你的 Mac，你的 PC，你的手机，你的设备应该使用什么 IP 地址，因为这
address your device should use because that too
也是不再手动配置了。
is no longer manually configured.
不再手动配置了。
So this all just nowadays happens automatically.
所以现在这一切都是自动发生的。
And in the case of a campus like this or at Yale,
对于像这样的校园，或者耶鲁大学来说，
it's because, at the very beginning of your visit to campus,
这是因为在你访问校园之初，
you did register somehow.
你以某种方式注册了。
You probably logged in.
你可能登录了。
You authenticated against your Harvard account or your Yale account.
你用你的哈佛账户或耶鲁账户进行了身份验证。
And that is what enabled the DHCP servers henceforth
而这正是使得 DHCP 服务器从此
and forever to recognize your particular computer
并且永远识别你的特定电脑
and answer those questions for you.
并为你回答这些问题。
All right.
好的。
So that's it for how the internet works, at least so
所以，关于互联网是如何工作的，至少就
far as we are concerned today.
今天我们所关心的而言，就是这些了。
We're going to now start building on top of it.
现在我们将开始在它的基础上构建。
And undoubtedly, the most popular form of the internet
毫无疑问，现在最流行的互联网形式是
nowadays is something called HTTP.
一种叫做 HTTP 的东西。
That is the World Wide Web, though most people don't really say it in long form
那就是万维网，尽管大多数人不再用长形式说它了
anymore.
了。
But HTTP is just another protocol that governs how web browsers
但是 HTTP 只是另一个协议，它管理着网页浏览器
and how web servers speak, just like IP is
以及 web 服务器是如何通信的，就像 IP 是
a protocol that governs how computers address each other on the internet,
一个管理着电脑在互联网上如何互相寻址的协议，
and how TCP governs how computers keep track of sequences of packets
以及 TCP 如何管理着电脑对从 A 点到 B 点的报文序列进行跟踪
from point A to point B and also multiplex among different services
以及如何通过不同的服务进行多路复用
using those port numbers.
使用这些端口号。
And to be clear, what's a protocol-- well, in the human world,
需要澄清的是，什么是协议？——嗯，在人类世界中，
it's a very common protocol.
这是一种非常普遍的协议。
And I can't reach any of you.
我无法接触到你们中的任何一个人。
But if I were to reach over and say hi, nice to meet you.
但如果我要伸出手说嗨，很高兴认识你。
You presumably, if we weren't five feet apart, would extend your hand.
如果我们不是相隔五英尺，你可能会伸出手。
We would sort of acknowledge, in this strange cultural convention.
我们会在这种奇怪的文化习俗中，进行某种形式的回应。
But that's a protocol.
但那是一种协议。
I know how to do it.
我知道怎么做。
You know how to do it.
你也知道怎么做。
I'm initiating.
我正在发起。
You're responding.
你在回应。
And that's exactly what's happening all the time on the internet.
而这正是互联网上一直发生的事情。
You have a client, like me in this case, that's initiating a request.
你有一个客户端，比如我，正在发起请求。
You have a server, like you in this case, that's
你有一个服务器，比如你，正在
responding to that request.
回应那个请求。
Or analogously, if you're in a restaurant,
或者，类比一下，如果你在餐厅，
you might be the client sitting down at the table.
你可能是坐在餐桌旁的顾客。
You want to order food.
你想点餐。
And there's a server that serves you that food after you have requested it.
然后会有一个服务员在你点餐后为你提供食物。
So computers, really, on the internet are implementing that same paradigm.
所以，实际上，互联网上的计算机正在实现相同的模式。
So when it comes very specifically to the web, which is different, of course,
所以，当我们具体谈到网络时，它当然与
from email and video conferencing and all
电子邮件和视频会议以及其他
of these other services on the internet, the world wide web
互联网服务不同，万维网
uses this protocol, HTTP, which standardizes
使用这种协议，HTTP，它标准化了
what goes inside of those envelopes in order
这些信封中的内容，以便
to allow a web browser to request and receive information from a web server.
让网页浏览器向网页服务器请求和接收信息。
So we've talked about really the lower level details up until now,
所以到目前为止，我们已经讨论了底层细节，
the outside of the envelope.
信封的外部。
Let's now look inside of the envelope when it comes to actual web pages
现在让我们来看看信封里面的内容，也就是实际的网页
that you might visit or soon today, you yourselves might design.
你们可能会访问的，或者很快你们自己可能会设计的。
So HTTP stands for Hypertext Transfer Protocol, which is another mouthful,
所以 HTTP 代表超文本传输协议，这又是一个很长的词，
but, again, just standardizes how we're going to get web traffic from point A
但是，它只是标准化了我们如何从 A 点
to point B, from browser to server and back.
到 B 点，从浏览器到服务器，再返回。
HTTPS is literally the secure version of that.
HTTPS 实际上是它的安全版本。
And what that means for today's purposes is that the connection is somehow
而对于今天来说，这意味着连接以某种方式
encrypted, scrambled using very fancy mathematics
被加密，使用非常复杂的数学方法进行加密
so that it is very, very, very unlikely that anyone
使得任何人都极不可能
who intercepts your traffic, your packets between point A and point B
截获你的流量，你的 A 点和 B 点之间的数据包
will have any idea what is inside of those envelopes.
知道这些信封里面是什么。
They might intercept the packet itself digitally.
他们可能会数字地截获数据包本身。
They might try to open it up.
他们可能会尝试打开它。
But it's going to look metaphorically like random zeros
但它看起来就像里面是随机的零
and ones on the inside when using HTTPS because of what's called encryption.
和一，这是因为使用了所谓的加密。
But let's look at some canonical URLs.
但是让我们来看一些规范的 URL。
All of us are in the habit of seeing these and typing these all the time.
我们都习惯于经常看到和输入这些 URL。
Well, let's actually tease apart some of the jargon here.
好吧，让我们来解析一下这里的一些术语。
So here is an example URL with all of the usual components.
这是一个包含所有常用组件的 URL 示例。
So here, for instance, with the yellow slash,
例如，这里带有黄色的斜杠，
this generally means, even though you rarely type it
这通常意味着，即使你很少输入它
and you rarely see it nowadays, this means the default page for the website.
而且如今你也很少看到它，这意味着这是网站的默认页面。
Give me the root of the website, so to speak.
可以说是，给我网站的根目录。
So this is to say this represents a folder,
所以，这意味着这代表一个文件夹，
like, the default folder inside of which is presumably the default web page.
比如，默认文件夹，里面可能就是默认的网页。
And we'll see what that means more concretely in just a bit.
我们很快就会更具体地了解它的含义。
If, though, you're visiting a more specific URL,
但是，如果你访问的是更具体的 URL，
we're going to henceforth call this a path.
我们今后将称之为路径。
So slash something is representative of a path, maybe a file, maybe a folder,
所以，斜杠后面接东西，代表一个路径，可能是一个文件，也可能是一个文件夹，
just like in the world of Macs, PCs, and cloud services.
就像 Mac、PC 和云服务的世界一样。
Specifically, you might sometimes be in the habit of visiting an actual file,
具体来说，你可能有时习惯于访问实际的文件，
something like /file.html.
比如 /file.html。
Nowadays, this is kind of very '90s, early 2000s.
现在，这有点像 90 年代初和 2000 年代初。
Nowadays most web servers hide the file extension,
现在大多数 Web 服务器隐藏了文件扩展名，
the dot HTML, even if it's there on the server.
也就是 .html，即使它在服务器上存在。
It just looks a little messy nowadays.
现在看起来有点乱。
It sort of reveals information that's not necessary.
它有点暴露了不必要的 信息。
So very often you won't see dot HTML, even if there is actually
所以你经常不会看到 .html，即使实际上
a file ending in that suffix.
存在以该后缀结尾的文件。
You might instead see /folder, with a slash.
你可能会看到 /folder，带一个斜杠。
Maybe not a slash, maybe a slash, but that generally
可能没有斜杠，可能有一个斜杠，但这通常
represents a folder on the server.
代表服务器上的一个文件夹。
And sometimes there are, of course, files in folders.
当然，有时文件夹中也会有文件。
So all of this stuff you're probably familiar with on Macs and PCs and even
所以所有这些东西你可能在 Mac 和 PC 上甚至
Google Drive and the like.
谷歌云盘等地方都很熟悉。
Those same semantics exist in the context of URLs.
这些相同的语义也存在于 URL 的上下文中。
So there's a mapping between this URL and something on a hard drive somewhere
所以，这个 URL 与某个服务器硬盘上的某个东西之间存在映射。
on some server.
在某个服务器上。
All right.
好的。
What about the other parts?
其他部分呢？
So this is the fully qualified domain name, so the full domain name.
所以这是完全限定域名，也就是完整域名。
Even though you and I, when we say domain name,
即使你和我，当我们说域名时，
we typically just mean this example.com, for instance.
我们通常只指的是这个 example.com，比如。
So technically, the W-W-W is what we would typically call a host name.
所以从技术上讲，www 通常被称为主机名。
A host name is like the name of a specific server that lives somewhere
主机名就像某个特定服务器的名称，它存在于某个地方
in that domain.
在这个域名中。
And this is just a human convention.
这只是一个人类约定。
Even though most URLs still probably start with W-W-W dot something,
即使大多数 URL 仍然可能以 www. 开头，
that's not strictly required.
但这不是严格要求的。
That's just a configuration detail.
这只是一个配置细节。
And historically, this was just to kind of signal
从历史上看，这只是为了给
to less technical people in particular, when you would see a URL in print,
特别是技术水平较低的人，当你看到印刷的 URL 时，
that oh, this is a web address.
就会发现，哦，这是一个网络地址。
This is an address on that new world wide web.
这是一个新的万维网上的地址。
W-W-W just kind of connotes that.
www 只是暗示了这一点。
But decreasingly, do you see websites using this?
但是，你是否看到越来越少的网站使用它？
I mean, some of CS50's own tools, it's just cs50.dev.
我的意思是，CS50 自己的一些工具，它就是 cs50.dev。
It's just CS50.ai.
它就是 CS50.ai。
Because most of us are now conditioned to know that,
因为我们大多数人现在已经被训练成知道，
oh, OK, that's probably a URL, even though there's no explicit W-W-W.
哦，好的，这可能是一个 URL，即使没有明确的 W-W-W。
And in fact, even if you type the W-W-W using tricks that we'll soon see,
事实上，即使你使用我们很快就会看到的技巧输入 W-W-W，
you can redirect the user from one to another.
你可以将用户从一个重定向到另一个。
Essentially, remove the W-W-W or add it to the server,
本质上，删除 W-W-W 或将其添加到服务器，
to the address bar in their browser.
到他们浏览器中的地址栏。
This thing here is called the top level domain.
这里的东西叫做顶级域名。
And many of the domain names that you and I are in the habit,
而你和我习惯使用的许多域名，
certainly in the US nowadays, end in .com, which stands for commercial,
当然，现在在美国，它们以 .com 结尾，代表商业，
.edu stands for educational, .gov stands for US government.
.edu 代表教育，.gov 代表美国政府。
But of course, there's hundreds of country codes, too, that by convention
当然，还有数百个国家代码，根据惯例
are two letters.
是两个字母。
So .uk for the United Kingdom, .jp for Japan,
所以 .uk 代表英国，.jp 代表日本，
and two characters for every other country in the world.
以及世界上其他每个国家的两个字符。
But even those have kind of been used in clever ways.
但即使是那些也以巧妙的方式使用。
So .tv, for instance, is actually a country code that's been used by a lot
例如，.tv 实际上是一个国家代码，已被很多
of the English-speaking world to represent television,
英语世界的人用来代表电视，
for TV shows and the like.
用于电视节目等。
.ai, similarly, does not actually mean artificial intelligence.
类似地，.ai 实际上并不意味着人工智能。
It's a two character country code that has been used by the world nowadays
它是一个由当今世界使用的两个字符的国家代码
to represent AI.
来代表 AI。
.ly for bitly and CS50.ly, too, that's a country code that allows people like us
.ly 代表 bitly 和 CS50.ly，也是一个国家代码，它允许像我们这样的人
to essentially buy domain names in that subdomain.
基本上购买那个子域中的域名。
But long story short, back in the day there only
但长话短说，在过去，只
used to be a few of these top level domains.
存在少数几个顶级域名。
Now there are hundreds of them.
现在有数百个。
So I do think, over time, it's going to become
所以我认为，随着时间的推移，它将变得
a lot less regimented as it seems to be now as to what URLs actually look like.
不那么死板，就像现在一样，关于 URL 的实际外观。
Lastly, beyond the :// here is the scheme, or the protocol.
最后，这里 :// 之后的，是方案或协议。
And this just means that this URL is going
而这仅仅意味着这个 URL 将
to be securely accessing the server thanks to the HTTPS instead of HTTP.
通过 HTTPS 而不是 HTTP 安全地访问服务器。
Mouthful.
说起来有点长。
But just to get some vocabulary out there.
但只是为了介绍一些词汇。
Questions on these here URLs that we've probably
关于这些我们可能已经
been taking for granted for years?
多年来一直认为理所当然的 URL 的问题？
AUDIENCE: Who approves .edu?
听众：谁批准 .edu？
DAVID MALAN: Really good question, who approves .edu.
大卫·马兰：真是个好问题，谁批准了 .edu。
So you have to be in an accredited educational institution to use .edu.
所以你必须在经认可的教育机构才能使用 .edu。
I don't recall the name of the organization that does this.
我不记得进行这项工作的组织的名称。
But it can't be anyone on the internet.
但这不能是互联网上的任何人。
You actually have to apply and be a seemingly legitimate
你实际上必须申请并成为一个看似合法的
educational institution.
教育机构。
That is not true of a lot of domain names.
对于许多域名来说，情况并非如此。
Anyone can buy a .com.
任何人都可以购买 .com。
Anyone can buy .org, a .net, not a .gov, for instance.
任何人都可以购买 .org，.net，例如，不是 .gov。
And then different countries might have their own policies
然后不同的国家可能会有他们自己的政策
over who can be in what domain or subdomain as well.
关于谁可以在哪个域或子域。
All right.
好的。
So now that we have URLs so defined, there's
因此，既然我们已经定义了 URL，那么
a couple of verbs with which to be familiar in the context of the web,
在 Web 的上下文中，有一些动词需要熟悉，
namely GET and POST.
即 GET 和 POST。
And that is to say, there's two different ways
也就是说，有两种不同的方式
to request information from a server.
从服务器请求信息。
That is, there's two different ways to format requests
也就是说，有两种不同的方式来格式化请求
that go inside of this envelope.
放入这个信封中。
And the default, daresay, and the most common one is just what's called GET,
默认的，可以说，最常见的一种就是所谓的 GET，
literally the verb, the English verb get.
就是动词，英文中的动词 get。
And we'll see in a moment what this means exactly concretely.
我们很快就会看到，这在实际中具体意味着什么。
But just know that there's an alternative that we'll
但只要知道，还有一个选择，我们会
play with over time known as POST.
随着时间的推移进行尝试，被称为 POST。
And whereas GET, as the verb suggests, is all about just getting information,
而 GET，正如动词所暗示的，仅仅是获取信息，
POST, as the verb kind of suggests, is more about sending information.
POST，正如动词所暗示的，更多地是发送信息。
So POST is used when you submit a credit card.
所以，当你提交信用卡时，会使用 POST。
Because you're sort of sending potentially sensitive information.
因为你正在发送可能敏感的信息。
POST is used when you upload an image to a website or the like,
当你将图像上传到网站或类似的地方时，会使用 POST，
but GET is used when you're just clicking on links
但当你只是点击链接
and visiting web pages and not really pushing any information to the server.
并访问网页，并没有真正将任何信息推送到服务器时，会使用 GET。
So for today, we'll focus primarily on GET.
所以，今天，我们将主要关注 GET。
So what does this mean?
那么，这意味着什么？
Inside of this envelope, probably unbeknownst to you up until now,
在这个信封里面，可能你直到现在还不知道，
is our messages that look like this.
是我们这样的消息。
These are HTTP messages that are being put automatically
这些是 HTTP 消息，它们被自动地
in these virtual envelopes for you by your Mac, your PC, for your phone.
放入这些虚拟信封中，由你的 Mac，你的 PC，你的手机为你完成。
So for instance, if you were to visit HTTPS://www.harvard.edu,
例如，如果你要访问 HTTPS://www.harvard.edu，
you would hit Enter.
你将按下回车键。
What your Mac, PC, or phone is going to do
你的 Mac，PC 或手机将要做的是
is put a textual message that looks literally
将一个文本消息放入信封中，这个消息看起来完全
like this inside of a virtual envelope, address it on the outside
像这样，放入一个虚拟信封中，在信封外面写上地址
to the appropriate IP address for harvard.edu using your own IP
到 harvard.edu 的正确 IP 地址，使用你自己的 IP
address as the source address, and then hand it off to some nearest router.
地址作为源地址，然后将其交给最近的路由器。
But inside of this envelope is enough information to the server
但在这个信封里面，包含足够的信息让服务器
to know what it is you want.
知道你想要什么。
So for instance, GET is the verb.
例如，GET 是动词。
So you just want to get some information.
所以你只是想要获取一些信息。
The information you want to get is /, which
你想要获取的信息是 /，它
I defined earlier as just the default page on the website.
我之前定义过，就是网站上的默认页面。
HTTP/2 just means what version of HTTP we're talking about.
HTTP/2 仅仅意味着我们正在讨论 HTTP 的哪个版本。
You'll see nowadays in the wild, 1.1, you'll see 2,
现在你会在现实中看到 1.1，你会看到 2，
you'll start to see version 3 over time.
随着时间的推移，你会开始看到版本 3。
But I'll use 2 for all of my examples here.
但我在这里的所有例子中都会使用 2。
And you'll see inside of this envelope, too,
你会在这个信封里面看到，
what we're going to start calling an HTTP header, a single line of text that
我们接下来将要称之为 HTTP 标头，是一行文本，它
literally tells the server what fully qualified domain name it's looking for.
字面上告诉服务器它正在寻找哪个完全限定域名。
And this is important only insofar as nowadays, generally on a server,
这很重要，因为如今，通常在一台服务器上，
you might have multiple websites being hosted.
你可能会托管多个网站。
This is not going to be true probably of Google or of Microsoft
这可能不适用于 Google 或微软
or Meta or massive companies like that.
或 Meta 或类似的大公司。
But it's definitely going to be true of smaller enterprises, even
但这肯定适用于较小的企业，甚至
places like Harvard that don't need thousands of web servers,
像哈佛这样的地方，不需要成千上万的 Web 服务器，
but maybe just a couple, or maybe just a few.
但也许只需要两三个，或者只有一两个。
So in this case, this ensures that when the server receives this packet,
因此，在这种情况下，这确保当服务器收到此数据包时，
it knows to serve up harvard.edu and not yale.edu
它知道要提供 harvard.edu，而不是 yale.edu
or some other website that, by coincidence, might just be
或其他一些巧合可能只是
hosted on the same server because both Harvard and Yale are maybe
托管在同一台服务器上，因为哈佛和耶鲁都可能
paying the same cloud provider to host their websites.
向同一个云提供商付费来托管他们的网站。
So dot dot dot just means there's other HTTP headers.
因此，点点点意味着还有其他 HTTP 标头。
But notice the colon here is just giving us yet another one of those key value
但请注意，此处的冒号只是为我们提供了另一个键值对。
pairs.
对。
The key is HOST.
键是 HOST。
The value is www.harvard.edu.
值为 www.harvard.edu。
There, again, are those dictionaries that I
再次出现了那些字典，我
claimed we would continue to see all over the place.
声称我们会继续在各处看到。
What then comes back from the server?
那么服务器会返回什么？
If this is what's inside the message from browser to server,
如果这就是浏览器到服务器消息的内容，
what does the server send back?
服务器会发回什么？
Ideally, the server sends back a message that
理想情况下，服务器会发送一条消息，
looks like this, an acknowledgment of what version is being used,
看起来像这样，确认正在使用哪个版本，
a status code, which is going to be an arcane looking number, like 200.
一个状态码，它将是一个看起来很神秘的数字，比如 200。
It's going to then have another HTTP header of its own saying
它随后将有另一个自己的 HTTP 标头，说明
what type of content is in this envelope, ideally,
这个信封中的内容类型是什么，理想情况下，
something called text/html.
称为 text/html 的东西。
That is hypertext markup language, which we're about to see.
这就是超文本标记语言，我们即将看到。
And then some other stuff.
然后是一些其他的东西。
That's what's coming back from the server to the browser.
这就是从服务器返回到浏览器的內容。
And we can actually now see this.
我们现在实际上可以看到这一点。
Let me actually go over to VS Code here.
让我实际到 VS Code 这里。
Let me maximize my terminal window just so we can see more at once.
让我最大化我的终端窗口，以便我们能够一次看到更多内容。
And let me go ahead and type in this command,
让我继续输入这个命令，
curl -I https://www.harvard.edu/, so a complete URL that's secure,
curl -I https://www.harvard.edu/，因此这是一个安全的完整 URL，
that's got the host name of W-W-W.
它包含 W-W-W 的主机名。
And curl just means connect to a URL.
curl 只是意味着连接到一个 URL。
It's a command line program that comes with Linux, comes with Mac OS, Windows.
它是一个命令行程序，随 Linux 一起提供，随 Mac OS 一起提供，随 Windows 一起提供。
You might have to install it individually.
你可能需要单独安装它。
And it just lets me simulate being a browser,.
它只是让我模拟成为一个浏览器，
It's going to let me simulate sending a packet like this
它将让我模拟发送一个像这样的数据包
without caring what the website actually looks like,
而不关心网站实际上是什么样子，
so no pictures, no images, no text, no nothing, just what's inside
因此没有图片，没有图像，没有文本，什么都没有，只有服务器响应的信封内
of the envelope in terms of the server's response.
的内容。
And here's mostly dot dot dot, the ellipses I raised my hand at earlier?
这里大部分是点点点，我之前举手提到的省略号？
There's a lot of these key value pairs.
这里有很多这样的键值对。
But if I scroll up to the top, you'll see that 200
但如果我向上滚动到顶部，你会看到 200
is the status code that came back.
是返回的状态码。
And you'll see that the content type is indeed text/html.
你会看到内容类型确实是 text/html。
And there's a whole lot of other stuff here, clearly.
这里还有很多其他的东西，很明显。
A lot of this is diagnostic.
很多都是诊断信息。
It reveals information about the server that
它揭示了有关服务器的信息，
might be useful generally to more technical people than me
对于比我更技术的人来说，通常可能是有用的
at this point in the conversation, or maybe my Mac or my PC or my phone.
在这个对话的阶段，或者可能是我的 Mac 或我的 PC 或我的手机。
For now, we can focus really on just the essence
现在，我们真的可以只关注
of this response, which is this here.
这个响应的本质，就是这里。
But here's where even these arcane numbers might start
但这里，即使是这些神秘的数字也可能开始
to get a little more familiar, in fact.
变得更熟悉一些，事实上。
Suppose that I want to see this in my browser.
假设我想在浏览器中看到它。
Actually, let me do this.
实际上，让我这样做。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code 这里。
Let me open up incognito mode here, which
让我在这里打开隐身模式，它
generally is to give you private browsing, so to speak.
通常是让你进行私密浏览，可以这么说。
And we'll talk more about this next week.
我们下周会详细讨论这个。
In incognito mode or private mode, you have no history, you have no cookies,
在隐身模式或私密模式下，你没有历史记录，你没有 cookie，
you have no sessions, terms we'll define next week.
你没有会话，这些术语我们下周会定义。
I'm going to use it again and again today
我今天将反复使用它
to make sure that my browser is essentially
以确保我的浏览器基本上
starting from scratch, freshly, so that I don't have anything in my history
从头开始，全新地，这样我的历史记录中就不会有任何东西
from previous examples.
来自之前的示例。
And what I'm going to do, actually, first
我实际上要做的第一件事是
is open up, via my browser's menu, so-called developer tools.
通过我的浏览器的菜单打开所谓的开发者工具。
These are going to look a little different in Chrome
这些在 Chrome 中看起来会略有不同
versus Edge versus Firefox versus Safari versus other browsers as well.
与 Edge、Firefox、Safari 或其他浏览器相比。
But almost any modern browser, whatever your favorite is nowadays,
但几乎所有现代浏览器，无论你目前最喜欢哪个，
has built into it developer tools.
都内置了开发者工具。
And you might have to click a different button to access it.
你可能需要点击不同的按钮才能访问它。
But these are tools for developers, like,
但这些是为开发者准备的工具，比如，
web developers that want to not just use the browser to go places,
想要不仅仅使用浏览器去访问地方的 Web 开发人员，
but use the browser to develop their own websites and web applications.
而是使用浏览器来开发他们自己的网站和 Web 应用程序。
Now there's a whole bunch of tabs here.
这里有一堆标签。
And I'm going to focus on the Network tab initially.
我最初将关注网络标签。
Essentially, this is like diagnostic information, kind of like debug50,
本质上，这就像诊断信息，有点像 debug50，
like a debugger.
就像调试器。
But it's specific to the web and the web browser here.
但它特定于这里 Web 和 Web 浏览器。
So with my developer tools open and with the Network tab open,
因此，在我的开发者工具打开并且网络标签打开的情况下，
I'm going to go up to the URL bar and type in https://www.harvard.edu/.
我将向上转到 URL 栏，并输入 https://www.harvard.edu/。
So the exact same thing that I typed in curl a moment ago in my terminal,
因此，与我之前在终端中输入的 curl 命令完全一样，
I'm just typing in my browser like I would normally do.
我只是像平时一样在浏览器中输入。
And if I hit Enter, what's interesting about developer tools,
如果我按回车键，开发者工具的有趣之处在于，
and let me go ahead and drag them to the top and maximize the window,
让我继续将它们拖到顶部并最大化窗口，
is you see all of the HTTP requests, all of the virtual envelopes
你将看到所有 HTTP 请求，所有虚拟信封
that just went instantaneously it would seem back and forth
似乎瞬间就来回切换了，在我这边的 Mac 和哈佛大学自己的网页服务器之间。
between my Mac here and Harvard's own web server.
And notice it's way more than a single envelope.
而且请注意，这远不止一个信封。
It's way more than a single request.
这远不止一个请求。
Why?
为什么？
For now, assume that each of those rows of output
现在，假设这些输出中的每一行都代表着可能下载的内容。
represents maybe a sound that was downloaded,
a video, an image, some text.
比如声音、视频、图像或文本。
There's all sorts of media in web pages nowadays.
现在网页中包含各种各样的媒体。
And they might actually be spread across multiple files.
而且它们可能实际上分布在多个文件中。
Browsers are designed, if you will, to recursively get
如果要这么说的话，浏览器被设计成递归地获取
all of the media for a single web page and download it automatically
单个网页上的所有媒体并自动下载，
with we humans only typing the URL itself once.
我们人类只需输入一次 URL 本身。
But watch this.
但是请看。
At the very top of this output, I scrolled all the way
在这个输出的最上面，我向下滚动到底部。
to the top of my network tab.
到达了我的网络选项卡的顶部。
I'll see a request, a row that represents
我看到一个请求，一行代表着
my original request for the website.
我对网站的原始请求。
And if I Zoom in here, we'll see that 200 means apparently OK.
如果我在这里放大，我们会看到 200 似乎代表着“OK”。
So all is well.
所以一切正常。
Here's the contents of the website.
这是网站的内容。
But there's a lot.
但是很多。
In fact, if I look at the very bottom of the window,
事实上，如果我看看窗口的最底部，
harvard.edu is composed of 91 separate files it would seem.
似乎 harvard.edu 由 91 个独立的文件组成。
And that's just the landing page itself, not
而这仅仅是主页本身，而不是
to mention everything else we might click on ultimately.
我们最终可能点击的任何其他内容。
But 200, OK, is a good thing.
但是 200，OK，是一件好事。
And odds are you've never actually seen that, because it's, indeed, OK.
而且很有可能你从未真正见过它，因为它确实很正常。
So let's consider actually what else could
所以，让我们考虑一下，当你发出这些请求时，还可能发生什么。
happen when you make these requests.
Well, here, for instance, is a shorter request.
好吧，例如，这是一个较短的请求。
Suppose that I omit the W-W-W just because it's faster to type.
假设我省略了 WWW，仅仅因为它输入起来更快。
And honestly, you and I are almost always,
说实话，你我几乎总是
nowadays I bet, in the habit of just typing something.com, or something.edu.
现在我敢打赌，已经习惯于仅仅输入 something.com 或 something.edu。
We don't bother typing the HTTPS, the so-called scheme or protocol.
我们不费心输入 HTTPS，也就是所谓的方案或协议。
We probably don't bother typing the W-W-W.
我们可能不费心输入 WWW。
You can probably think of someone in your life
你可能能想到你生活中某个人
who's very pedantic like that, typing it out in its full.
他非常迂腐地那样，完整地输入它。
But you don't need to do that typically for a couple of reasons.
但你通常不需要那样做，原因有几个。
If I, in fact, go back to VS Code here, let
如果我实际上回到这里的 VS Code，让我再次使用 curl 连接到另一个类似的 URL。
me use curl again to connect to another URL that's similar,
https://harvard.edu.
https://harvard.edu。
Now notice before I went to W-W-W. And that's indeed Harvard's preferred URL,
现在请注意，之前我使用了 WWW。而那确实是哈佛大学首选的 URL，
if you will.
如果要这么说的话。
But harvard.edu will still work.
但 harvard.edu 仍然可以工作。
But watch what happens when I hit Enter.
但请看，当我按下回车键时发生了什么。
I'm going to get back the contents of the virtual envelope
我会收到哈佛大学发回给我的虚拟信封的内容。
that Harvard just sent back to me.
But it's not OK.
但它不是 OK。
It's not 200 anymore.
它不再是 200 了。
It's actually this number here, 301, which
它实际上是这里这个数字 301，它
actually means something specific.
实际上意味着一些特定的东西。
301 actually means that Harvard's website moved permanently, so to speak.
301 实际上意味着哈佛大学的网站永久地迁移了，可以这么说。
In other words, Harvard, Yale, any server
换句话说，哈佛大学、耶鲁大学，任何服务器
can configure itself to redirect the user to another place
都可以配置自身将用户重定向到另一个地方，
if they prefer to canonicalize on some other URL.
如果他们更喜欢在另一个 URL 上标准化。
So by default for branding purposes, most websites still
所以默认情况下，出于品牌目的，大多数网站仍然
probably use www.something.something.
可能使用 www.something.something。
So Harvard is, in fact, doing this.
所以哈佛大学实际上正在这样做。
And for reasons we'll talk about next week,
而且由于下周我们将讨论的原因，
there's technical motivations to do so related to something
这样做有技术上的原因，与一些东西有关，
called cookies and sessions.
叫做 cookies 和 sessions。
But for now, that just seems to be a different status code.
但现在，这似乎只是一个不同的状态码。
But if I now open up another browser window and I'll do this again in,
但是如果我现在打开另一个浏览器窗口，并且我将在
let's say, how about incognito mode, just to start fresh with a brand
比如，隐身模式中重新开始，
new window.
新窗口。
Let me open my developer tools again.
让我再次打开我的开发者工具。
Let me go to the URL bar and only type https://harvard.edu/ Enter.
让我去 URL 栏，只输入 https://harvard.edu/ 回车。
I'm still in my network tab here.
我仍然在我的网络选项卡中。
And if I scroll to the very top of this, notice, ah,
如果我滚动到最上面，请注意，啊，
the top row looks a little different now.
最上面的那行看起来现在有些不同。
It's not 200 anymore.
它不再是 200 了。
And I can click on that here.
我可以在此处点击它。
And what I'm now seeing in yellow is that 301, AKA, moved permanently.
现在，我在黄色中看到的是 301，也就是“永久移动”。
So this is to say you've been able to do this all this time in your browser
所以，这意味着你可以一直以来都在浏览器中做这件事，
if you care to.
如果你愿意的话。
You can see what's going on underneath the hood, if you will.
如果你愿意的话，你可以看到幕后发生了什么。
Check that off, I think.
我认为，这已经确定了。
Underneath the hood so as to just understand what's going on.
了解幕后发生了什么，仅仅是为了理解发生了什么。
Now for users, this is not that useful or intellectually interesting.
现在，对于用户来说，这并不那么有用，也不那么具有智力上的趣味性。
But for developers, this can be very useful for understanding things
但对于开发者来说，这对于理解事情非常有用，
and also diagnosing problems ultimately.
并且最终用于诊断问题。
So that's just a couple of the status codes that can come back, not just 200,
所以，这只是可以返回的几种状态码中的两种，不仅仅是 200，
but perhaps 301.
也可能是 301。
There's also this one now, with which humans generally are familiar, 404.
现在还有这个，人类通常很熟悉，404。
Well, it turns out 404 is what happens when a file is not found.
事实证明，404 是指文件未找到时发生的情况。
So I can simulate that here.
所以我可以在此处模拟它。
Let me go back to VS Code and my terminal window.
让我回到 VS Code 和我的终端窗口。
Let me do curl -I https://www--
让我执行 curl -I https://www--
because Harvard prefers that-- harvard.edu/cats.
因为哈佛大学更喜欢这样——harvard.edu/cats。
Let's see if there's a page about cats within Harvard's website.
我们看看哈佛大学的网站上是否有关于猫的页面。
I'm pretty sure there's not.
我相当确定没有。
And so, indeed, when I hit Enter, a whole lot of output, a lot of HTTP
所以，当我按下回车键时，确实产生了大量输出，很多 HTTP
headers.
头信息。
But notice at the top, 404.
但请注意，最上面是 404。
It's File Not Found.
意思是文件未找到。
Now what you see in the browser is going to completely depend on the website.
现在，你在浏览器中看到的内容将完全取决于网站。
Some websites just display an error message or a status code number.
一些网站只显示一条错误消息或一个状态码。
And that's why you and I have seen probably in the world 404 messages.
这就是为什么你和我在世界上可能都看到过 404 消息。
Sometimes they're much more user friendly.
有时它们更加人性化。
Sometimes there are links back to the home page to help you out.
有时会有链接返回主页来帮助你。
It's entirely up to the server.
这完全取决于服务器。
But that status code indicates that something has gone wrong.
但这个状态码表明有些地方出错了。
And in fact, there's a whole bunch of these status codes.
事实上，存在很多这种状态码。
Some of which you'll now start to see in the class.
其中一些你会在课堂上开始看到。
200's OK.
200 表示 OK。
And it's a good thing if you never see that,
如果你从未见过它，那是一件好事，
because it means everything's working.
因为这意味着一切正常。
404 is not found.
404 表示未找到。
301 is moved permanently.
301 表示永久移动。
Any of these that start with 3 relate to redirects.
所有以 3 开头的状态码都与重定向相关。
Long story short, there's different ways to redirect the user from one place
简而言之，有很多种方法可以将用户从一个地方重定向
to another, as we saw from that location header a moment ago.
到另一个地方，正如我们刚才从 Location 标头中看到的。
400s are generally bad.
400 状态码一般代表错误。
It means that the user, the browser somehow did something wrong.
这意味着用户或浏览器以某种方式做错了什么。
Like, 403 forbidden probably means you're not logged in.
例如，403 Forbidden 可能意味着你没有登录。
500 you're going to start doing next week most likely.
500 状态码你下周可能会开始遇到。
500 is, like, the segfault of the web, if you will.
500 就相当于网络中的段错误，如果你理解的话。
So there's no pointers or anything like that.
所以没有指针或任何类似的东西。
But 500 means that you wrote some buggy code, as invariably we all will
但是 500 状态码意味着你写了一些有错误的代码，正如我们每个人都会不可避免地
next week.
在下周遇到一样。
418 is an April Fool's joke from years ago.
418 是几年前愚人节的一个玩笑。
Some servers honor this.
一些服务器会遵守这个。
But someone wrote up literally this long technical document
但有人写了整整一份技术文档
proposing a response that says I'm a teapot for a server,
建议服务器返回一个“我是一个茶壶”的响应，
even though it was just a joke on April 1 some years ago,
即使这只是几年前愚人节的一个玩笑，
so sort of geek humor, if you will.
所以这算是一种极客幽默，如果你理解的话。
So those are then the status codes that are available to us.
所以这些就是我们可用的状态码。
Let me show you one other.
我再向你展示一个。
Has anyone been to this URL here?
有人访问过这个 URL 吗？
So you have?
你访问过？
All right.
好的。
So without spoiling here, let me actually--
所以不剧透了，我实际上 -
well, let me go into incognito mode here.
好吧，我进入隐身模式。
Someone's pulling it up on their phone, clearly.
显然有人用他们的手机打开了它。
Safetyschool.org/ Enter.
safetyschool.org/ 进入。
Oh, my goodness.
我的天哪。
Another box gets crossed out today, too, I think.
我想今天又有一个方框被划掉了。
So how is that working?
所以这是怎么工作的？
Well, if we actually diagnose this with curl-- let me go into VS Code,
好吧，如果我们用 curl 来诊断它 - 我进入 VS Code，
curl -I HTTP-- and it doesn't support HTTPS because this is an old website--
curl -I HTTP - 因为它不支持 HTTPS，因为这是一个老网站 -
://safetyschool.org/ Enter, all this server does is return an HTTP 301
://safetyschool.org/ 进入，这个服务器只返回一个 HTTP 301
response with a location that literally refers us back to yale.edu.
响应，其中 Location 指向了 yale.edu。
And this is amazing.
这太神奇了。
Someone has been paying for this domain name for decades.
有人已经为这个域名支付了数十年的费用。
And all it does is literally this.
它所做的仅仅是这些。
Now I know for our friends at Yale who are watching this,
现在我知道对于观看这场直播的耶鲁大学的朋友们来说，
it's not quite fair to poke fun.
拿它开玩笑并不公平。
It turns out Yale got us even better.
结果耶鲁大学给我们准备了更棒的东西。
So later today, we'll turn the tables a little bit.
所以今天晚些时候，我们会反过来。
All right.
好的。
So let's go ahead and take a look now at what
所以让我们现在来看看
it is that composes this web page when it is indeed 200 OK.
是什么构成了这个网页，当它确实是 200 OK 时。
Let's introduce another language here, or an actual language
让我们在这里介绍另一种语言，或者说是一种真正的语言
called HTML, which is not a programming language but is a mark up language.
叫做 HTML，它不是一种编程语言，而是一种标记语言。
Which is to say it's all about aesthetics, like,
也就是说它完全是关于美观的，比如
mocking up a web page so that you can see the information you care about.
模拟一个网页，这样你就可以看到你关心的信息。
But HTML is not going to have functions and loops and conditionals
但 HTML 不会包含函数、循环和条件语句
and all of that stuff we talked about in Week 0
以及我们在第 0 周讨论的所有内容。
It's just about presenting information.
它仅仅是用来呈现信息。
So here are some of the building blocks of HTML.
所以这里是一些 HTML 的构建块。
You're about to see really only two vocabulary words.
你将只看到两个词汇。
HTML honestly is the kind of language that you learn in, like, 30 minutes
坦白地说，HTML 是一种你可以在 30 分钟内学会的语言
and then you're just kind of off and running with online tutorials,
然后你就可以通过在线教程开始使用它了，
documentation, and the like.
文档等等。
I still remember years ago just learning it
我还记得多年前刚学它
from a teaching fellow who kind of gave me a crash course
是一位助教给了我一个速成课程
and then you kind of fill in the blanks yourself
然后你就可以自己填补空白了
because it has relatively few concepts associated with it.
因为它相关的概念很少。
Even though, in fairness, it can take years
尽管公平地说，这可能需要很多年
to get good at making pretty websites, today we
才能熟练地制作漂亮的网站，但今天我们
can get good very quickly at making functional websites, so
可以很快地学会制作功能完备的网站，所以
that artistic disclaimer.
这就是艺术方面的免责声明。
So in the world of HTML, there's really two concepts, tags and attributes.
所以，在 HTML 的世界里，实际上只有两个概念，标签和属性。
And those of you who have played with websites growing up
而那些从小就接触过网站的人
might be familiar with some of these already.
可能已经熟悉其中的一些了。
So here is some sample HTML.
所以这里是一些 HTML 示例。
HTML is just a text-based language.
HTML 仅仅是一种基于文本的语言。
You type it out with your keyboard.
你用键盘输入它。
Again, it's not a programming language.
再说一次，它不是一种编程语言。
So you can't call functions or write logic.
所以你不能调用函数或编写逻辑。
But you can mock up a web page.
但你可以模拟一个网页。
And this web page, for instance, is quite simply
例如，这个网页很简单
going to say hello, title in its title bar, or the tab.
将会显示“hello”，标题栏或标签中的标题。
And then the body of it, the big white box,
然后是它的主体，那个大白框，
it's going to say hello comma body, just to distill this really into its essence
它会显示“hello, body”，只是为了将这个东西真正地概括为它的本质
before we make more interesting pages.
在我们制作更有趣的页面之前。
So what's going on in this HTML is enough detail
所以，这段 HTML 中的代码足够详细
that the server can display the information for it.
使得服务器能够显示它所包含的信息。
So in fact, let me go ahead and reveal this as follows.
所以事实上，让我按照以下步骤来展示它。
I'm going to go over to VS Code here.
我要转到 VS Code。
I'm going to create a new file here called, for instance--
我将在这里创建一个新文件，比如 -
let's just call it hello.html.
就叫它 hello.html 吧。
And I'm going to really quickly whip up that same web page from memory.
我将很快地从记忆中写出相同的网页。
So DOCTYPE html html lang equals quote, unquote "en" close bracket.
所以 DOCTYPE html html lang 等于引号，引号 "en" 关闭括号。
Open head, open title, hello comma title.
打开头部，打开标题，hello逗号标题。
And then down here, open body.
然后在下面，打开主体。
And you'll notice I'm actually not quite as fast as I might seem to be.
你会注意到，我实际上并没有像看起来那样快。
VS Code is configured to automatically finish half of my thought for me.
VS Code 被配置为自动完成我一半的想法。
So when I open one of these things that we're about to call tags,
所以当我打开我们即将称之为标签的东西之一时，
VS Code is doing some of the heavy lifting for me.
VS Code 正在为我做一些繁重的工作。
And in here, I'm going to do hello comma body.
在这里，我将做 hello逗号主体。
But I think this is the entirety of the file
但我认为这是整个文件
that I just proposed in the slide version thereof.
我刚刚在幻灯片版本中提出的。
So this is clearly now a text file in my code space within VS Code.
所以现在这显然是我在 VS Code 中的代码空间中的一个文本文件。
How do I actually view it with a web browser?
我如何使用网络浏览器实际查看它？
So if this file were created on my Mac or PC,
所以如果这个文件是在我的 Mac 或 PC 上创建的，
I could literally double click it and Chrome or my default browser
我可以直接双击它，Chrome 或我的默认浏览器
would open up and show me this web page.
会打开并向我显示这个网页。
But this file, technically, is not on my Mac or PC.
但这个文件，从技术上讲，不在我的 Mac 或 PC 上。
It's in the cloud.
它在云端。
It's in your code space.
它在你的代码空间中。
So all that we need to do is actually turn on a web server
所以我们所需要做的就是实际打开一个网络服务器
to serve this file to me or to anyone else in the world, in fact.
来向我或世界上任何其他人提供这个文件，事实上。
And the command we're going to run now is literally called http-server.
而我们现在要运行的命令字面上称为 http-server。
This is a piece of software that someone else
这是一段其他人写的软件
wrote that we pre-installed in everyone's code space.
我们预先安装在每个人的代码空间中。
And by running this, it starts a server whose purpose in life
通过运行它，它启动一个服务器，其生命中的目的是
is to listen for HTTP requests.
监听 HTTP 请求。
And as soon as it receives one from a browser,
一旦它从浏览器收到一个请求，
be it mine or anyone else's, it will respond with the contents of that file.
无论是我的还是任何其他人的，它都将使用该文件的内容进行响应。
So let me go into VS Code here.
所以让我进入这里的 VS Code。
Let me reopen my terminal window.
让我重新打开我的终端窗口。
And I'm going to go ahead and literally run http-server Enter.
我会继续直接运行 http-server Enter。
And now you'll see a whole bunch of output, most of which
现在你会看到一大堆输出，其中大部分
isn't germane to our discussion yet.
还没有与我们的讨论相关。
But here is this URL here.
但这里就是这个 URL。
And if I hover over it, I'll see a little Open URL pop up
如果我将鼠标悬停在它上面，我会看到一个小的“打开 URL”弹出窗口
that I can click on, or on my Mac, I can Command click on the URL itself,
我可以点击它，或者在我的 Mac 上，我可以使用 Command 点击 URL 本身，
and that will open up in a new tab this folder.
这将在新标签中打开此文件夹。
So this is going to look a little esoteric at first glance.
所以乍一看，这将看起来有点深奥。
But this is what's called a directory listing.
但这就是所谓的目录列表。
It's just literally the contents of the folder that I'm in.
它只是我所在的文件夹的内容。
So I'm in my Codespaces default folder.
所以我位于我的 Codespaces 默认文件夹中。
I deleted everything from last week and weeks prior.
我删除了上周和更早几周的所有内容。
Your folder will, of course, have many other things
你的文件夹当然会有很多其他东西
that you've created and kept.
你已经创建并保留了。
I have a Source 8 directory that I downloaded
我有一个 Source 8 目录，我已经提前下载了
in advance because it's got all of today's examples made in advance.
提前，因为它包含了今天所有提前制作的示例。
But there's the file I just created.
但那是刚刚创建的文件。
And there's some other information here, like the date and time at which
这里还有一些其他信息，比如我创建此文件的日期和时间，等等。
I created this file, and so forth.
我创建了这个文件，等等。
But you'll see that this is just a web page that lives at this URL here.
但你会看到，这只是一个位于此 URL 的网页。
And this is actually somewhat specific to Codespaces,
而这实际上是针对 Codespaces 的，
the infrastructure we're using.
我们正在使用的基础设施。
But if I Zoom in up here, you'll see that I am effectively
但如果我在上面放大，你会看到我实际上是在
running my own web server at this weird looking URL
在我的这个奇怪的 URL 上运行自己的网络服务器
that GitHub dynamically generated for us, for me.
GitHub 为我们动态生成的，为我生成的。
And you'll have a different unique one as well.
你也会有不同的唯一 URL。
You'll see that baked into this URL is actually a port number.
你会看到实际上在 URL 中包含一个端口号。
And they're doing some trickery.
他们正在做一些欺骗。
Normally, I would have to access this web server at Port 80, or 443,
通常，我必须在端口 80 或 443 上访问此网络服务器，
or even 8080.
甚至 8080。
And the reason for this is because cs50.dev,
而原因是，因为 cs50.dev，
that is to say Codespaces, the tool that we're using in the cloud,
也就是说 Codespaces，我们在云端使用的工具，
is obviously itself already a web server.
本身就已经是一个网络服务器了。
And it's GitHub's web server that's listening already on Port 80 and 443.
并且它是 GitHub 的网络服务器，已经在端口 80 和 443 上监听了。
So if I want to run my own web server on their web server,
所以如果我想在他们的网络服务器上运行自己的网络服务器，
I just have to pick another port number.
我只需要选择另一个端口号。
And so what you're seeing in the URL here is a hint of that.
所以你在这里看到的 URL 就是一个暗示。
By convention, the program I just ran, http-server, does not try to use 80.
按照惯例，我刚刚运行的程序 http-server 不会尝试使用 80。
It does not try to use 443.
它不会尝试使用 443。
It uses 8080 by default. And that's why you see it in the URL here.
它默认使用 8080。这就是你在 URL 中看到它的原因。
And underneath the hood, that virtual envelope actually contains Port 8080.
在幕后，那个虚拟信封实际上包含了端口 8080。
Because this is not an official web server.
因为这不是一个官方的网络服务器。
This is not CS50.dev or GitHub.dev.
这不是 CS50.dev 或者 GitHub.dev。
This is little old me trying to serve up my brand new hello.html file.
这是我这个老家伙试图提供我的全新的 hello.html 文件。
But the point here is this.
但重点在这里。
When I click on this file, I should see the results of my hard work.
当我点击这个文件时，我应该看到我辛勤工作的成果。
And there is a big white box, otherwise known as the view port, inside of which
而且有一个大的白色框，也称为视窗，在其中
are the only words in the body of my page, hello, body.
是我的页面主体中唯一的单词，hello, body。
And if I scroll up further, you'll see in my tab here hello comma title.
如果我继续向上滚动，你会在我的标签中看到 hello逗号标题。
So this now maps back to the code we just saw.
所以现在它映射回我们刚刚看到的代码。
Here is the HTML that I just pulled up in my browser.
这是我刚刚在浏览器中打开的 HTML。
And it is what told the browser what to do visually.
并且它告诉了浏览器在视觉上该怎么做。
So let's walk through this top to bottom.
所以让我们从上到下走一遍。
This first line here is what's called the document type declaration.
这里的第一行叫做文档类型声明。
Honestly, you just copy paste this nowadays.
老实说，你 nowadays 只是复制粘贴它。
And it means hey, browser, I'm using version 5 of HTML.
这意味着嘿，浏览器，我正在使用 HTML 第 5 版。
Odds are in some number of years, this line
在几年后，这一行
might change over time to indicate different versions.
可能会随着时间的推移而改变，以指示不同的版本。
But for now, this just means I'm using the latest version of this HTML
但现在，这仅仅意味着我正在使用此 HTML 的最新版本
language.
语言。
That's kind of anomaly, because you're not going
这有点异常，因为你不会
to see this exclamation point again.
再次看到这个感叹号。
Everywhere else, you're going to see a lot of less than signs
在其他地方，你会看到很多小于号
and greater than signs or angled brackets, so to speak.
和大于号，或者说是尖括号。
But they're almost always going to be symmetric, as follows.
但它们几乎总是对称的，如下所示。
This tag here, this is an HTML tag, says, hey browser, here comes my HTML.
这里这个标签，这是一个 HTML 标签，意思是，浏览器，我的 HTML 代码来了。
And this is what's known as an attribute.
而这被称为属性。
So anything after the name of a tag is what we'd call an attribute.
所以，标签名后面的任何东西我们都称之为属性。
And attributes can have values.
属性可以有值。
Those values that are associated with the attributes with an equal sign
与属性相关联的值用等号
and typically quotation marks, single quotes or double quotes,
以及通常的引号，单引号或双引号，
as in this case.
就像这种情况。
So here we, again, have that paradigm of a dictionary, key, value, pairs.
所以在这里，我们再次看到了字典的模式，键值对。
They're everywhere in computing, even though the syntax obviously
它们在计算领域无处不在，尽管语法显然
keeps changing, whether when we're in SQL, or Python, or now HTML.
一直在改变，无论是在 SQL 中，还是在 Python 中，抑或是在现在的 HTML 中。
This tag at the very bottom now means hey, browser, that's it for my HTML.
最下面的这个标签意思是，浏览器，我的 HTML 代码到此为止了。
So when you see a tag that looks like another,
所以，当你看到一个标签看起来像另一个标签，
but starts with a forward slash--
但以正斜杠开头 -
and you do not need to repeat the attributes, that would just
而且你不必重复属性，那样的话，
be very annoying to have to type it here and here, we
在这里和这里输入就会很烦人，所以我们
keep it succinct-- this is what's known as a close tag, or an end tag that
保持简洁 - 这被称为闭合标签，或结束标签，它
conceptually corresponds to this start tag or open tag.
在概念上对应于这个开始标签或打开标签。
So they're sort of symmetric.
所以它们有点对称。
Inside of that are two children, so to speak.
在里面有两个孩子，可以这么说。
So there's actually a notion of a family tree-type hierarchy here, or a tree,
所以这里实际上有一个家族树类型的层次结构，或者说是一棵树，
as we've discussed in data structures.
正如我们在数据结构中所讨论的。
The HTML tag, per the indentation here, has
HTML 标签，根据这里的缩进，它有
one child called head and another child called body.
一个叫做 head 的孩子，另一个叫做 body 的孩子。
Everything between the start tag and an end tag
开始标签和结束标签之间的所有内容
here is what's also generically known as an element.
这里也被通称为元素。
So this is the head element.
所以这是 head 元素。
This is the body element.
这是 body 元素。
A bunch of new vocab, but it's not that intellectually interesting.
一堆新的词汇，但并不那么有趣。
It's just jargon that we'll use.
这只是我们使用的术语。
Here means hey, browser, here comes the head of my page.
这里的意思是，浏览器，我的页面头部来了。
So like the very top of it, which generally for now
所以，就像最上面的部分，目前一般来说
means just the title bar.
指的是标题栏。
In fact, this means, hey, browser, here comes the title of my page.
事实上，这意味着，浏览器，我的页面标题来了。
And then here, notice there's no more angle brackets.
然后在这里，注意没有更多尖括号了。
This is literally raw text.
这纯粹是原始文本。
And this is why we saw in the actual gray tab of my browser hello comma
而这就是为什么我们在浏览器的灰色标签中看到了 hello,
title.
title。
This means, hey, browser, that's it for the title.
这意味着，浏览器，标题到此为止了。
This means, hey, browser, that's it for the head.
这意味着，浏览器，头部到此为止了。
Meanwhile, down here, hey, browser, here comes the body of my main page.
同时，在下面，浏览器，我的主页面主体来了。
Like, 90-plus percent of the page inside of the so-called viewport,
比如，90% 以上的页面都在所谓的视窗内，
the big rectangular region, hey, browser, here comes the body.
这个大的矩形区域，浏览器，主体来了。
Hey, browser, sir, that's it for the body.
浏览器，主体到此为止了。
What is in the body?
主体里有什么？
In this super simple case, literally just hello comma body.
在这个超级简单的例子中，只是 hello, body。
That's it.
就是这样。
So HTML really is that pedantic.
所以 HTML 真的很刻板。
It just tells the browser start doing this.
它只是告诉浏览器开始执行此操作。
Stop doing this.
停止执行此操作。
Start.
开始。
Stop.
停止。
Start.
开始。
Stop.
停止。
And that's how it knows what to do, top to bottom,
这就是它如何知道要做什么，从上到下，
left to right when actually reading the code therein.
从左到右，当实际读取其中的代码时。
All right.
好的。
Questions about any of this here HTML code.
关于这里任何 HTML 代码的问题？
And yeah, in front?
还有，前面？
AUDIENCE: Would browsers be considered a HTML interpreter?
观众：浏览器可以被视为 HTML 解释器吗？
DAVID MALAN: Say that again?
大卫·马兰：再说一遍？
AUDIENCE: Would browsers be considered a HTML code interpreter?
观众：浏览器可以被视为 HTML 代码解释器吗？
DAVID MALAN: Oh, yes.
大卫·马兰：哦，是的。
I think that's fair.
我认为这是合理的。
The question is, can browsers be considered HTML interpreters?
问题是，浏览器可以被视为 HTML 解释器吗？
Yes, I don't think people tend to call it that.
是的，我不认为人们倾向于这样称呼它。
Interpretation generally implies that you're
解释通常意味着你正在
parsing something that's logical in nature, your functions, loops,
解析本质上是逻辑的东西，你的函数、循环，
conditionals, and so forth.
条件语句等等。
Parser is a term you might indeed hear much more often.
解析器是你可能经常听到的一个词。
A parser is a piece of software that analyzes code,
解析器是一段分析代码的软件，
analyzes text top to bottom, left to right,
从上到下，从左到右分析文本，
breaks it down into chunks that have semantic meaning, like the tags,
将其分解成具有语义含义的块，比如标签，
like the attributes, like the elements that we're talking about
比如属性，比如我们正在谈论的元素，
and then it displays them, in this case.
然后它显示它们，在这种情况下。
There's not as much to interpret in quite the same way.
没有那么多东西需要以完全相同的方式解释。
But that's reasonable, nonetheless.
但这仍然是合理的。
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: With all the frameworks, do you
观众：有了所有的框架，你
think is is worth learning HTML from scratch
认为是否值得从头开始学习 HTML
or just use a Bootstrap [INAUDIBLE]?
还是直接使用 Bootstrap？
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
大卫·马兰：非常好的问题。
With all the frameworks out there, should you
有了所有的框架，你是否应该
bother learning HTML and writing it from scratch or using frameworks,
费心学习 HTML 并从头开始编写，还是使用框架，
like something called Bootstrap.
比如像 Bootstrap 这样的东西。
Well, we spent a few minutes today talking about that very framework.
好吧，我们今天花了几分钟时间谈论了这个框架。
But even frameworks like Bootstrap absolutely
但即使像 Bootstrap 这样的框架也绝对
assume that something about HTML, something
假设一些关于 HTML 的东西，一些
also about something called CSS, more on that in a bit, and better still,
也关于一些叫做 CSS 的东西，稍后会详细介绍，更重要的是，
something about JavaScript.
一些关于 JavaScript 的东西。
If you really don't want to know and understand these things,
如果你真的不想了解和理解这些东西，
that's when you reach for like a third party service,
这时你就会选择第三方服务，
like Squarespace nowadays or Wix, where you really just click and drag and drop
比如现在的 Squarespace 或 Wix，在那里你只需要点击、拖动和放置
and create websites that are, at the end of the day, still HTML.
然后创建网站，最终它们仍然是 HTML。
But the developers at Wix and Squarespace
但 Wix 和 Squarespace 的开发者
have automated the process with a graphical user interface
已经用图形用户界面自动化了这个过程
or GUI of letting you create it.
或者说 GUI 让你创建它。
But even then, most web developers, or even just business people
who want to create their own website and they're not
programmers themselves or technical folks,
they might still like to know a little something about HTML, CSS,
and JavaScript because then you can open like the advanced settings
and configure things.
And indeed, that's a frustration that you'll
tend to feel if you can't quite drop down conceptually to that level.
All right.
So just to make this a little more--
to give you more of a mental model for this,
this indentation is not strictly necessary.
Kind of, like, in C, where we care, where style50 cares, but not
Clang, about what your code looks like.
Similarly, browsers are pretty tolerant.
You can have all of this white space, all of this pretty indentation.
Or you cannot.
It's not going to care, generally, one way or the other.
However, this is certainly much more readable.
But we'll see next week as we start to generate HTML automatically,
it's not always important that the code you generate be pretty printed.
But when you're writing in this format, it absolutely
should be when you're collaborating or submitting to other people.
So this, though, is what we would call a tree representation of this.
So here is that hierarchy.
So if we think of the whole web page as what's generally known as a document,
that document has a root element called the HTML element, which
it's open HTML tag and its closed tag.
It has, as I claim, two children.
The head tag has one child title.
And then both of those leaf nodes, or leaves
to borrow the family tree vernacular, have text nodes of hello, title
and hello, body, respectively.
So this is going to be useful later today because it turns out,
with JavaScript, an actual programming language,
we can start to modify this tree in the computer's memory or RAM
and make the page dynamically change by essentially
creating new HTML on the fly, even if that didn't come from the server.
Case in point, many of you use Gmail or maybe Outlook.
Generally speaking, you don't have to reload the page
to see if you've got new mail.
It just magically appears at the top of the page in kind of a stack.
And it just keeps pushing old mail down, down, down.
Well, that's going to be the result of some JavaScript
code updating this tree in memory.
And it has the effect of just dynamically generating
more and more HTML that represents your email's inbox, for instance.
All right.
So with that said, why don't we go ahead and actually
try this out in a couple of ways.
So let me go back to VS Code here.
Let me propose to actually tweak my code here a little bit.
So let me go into, let's see, my VS Code editor here.
Let me zoom out.
And notice down below, actually, all this time
as I was clicking on hello.html, my HTTP server program
actually is outputting sort of the logs from a server.
It turns out any time you request a page with a browser from a server,
that server is probably logging a little something about you.
One, it's probably logging your IP address.
Two, it's probably logging the type of browser
you're using Chrome, or Safari, or Edge, or something like that.
It's probably logging the operating system version you're using,
be it Windows, or Mac OS, or Android, or iOS, or the like,
and maybe some other information as well.
We won't dwell on this today.
But there's a lot of information that will be logged about you, even if you
are in incognito mode or private mode.
So more on that next week.
And today, unlike all past lectures, even though by default you
see this in your own code space, you see here
a ports tab, which for the most part is not that useful for us today.
But you will see that this row here mentions HTTP server.
Why?
Because in my terminal, that command is still running.
It is a server.
And it's just there living to serve now by waiting and waiting and waiting
for me to click on more of those links.
And every time I do click on a link, I'll see another line of output here.
But it turns out that all this time in your ports tab of VS Code, you
can see all of the TCP ports, for instance, that are in use.
Now generally, you haven't needed any of those, at least for your own work.
But notice that HTTP server is indeed listening on Port 8080.
CS50 has some of its own customizations.
And this is a bit of a geek Easter egg.
But we presume to use Port 1337, which perhaps those more comfortable
will know what it means.
This is like leetspeak.
So it actually spells Leet if you're cool and use a 1, 7, and 2, 3.
OK.
So anyhow, we chose that port number.
But there are some conventions.
Next week we're going to actually start using Port 5,000, which
isn't in use at the moment.
目前没有使用。
But long story short, you can see this stuff underneath the hood.
但长话短说，你可以在引擎盖下面看到这些东西。
And indeed, we're just sort of peeling back
事实上，我们只是剥开
some of these layers that have been there now for some time.
一些已经存在了一段时间的层。
Well, let's go ahead and do this.
好吧，让我们继续做吧。
I'm going to go ahead and create another terminal window using my plus icon down
我将继续使用我的加号图标创建一个新的终端窗口
here in the console.
这里在控制台中。
Notice that at the right-hand side of my screen, I now have two bash shells.
注意，在我的屏幕右侧，现在我有两个 bash shell。
Bash is the name of your prompt, so to speak, where the dollar sign is.
Bash 就是你的提示符的名称，可以这么说，美元符号所在的地方。
If I click on the first one, there's HTTP server.
如果我点击第一个，那里有 HTTP 服务器。
It's still running.
它还在运行。
And I want it to keep running today.
我今天想让它继续运行。
But I'd also like to be able to run more commands in my code space.
但我也想在我的代码空间中运行更多命令。
So I've simply created a second terminal.
所以我只是创建了第二个终端。
And I can go back and forth by clicking it right.
我可以通过点击它来回切换。
Let me go ahead now and copy hello.html like that and create a brand new file
现在让我继续复制 hello.html，就像那样，创建一个全新的文件
called--
叫做——
how about paragraphs.html?
paragraphs.html 怎么样？
And in paragraphs.html, I'm going to first paste all of that.
在 paragraphs.html 中，我将首先粘贴所有这些。
I'm going to hide my terminal window now without stopping HTTP server.
我将现在隐藏我的终端窗口，而不会停止 HTTP 服务器。
And I'm going to go ahead and just create some paragraphs of text.
我将继续创建一些文本段落。
And in fact, let me go ahead and cheat here real quick.
事实上，让我在这里快速作弊一下。
I'm going to go ahead and, in my other window here secretly, open up
我将继续，在我的另一个窗口里偷偷地打开
a whole bunch of text so that I can grab some Latin-like text to copy paste.
一大堆文本，这样我就可以获取一些类似拉丁文的文本进行复制粘贴。
So now I'm back.
所以现在我回来了。
And all I did was secretly copy paste a whole bunch of text.
我所做的就是偷偷地复制粘贴了一大堆文本。
I'm going to make a couple of changes to this file, where I currently
我将对这个文件做一些修改，我现在
have just a title and a body.
只有标题和正文。
One, I'm going to rename this to paragraphs, just so I can keep straight
第一，我将把它重命名为 paragraphs，这样我就可以保持直观
which file is which.
哪个文件是哪个。
And down here, I'm going to go ahead and paste in a big paragraph of text.
在这里，我将继续粘贴一段很长的文本。
This is not actually Latin.
这实际上不是拉丁语。
It's sort of lorem ipsum text, which is Latin-like random words that's
这是一种 lorem ipsum 文本，它是一种类似拉丁语的随机词语
meant to look like Latin.
看起来像拉丁语。
And typographers historically used this as sort of placeholders
排版人员历史上使用它作为占位符
for actual text.
用于实际文本。
But notice this is a pretty decently long paragraph.
但请注意，这是一个相当长的段落。
And so it's going to make my web page a bit bigger.
所以它会让我的网页变得更大。
So let me go back to my other tab, where I have hello.html open from before.
所以让我回到我的另一个标签页，在那里我之前打开了 hello.html。
Let me click back.
让我点击回去。
And now notice, in my directory listing, I have a new file, paragraphs.html.
现在请注意，在我的目录列表中，我有一个新的文件，paragraphs.html。
Let me go ahead and open that up.
让我继续打开它。
And voila, there is a big paragraph of text.
瞧，那里有一段很长的文本。
Just for fun, let me create three such paragraphs.
为了好玩，让我创建三个这样的段落。
So I'm going to cheat temporarily and just copy and paste two more times.
所以我将暂时作弊，复制粘贴两次。
But I'm going to separate it with a blank line,
但我会用空白行隔开它，
as you would in, like, Google Docs or Microsoft Word for paragraphs
就像你在 Google Docs 或 Microsoft Word 中对段落所做的那样
in English or any language.
在英语或任何语言中。
And I'm going to go back to my paragraphs.
我将回到我的段落。
Nothing has changed yet because HTTP, just like the exercise with Phyllis
还没有变化，因为 HTTP，就像与 Phyllis 的练习一样
and Brian, requires that we send the packets back and forth if we
和 Brian 一样，要求我们在想要获取更新的内容时来回发送数据包。
want to get updated content.
想要获取更新的内容。
So I have to click my browser's reload button, or hit Control R or Command R,
所以我必须点击浏览器的刷新按钮，或者按下 Control R 或 Command R，
depending on your browser or OS, and notice that when I do that,
取决于你的浏览器或操作系统，请注意，当我这样做时，
I definitely get more text.
我肯定会得到更多文本。
But it just looks like one big blob, not three separate paragraphs.
但它看起来像一个大块，而不是三个独立的段落。
What might your intuition be for why that
你的直觉是什么，为什么
is, even though I've clearly indented this and given blank lines between?
是这样的，即使我清楚地缩进了它并在它们之间留下了空白行？
Yeah?
是吧？
AUDIENCE: HTML doesn't care about the whitespace.
观众：HTML 不关心空白。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
So HTML doesn't care about the whitespace or technically,
所以 HTML 不关心空白，或者更准确地说，
more than one whitespace.
不止一个空白。
I can hit as many Enters as I want.
我可以按任意多个 Enter 键。
All of them are going to be ignored except for a single space.
除了一个空格之外，所有这些都会被忽略。
It's going to be normalized to just a single space.
它将被规范化为一个空格。
In general, this is useful.
总的来说，这很有用。
Because it means I can pretty print my HTML and indent things visually,
因为这意味着我可以美化我的 HTML 并直观地缩进东西，
even if I don't want the browser to indent anything manually for me.
即使我不希望浏览器为我手动缩进任何东西。
But here's where we're going to need some more tags.
但这里我们需要一些额外的标签。
And it turns out the simplest fix for this problem
事实证明，解决这个问题最简单的办法
is to use the paragraph tag.
就是使用段落标签。
And for short, it's just open bracket p close bracket.
简而言之，就是左尖括号 p 右尖括号。
I'm going to be a little pedantic, and even though VS Code
我要有点迂腐，即使 VS Code
is being a little annoying because it's trying to autocomplete my thoughts
有点烦人，因为它试图自动完成我的想法
but I don't want it to autocomplete just yet,
但我现在不想让它自动完成，
sometimes you have to fight with the text editor.
有时你必须与文本编辑器作斗争。
So these autocomplete features have upsides and downsides.
所以这些自动完成功能有优点也有缺点。
But I'm going to go ahead and put a paragraph tag,
但我将继续添加一个段落标签，
open and close around each of these paragraphs.
在每个段落的开头和结尾添加一个。
And I'm going to maintain my indentation, just to keep
我将保持我的缩进，只是为了保持
it visually clean on the screen.
它在屏幕上视觉上整洁。
And now I'm going to put this one last close tag on this line here.
现在我要在这行里添加最后一个闭合标签。
And so it's a lot more verbose.
所以它更加冗长。
But notice that it's effectively telling the browser start a paragraph,
但请注意，它实际上是在告诉浏览器开始一个段落，
end a paragraph, start a paragraph, end a paragraph, and so forth.
结束一个段落，开始一个段落，结束一个段落，等等。
So if I go back to my other tab and I click Reload,
所以如果我回到另一个标签页并点击刷新，
now we have some semblance of what I expected,
现在我们有一些我期望的东西，
which is three separate paragraphs in this case.
在这种情况下，就是三个独立的段落。
All right?
好吧？
So that's the p tag, the paragraph tag.
所以这就是 p 标签，段落标签。
P for short, because as you'll see, many of these tags are
p 是缩写，因为你会看到，许多标签都是
abbreviated just because they're slightly faster to type.
缩写的，因为它们输入起来稍微快一点。
Let's do another example.
让我们再举一个例子。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
让我回到 VS Code。
I'm going to copy this text.
我要复制这段文字。
I'm going to create a new file called--
我要创建一个新文件，叫做——
how about headings.html?
叫 headings.html 好吗？
And I'm going to paste this, close my terminal just to give me more room.
然后我粘贴它，关闭我的终端，以便给我更多的空间。
I'm going to rename the title to be Headings,
我要把标题重命名为 Headings，
just to keep straight which is which.
仅仅为了区分它们。
I'm going to delete all of these paragraphs to make it-- actually,
我要删除所有这些段落，以便—— 实际上，
no, let's not do that.
不，我们别这样做。
Let's keep the paragraphs.
让我们保留这些段落。
But like an academic paper or a textbook,
但是就像一篇学术论文或一本教科书，
let's give these chapter headings or section headings or the like.
让我们给这些章节标题或段落标题之类的。
Well, I could just do something like this.
嗯，我可以这样去做。
How about 1?
1 怎么样？
And then down here I could put 2, and then down here I could put 3.
然后在这里我可以写 2，然后在这里我可以写 3。
But of course, if I reload this, it's not really going to look as I-- whoops,
但是当然，如果我重新加载这个，它看起来并不像我—— 哎呦，
if I go back to this directory listing, open up headings.html, it's fine.
如果我回到这个目录列表，打开 headings.html，它看起来没问题。
It's not super pretty.
它并不非常漂亮。
But it would be nice to give a little more prominence to these headings.
但是，给这些标题多一点突出显示效果会更好。
And in fact, there's a bunch of tags for this.
实际上，有很多标签可以实现这个。
I can use H1, for instance, for one really big heading.
例如，我可以使用 H1 来表示一个非常大的标题。
And then let me close the tag over here and indent.
然后让我在这里关闭标签并缩进。
Then down here-- and, again, whitespace doesn't matter,
然后在这里—— 再次说明，空格并不重要，
so I'm going to give myself a little bit of breathing room just so it's clear
所以我要给自己一点呼吸空间，这样看起来就很清楚
which of these is which.
哪些是哪些。
For this, maybe it's not Chapter 2, but Section 2.
对于这个，也许它不是第 2 章，而是第 2 节。
So let me do H2.
所以让我使用 H2。
And then inside of this, I'm going to go ahead and do 2.
然后在这个里面，我会继续使用 2。
And just to be clear, I don't have to put these on their own lines.
为了更清楚，我不必把它们放在单独的行上。
I'm just doing that to be a bit pedantic.
我只是这样做的，有点迂腐。
You can technically just do this and keep everything on one line.
你实际上可以这样做，把所有东西都放在一行上。
But I'll be consistent, at least.
但是，至少我会保持一致。
But either approach is fine.
但是两种方法都可以。
And then, down here, I'm going to use maybe a sub subsection.
然后，在这里，我可能会使用一个子子部分。
So let me delete this and do h3.
所以让我删除这个并使用 h3。
I'm just going to write the word three.
我只是要写单词 three。
And then just to be neat, I'm going to indent everything like this here.
然后，为了整洁，我将在这里将所有内容缩进。
So now if I go back to headings and I reload,
所以现在，如果我回到 headings 并重新加载，
I'm going to get some default formatting.
我将获得一些默认格式。
It might not be the formatting you want, but it
它可能不是你想要的格式，但是它
looks like it's big and bold, but in decreasing order.
看起来它很大，很粗体，但是按照降序排列。
H1 is the biggest.
H1 是最大的。
H2 is smaller.
H2 更小。
H3 is even smaller.
H3 更小。
And you can go down to h6.
你可以一直到 h6。
And it gets smaller and smaller.
它会越来越小。
And at that point, if you've got, like, sub sub sub sub
在这一点上，如果你有，像，子子子子
subsections of your book or paper, you're probably organizing it poorly.
你书或论文的子部分，你可能组织得不好。
So they stop at some point there.
所以它们会在某个点停止。
All right.
好的。
Well, what else can we do in HTML?
好吧，我们还能在 HTML 中做什么？
These things are omnipresent.
这些东西无处不在。
Let me copy this HTML and close that tab, open my terminal,
让我复制这个 HTML 并关闭那个标签，打开我的终端，
and create a new file, like, code list.html.
并创建一个新文件，例如，code list.html。
And let's make a list of information.
让我们做一个信息列表。
Let me just paste that HTML, just to save some time today, and change
让我只是粘贴那个 HTML，仅仅是为了节省今天的一些时间，并改变
my title to list.
我的标题为 list。
Let me get rid of all of these paragraphs, just to simplify things.
让我去掉所有这些段落，仅仅为了简化。
So now I'm sort of back to where I began.
所以现在我回到了开始的地方。
And then inside of the body of this page, let me go ahead and make a list,
然后在这个页面的 body 中，让我继续创建一个列表，
like foo, bar, baz.
像 foo、bar、baz。
If you've never heard these words, these are, like,
如果你从未听说过这些词，这些词，就像，
computer scientists go-to words.
计算机科学家的常用词。
A mathematician might choose x, y, and z by default.
一个数学家可能会默认选择 x、y 和 z。
CS people tend to go with foo, bar, and baz for historical reasons.
CS 人倾向于使用 foo、bar 和 baz，出于历史原因。
So here's a list of three arbitrary words.
所以这里是一个包含三个任意词的列表。
If I go over to my other tab, go back to my directory listing,
如果我切换到另一个标签，回到我的目录列表，
there's my new file.
这是我的新文件。
Let's click on list.html, same problem.
让我们点击 list.html，同样的问题。
It's a list.
它是一个列表。
But it's not one after the other.
但是它们不是一个接一个。
Last time, of course, we fixed this with paragraphs.
上次，当然，我们用段落解决了这个问题。
But you know what'd be nice?
但你知道什么会更好吗？
To make it a little prettier, like a bulleted list, which
把它弄得更漂亮一些，就像一个项目符号列表，它
are kind of everywhere these days.
现在到处都是。
So I could try to simulate this.
所以我可以尝试模拟它。
And you might be in the habit of doing this in some programs.
你可能习惯在一些程序中这样做。
But of course, if I go back to my other tab, Reload,
但是当然，如果我回到另一个标签，重新加载，
I'm just sort of making the problem worse visually.
我只是让这个问题在视觉上更糟糕。
But it turns out--
但是事实证明——
let me undo that-- there is an unordered list tag, otherwise known
让我撤销—— 有一个无序列表标签，也称为
as ul for short, that I can put all three
简称 ul，我可以把所有三个
of these words in an unordered list.
词放到一个无序列表中。
Let me go ahead and indent everything consistently.
让我继续并将所有内容缩进。
But to have three items in this list, I actually
但是为了在这个列表中拥有三个项目，我实际上
need another tag, a list item tag.
需要另一个标签，一个列表项标签。
And I'm going to go ahead and add that tag there, list item here and there,
我会继续在那里添加那个标签，这里和那里添加列表项，
and then another list item tag here.
然后在这里添加另一个列表项标签。
And here's where it's a stylistic choice.
而这里是一个风格选择。
I could move foo and bar and baz onto their own lines.
我可以将 foo、bar 和 baz 移动到它们自己的行上。
But this is going to start to get excessively tall, like, too
但是这样会开始变得过高，就像，太多
much white space.
空白。
So reasonable people will disagree.
所以，理性的人会不同意。
But this feels a little more readable to me.
但是，我觉得这样更易读。
So I'm going to leave it as such.
所以我会保持不变。
Go back to my other tab.
回到我的另一个标签。
And now when I reload, you get a nice bulleted list by default.
现在，当我重新加载时，你会得到一个默认的漂亮项目符号列表。
And you see these all over the web.
你可以在网上看到这些。
What if I want to have a numbered list, that is to say, ordered list?
如果我想有一个编号列表，也就是说，有序列表呢？
Any instincts for changing these bullets to numbers?
您想将这些项目符号改为数字吗？
So ol is a good instinct.
所以用 ol 标签是一个不错的直觉。
And, indeed, sometimes HTML makes perfect sense.
确实，有时 HTML 非常合乎逻辑。
As in this case, if I change ul to ol, I don't have to manually number anything.
就像在这种情况下，如果我将 ul 改为 ol，我就不用手动编号了。
Because when I reload, it's going to use Arabic numerals automatically
因为当我重新加载时，它会自动使用阿拉伯数字
for me like this, top to bottom.
像这样，从上到下。
And what's nice about this is, if I go in and I insert things in the middle,
好处是，如果我在中间插入内容，
I don't have to manually renumber things.
我不用手动重新编号。
The browser is going to do the counting for me.
浏览器会帮我计数。
And if you're doing an outline, you can actually
如果你正在做大纲，你可以实际上
specify whether you want 1, 2, 3, or A, B, C, or I,
指定你想要 1, 2, 3 还是 A, B, C 或者 I，
double I, triple I, or so forth.
双 I，三 I 等等。
There's different numbering systems you can use.
你可以使用不同的编号系统。
But by default, we get our decimal numbers here.
但默认情况下，我们会在这里得到十进制数字。
I'm going quickly.
我讲得很快。
But it's hard to get too excited about bulleted lists and such.
但很难对项目符号列表之类的东西过于兴奋。
But any questions on these tags thus far?
到目前为止，对这些标签还有什么问题吗？
We'll by design try to escalate quickly momentarily.
我们设计上会尽快升级。
All right.
好的。
So how about just a few other tags to make things more visually interesting?
那么，我们来学习一些其他的标签，让内容看起来更有趣吧？
Let me go ahead here and cheat by opening up a file
我来打开一个我提前准备好的文件，
that I made in advance that's going to demonstrate what a table looks like.
来展示一个表格长什么样。
So here let me open a file that I brought with me called table.html.
我来打开一个我带来的名为 table.html 的文件。
And because I brought it with me, I actually included a comment at the top.
因为我把它带来了，我在顶部加了一个注释。
And in fact, if you download today's files from the website,
事实上，如果你从网站上下载今天的文件，
you'll see that they're generally commented,
你会发现它们通常都有注释，
like our C code and Python code was.
就像我们的 C 代码和 Python 代码一样。
It's a little weird.
有点奇怪。
But here is the syntax for a comment in HTML.
但这是 HTML 中注释的语法。
It's a less than sign, or open bracket, then an exclamation point, then dash
是一个小于号，或左括号，然后是一个感叹号，然后是连字符
dash, two hyphens.
连字符，两个连字符。
Then at the very end of the comment, it's almost the opposite but not quite.
然后在注释的最后，它几乎是相反的，但并不完全一样。
It's hyphen hyphen close bracket instead.
而是连字符连字符右括号。
Why these symbols?
为什么是这些符号？
Humans probably decided years ago that there's
人们可能在很多年前就决定了，
no way someone's going to accidentally type or rather, intentionally
没有人会意外地输入，或者说，故意输入
type those characters visually.
这些字符。
So let's use them for comment symbols as well.
所以我们也用它们作为注释符号。
If you really want to type them, there is a way around that.
如果你真的想输入它们，有一种方法可以绕过。
But here is my table title.
但这是我的表格标题。
And here is just kind of a little, maybe, guessing game.
这有点像一个小游戏，猜猜看。
Here is a table tag with a tr child.
这里有一个 table 标签，它有一个 tr 子标签。
And here's the closed child.
这是它的闭合子标签。
And then there's a bunch of td tags.
然后还有很多 td 标签。
So I'll give you tr stands for table row.
我告诉你 tr 代表 table row（表格行）。
td stands for table data, AKA cell, to borrow language
td 代表 table data（表格数据），也称为 cell（单元格），借用一下
from, like, spreadsheet software.
类似于电子表格软件中的术语。
Does anyone want to guess what this file is
有人想猜猜看，如果我在浏览器中打开 table.html，这个文件会
going to look like if I open table.html in my browser?
看起来像什么吗？
What is this reminiscent of?
它让人想起什么？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: Num pad.
观众：数字键盘。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
DAVID MALAN：是的。
So it's like a numeric keypad from a phone,
所以它就像手机上的数字键盘，
for instance, if you're dialing someone's number manually.
例如，当你手动拨打某人的电话号码时。
So let me actually go to my other tab.
所以，我来切换到另一个标签。
Go back to my directory index.
回到我的目录索引。
There's table.html.
这里有 table.html。
And it's not going to look very pretty.
它看起来不太好看。
But it is structured in the way I might expect.
但它的结构符合我的预期。
And in my browser, I'm going to go ahead and just zoom in.
在我的浏览器中，我将放大。
Command plus or Control plus will generally do this.
Command 加号或 Control 加号通常可以做到这一点。
It does look like it's laid out tabular in rows and columns
它看起来像以表格形式排列成行和列
with everything very nicely aligned.
所有的内容都整齐地对齐。
So that might be useful as we get to larger and larger data sets.
因此，当我们处理越来越大的数据集时，这可能很有用。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
我回到 VS Code。
Let me create one more program, for instance.
我再创建一个程序。
And how about code image.html?
就叫 image.html 吧？
And just to save time, let me paste that code.
为了节省时间，我粘贴一下代码。
And also, let me secretly copy over a file
另外，我偷偷复制一个文件
that I brought with me that we've seen in the past.
我之前带过的文件。
Let me close my terminal.
我关闭一下终端。
I'm going to delete everything about tables from this file
我将删除这个文件中所有关于表格的内容
because I'm just saving time by copying and pasting.
因为我只是用复制粘贴来节省时间。
But I'm going to rename the top to image.
但我将把顶部改名为 image。
I'm going to get rid of the comment because it's no longer applicable.
我要删除注释，因为它不再适用。
But in the body of this page, I'm going to link to maybe an image of the Weeks
但在页面的主体部分，我将链接到 Weeks
bridge by the river.
桥的图片。
So I'm going to use an image tag, img for short.
所以我要使用一个 image 标签，简称 img。
And now, huh, it's obviously not going to be sufficient to just say image tag.
现在，显然只写 image 标签是不够的。
Because what image?
因为哪张图片呢？
So here is where attributes, again, get useful.
所以，这里属性再次发挥作用了。
This attribute earlier, though I didn't quite highlight it,
这个属性之前，虽然我没有特别强调它，
seems to indicate that this page is largely in English, as have
似乎表明这个页面大部分是用英语写的，就像我之前的页面一样，除了拉丁语的页面。
been my past ones, the Latin one aside.
这个属性在 HTML 标签上非常有用，
That attribute on the HTML tag is useful for browsers that have Google Translate
对于那些内置了 Google Translate 或类似功能的浏览器。
or something similar built in.
它对搜索引擎优化（SEO）也有用。
And also, it's useful for SEO, search engine optimization.
因为当 Google 和 Bing 在未来自动爬取我的网页时，
Because when Google and Bing sort of automatically
它们会知道我想要的大部分内容的语言是什么，这可以帮助它们索引
crawl my web page in the future, they'll know what language
我的网页，并将其保存到搜索结果中。
I intend for most of the content to be in, which might help them index
因此，对于 image 标签，我也需要一个属性。
it and keep track of it for search results.
这个属性叫做 source，简称 src。
So here, for the image tag, I'm similarly going to need an attribute.
你可以在它的引号内放置你想包含的图片名称，
And that attribute is called source, src for short.
可以使用双引号或单引号。
And what you put inside of its quotes for its value, double quotes
就是这样。
or single quotes, is the name of the image that you want to include.
And I include it in advance in my code space,
我提前在我的代码空间中包含了它，
a file called bridge dot ping from Week 4 when we played around with images.
一个名为 bridge.png 的文件，来自第 4 周，当时我们玩过图像。
And if I go ahead now and go to my other tab, go back to my directory index
如果我现在继续，然后转到我的另一个选项卡，回到我的目录索引
and zoom out, you'll see now not only bridge.png,
然后缩小，你会看到不仅有 bridge.png，
portable network graphic, which I manually copied in, but also
便携式网络图形，我手动复制了它，还有
image.html, which I just created.
image.html，我刚刚创建了它。
And voila, here is that same Weeks bridge.
瞧，这就是同一周的桥。
It's a little too big for my browser window.
它对于我的浏览器窗口来说有点太大了。
We'll see in a little bit how we can fix things like that.
我们将在稍后看到如何解决类似的问题。
But indeed, that's an image that's now embedded into the page.
但确实，那是一张现在嵌入到页面中的图像。
But notice, if this image were ever broken,
但请注意，如果这幅图像曾经损坏，
or if I had visual difficulties such that I might have screen reader
或者如果我视力有问题，以至于我可能安装了屏幕阅读器
software for accessibility installed, it's
用于辅助功能的软件，那么
generally good practice to also make sure
通常的做法是确保
that pages are accessible as possible.
页面尽可能地可访问。
And so some tags have additional attributes you can include.
因此，某些标签可以包含额外的属性。
Like, for an image here, there's actually
例如，对于这里的一幅图像，实际上
an Alt attribute that specifies alternative text
有一个 Alt 属性，它指定了替代文本
to describe this image.
来描述这幅图像。
This is what a human would see if they have
如果一个人有
a very slow interconnect connection.
非常慢的互连连接。
And before the image downloads, they can see this alternative text.
在图像下载之前，他们可以看到这个替代文本。
Or if I'm blind, I need a screen reader, I
或者如果我失明了，需要一个屏幕阅读器，我
could have these words recited to me verbally by providing this clue.
可以通过提供这个提示，让这些单词被口头朗读给我。
So it's best practice to include this, like, photo of bridge
所以最好包含这个，比如，桥的照片
so that all users can know what they're looking at, clicking on, or the like,
这样所有用户都知道他们正在看什么，点击什么，或者类似的东西，
so keeping that in mind, too.
所以也要记住这一点。
All right.
好的。
Let's do one other piece of multimedia.
让我们再做一项多媒体。
Let me close these two tabs.
让我关闭这两个选项卡。
Let me open my terminal and open up a file called video.html.
让我打开我的终端，并打开一个名为 video.html 的文件。
Let me go ahead and copy, secretly, a file called video.mp4,
让我继续复制，秘密地，一个名为 video.mp4 的文件，
which is a common video file format, and close my terminal window
这是一种常见的视频文件格式，然后关闭我的终端窗口
and go ahead and paste in here some HTML from before.
然后继续在这里粘贴一些之前的 HTML。
But let's now embed a video file, as you might if making a video-based website.
但现在让我们嵌入一个视频文件，就像你可能在制作一个基于视频的网站时一样。
Let me rename this one, too, to video.
让我把这个也重命名为 video。
Let me get rid of the old comment, which is not applicable.
让我删除旧的注释，它不再适用。
And it turns out videos are almost as simple.
事实证明，视频几乎一样简单。
There is a video tag.
有一个 video 标签。
There is a bunch of different attributes we can put on that.
我们可以添加很多不同的属性。
But I'll come back to that in a moment.
但我过一会儿会回到这一点。
But videos, because you might want to have high resolution, low resolution,
但视频，因为你可能想要有高分辨率，低分辨率，
depending on people's bandwidth, because these things can be big,
取决于人们的带宽，因为这些东西可能很大，
they actually have source children.
它们实际上有 source 子节点。
And confusingly, it's actually S-O-U-R-C-E, not S-R-C, in this case.
令人困惑的是，在这种情况下，实际上是 S-O-U-R-C-E，而不是 S-R-C。
And even more annoyingly, it takes an attribute called source.src.
更令人讨厌的是，它接受一个名为 source.src 的属性。
This is not good design.
这不是一个好的设计。
But this is what we're stuck with, video.mp4.
但这就是我们不得不接受的，video.mp4。
And then the type of this video, which you could generally
然后是这个视频的类型，你通常可以
look up if the browser doesn't recognize it, video/mp4.
查找，如果浏览器不识别它，video/mp4。
This is what's known as a content type or mime type.
这被称为内容类型或 MIME 类型。
And then, I can actually configure this.
然后，我实际上可以配置它。
And you would only know this by taking a class, reading a book,
你只有通过上课，读书，
looking at an online reference.
查看在线参考才能知道这一点。
I can actually add some video controls to the website,
我实际上可以为网站添加一些视频控件，
like a Play button, a Pause button, and all of that.
比如播放按钮，暂停按钮等等。
I can mute the video by default. And so this
我可以默认静音视频。所以这
is just going to modify the behavior of this video tag.
只是会修改这个 video 标签的行为。
But this is anomalous.
但这反常。
For some attributes, it just doesn't make sense to have values.
对于某些属性，拥有值是没有意义的。
Because muted, it sort of says all the information we need.
因为静音，它表示了我们需要的所有信息。
We could do, quote, unquote, "true."
我们可以做，“true”。
But humans decided years ago not to bother with that.
但人类几年前就决定不再理会这个问题。
So some attributes do not need value.
因此，某些属性不需要值。
So you do not need equal signs or quotation marks.
所以你不需要等号或引号。
And you would only know this from, say, documentation.
你只能从文档中知道这一点。
All right.
好的。
Let me go back to my directory listing.
让我回到我的目录列表。
Let me go back here to this here.
让我回到这里。
You'll see that there's now not only video.mp4, but also video.html.
你会看到，现在不仅有 video.mp4，还有 video.html。
I hope you'll forgive me for this.
我希望你能原谅我。
There's at least no sound.
至少没有声音。
But when I click on this page, it embeds a video here,
但当我点击这个页面时，它会在这里嵌入一个视频，
which I can then click on the controls for.
然后我可以点击它的控件。
And you see some short video file playing here, albeit without sound.
你会看到这里播放了一个简短的视频文件，尽管没有声音。
All right.
好的。
None of that, let me go back here to my VS Code.
这些都不重要，让我回到我的 VS Code。
And let's play around now with what the web is really known for,
现在让我们玩一玩，看看网络真正以什么而闻名，
which is hyperlinks.
那就是超链接。
So hypertext markup language, HTML, is all
所以超文本标记语言，HTML，都是
about linking one site to another, one page to another.
关于将一个网站链接到另一个网站，一个页面链接到另一个页面。
And nothing we've done thus far is interactive
到目前为止，我们所做的一切都没有交互性
beyond this own video controls.
除了这个视频自身的控件。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这件事。
Let me go into VS Code here.
让我进入这里的 VS Code。
And let me go ahead and create the simplest of files
然后让我继续创建一个最简单的文件
that just allows me to click on a link.
它只允许我点击一个链接。
So let me go ahead and copy this to save time,
所以让我继续复制它以节省时间，
open up VS code's terminal window.
打开 VS Code 的终端窗口。
Code a file called link.html.
创建一个名为 link.html 的文件。
I'll close my terminal.
我会关闭我的终端。
Paste this code.
粘贴这段代码。
Rename video to link.
将 video 重命名为 link。
Get rid of the actual video tag.
删除实际的 video 标签。
And in the body of this page, let's do something simple like invite people
在页面的主体中，让我们做一些简单的事情，比如邀请人们
to visit, for instance, Harvard.
访问，例如，哈佛大学。
All right.
好的。
If I now go to my directory index and reload, we'll now see link.html.
如果我现在转到我的目录索引并重新加载，我们现在将看到 link.html。
And of course, this doesn't really do anything useful,
当然，这并没有真正发挥任何作用，
because I literally just used English text.
因为我实际上只是使用了英文文本。
All right.
好的。
Well, what if I do what you're in the habit of doing
那么，如果我做你习惯做的事情呢
on social media and various websites, visit harvard.edu.
在社交媒体和各种网站上，访问 harvard.edu。
Let me go back to the web page, reload.
让我回到网页，重新加载。
The text changes.
文本改变了。
But it's clearly not automatically linking.
但它显然没有自动链接。
I still can't click on this.
我仍然无法点击它。
All right.
好的。
Well, maybe it needs to be www.harvard.edu.
好吧，也许它需要是 www.harvard.edu。
Let me go back, reload.
让我回去，重新加载。
All right.
好的。
Still not auto linking.
仍然没有自动链接。
Let me go over here.
让我到这边去。
And maybe it needs https:// and a slash at the end, like a full URL.
也许它需要 https:// 并在末尾加上一个斜杠，就像一个完整的 URL。
Let's go over here, reload.
让我们到这边去，重新加载。
And it's still not working.
它仍然没有工作。
I can highlight and copy it, but that's not very user friendly.
我可以选中并复制它，但这并不太人性化。
So what's going on?
所以发生了什么事呢？
Well, all of today's social media sites, when you copy paste a URL,
嗯，今天所有的社交媒体网站，当您复制粘贴 URL 时，
someone at the server side wrote code, be it
服务器端的人员会编写代码，无论它
in Python or JavaScript or anything else,
是用 Python 还是 JavaScript 或者其他任何语言，
to automatically notice and detect URLs and then
自动识别和检测 URL，然后
wrap them with HTML tags that actually hyperlink them.
用 HTML 标签将其包装起来，实际上将它们链接起来。
So what I actually need to do here is this.
所以，我实际上需要在这里做的是这样。
I'm going to introduce an anchor tag, a for short.
我将引入一个锚点标签，简称为 a。
The hyper reference attribute of which is the URL that I want
它的超链接属性是我想要的 URL
to send the user to, so href for short.
发送给用户的，简称为 href。
I'm going to close the tag.
我要关闭标签。
But then, in between the start tag and close tag,
但是，在开始标签和结束标签之间，
I'm now going to put the text that I want the human to see.
我现在要放上我想让人看到的文本。
So it's a lot more verbose.
所以它更加冗长。
But this is what websites like social media sites
但这就是像社交媒体网站这样的网站
are generating automatically for you when they just detect with a pattern
在它们通过模式检测到您输入的内容确实看起来像 URL 时，自动为您生成的内容。
that you have typed something that indeed looks like a URL.
您输入的内容确实看起来像 URL。
Let me go back to VS Code.
让我回到 VS Code。
Let me go back to this tab here and reload.
让我回到这里的这个选项卡并重新加载。
And now we actually see a working link.
现在我们实际上看到了一个有效的链接。
And this is going to be super small.
而且这将非常小。
You're not going to be able to see this quite well.
您可能无法很好地看到它。
But if you hover over this link, you'll generally see in most browsers
但如果您将鼠标悬停在这个链接上，您通常会在大多数浏览器中看到
a little clue at the bottom as to where you're going
在底部有一个小小的提示，告诉你将要前往哪里
to be directed before you click there.
在您点击它之前。
This can help if you're a little suspicious
这可以帮助您，如果您有点怀疑
and might not want to click on the actual link.
可能不想点击实际的链接。
It's small on my screen, but hopefully more visible on yours.
在我的屏幕上它很小，但希望在您的屏幕上更清晰。
That's not generally the case on mobile in quite, though, the same way.
不过，在手机上通常情况并非如此，情况不太一样。
But notice that this very simple primitive of anchor tags like this
但请注意，像这样简单的锚点标签
can pretty quickly be abused, unfortunately.
不幸的是，很快就会被滥用。
In fact, let me go ahead here and go back to VS Code.
事实上，让我继续，回到 VS Code。
And I could do something malicious like this,
我可以做一些像这样的恶意行为，
like, actually trick someone into applying to Harvard instead of Yale
比如，实际上欺骗某人申请哈佛而不是耶鲁大学
by just changing the href to not match the text that the human is seeing.
只需更改 href，使其与人看到的文本不匹配即可。
And if I reload the page here, you'll see
如果我在此处重新加载页面，您将看到
that it looks like I'm going to Yale.
它看起来像我要去耶鲁大学。
But notice, super small, bottom left-hand of my screen,
但请注意，我的屏幕左下角非常小，
it still says the real URL.
它仍然显示真实的 URL。
But you can get even more malicious.
但你还可以变得更加恶意。
You can not just say Yale.
你不应该仅仅说耶鲁大学。
You could literally say https://www.yale.edu/.
你可以直接说 https://www.yale.edu/。
You can make it look like a real URL, reload it.
你可以让它看起来像一个真实的 URL，然后重新加载它。
And now it's really quite malicious.
现在它真的非常恶意。
And this is representative of what you all probably know already as phishing
这代表着你们可能已经知道的钓鱼攻击
attacks, P-H-I-S-H-I-N-G, whereby you're being socially engineered.
攻击，P-H-I-S-H-I-N-G，它是一种社会工程学攻击。
People are trying to dupe you into clicking something
人们试图欺骗你点击一些东西
that leads you to your PayPal account, typically,
它通常会把你带到你的 PayPal 帐户，
so that you log into some bogus website.
这样你就会登录到一个虚假的网站。
Now you've given them access to your account and you're out some money.
现在你已经给了他们访问你帐户的权限，你会损失一些钱。
It's this simple because of, unfortunately,
之所以如此简单，是因为不幸的是，
these building blocks of HTML.
这些 HTML 的构建块。
All right.
好的。
With that said, any questions on this?
话虽如此，对此有什么问题吗？
No?
没有吗？
All right.
好的。
How about just for one final flourish before snacks will be served,
在提供点心之前，我们再做一个最后的润色，怎么样？
let me propose to introduce some final features herein.
我建议在这里介绍一些最终功能。
It turns out, and I'll open some of these premade already.
事实证明，我将打开一些已经预先制作好的文件。
Let me open up VS Code and open up a file called meta0.html.
让我打开 VS Code 并打开一个名为 meta0.html 的文件。
This has nothing to do with Meta, the social media company.
这与 Meta（社交媒体公司）无关。
It has to do with metadata, or specifically, meta tag.
它与元数据有关，或者更具体地说，与元标签有关。
It turns out that in the head of the web pages that we've written thus far,
事实证明，在我们迄今为止编写的网页的头部中，
we've only had titles.
我们只有标题。
But it turns out there's actually literally a tag
但事实证明，实际上确实有一个标签
called meta that has a couple of attributes like name and content.
名为 meta，它具有几个属性，如 name 和 content。
And this one here, it's a little arcane, but it's very common
而这一个，它有点深奥，但它非常常见
to copy paste these into the source code for websites
将这些内容复制粘贴到网站的源代码中
nowadays because essentially, this makes them mobile friendly.
如今，因为本质上，这使它们对移动设备友好。
Instead of making the font some default small size,
而不是将字体设置为默认的小尺寸，
it will take into account the width of the phone
它会考虑手机的宽度
or the tablet and sort of scale the font proportionally.
或平板电脑，并按比例缩放字体。
So there's some useful accessibility and user friendly tips like this.
因此，这里有一些有用的辅助功能和用户友好提示。
There's other use cases for meta tags like this.
像这样的元标签还有其他用例。
Let me open a file called meta1.html that I made in advance.
让我打开一个名为 meta1.html 的文件，我之前已经制作好了。
Here are three meta tags inside of this file.
在这个文件中，有三个元标签。
They're using a property attribute with a content attribute as well.
它们也使用 property 属性和 content 属性。
And this is a little more specific.
这是更具体的例子。
But nowadays, too, on social media, when you copy and paste
但如今，在社交媒体上，当你复制粘贴
a URL into a message online and hit Enter,
一个 URL 到在线消息并按下回车键时，
you very often see a preview of that link.
你会经常看到链接的预览。
It's sort of automatically generated.
它是自动生成的。
It makes a nice pretty image and some nice fonts.
它会生成一个漂亮好看的图片和一些漂亮的字体。
Where does that image come from?
这个图片是从哪里来的？
Where does that information come from?
信息从哪里来呢？
From these meta tags, any web page can have meta tags like this
从这些元标签，任何网页都可以有这样的元标签
so that when this page's URL is copy pasted
所以当这个页面的 URL 被复制粘贴
into social media sites or others, those sites
到社交媒体网站或其他网站时，这些网站
know what preview to show to humans.
就知道该向用户显示什么预览。
It comes literally from the values of these tags.
它实际上来自这些标签的值。
So for instance, this would create some user friendly preview
例如，这将创建一个用户友好的预览
that says CS50, Introduction to The Intellectual Enterprises
上面写着 CS50，计算机科学的智力事业导论
of Computer Science and The Art of Programming.
和编程艺术。
And in this case, it would show a picture of a cat
在这种情况下，它会显示一张猫的图片
as the default image for that particular page.
作为该页面的默认图片。
You have full control as a web developer over those kinds of things.
作为一名网页开发者，你可以完全控制这些东西。
Lastly, when it comes to features of HTML, let's go ahead and quickly
最后，关于 HTML 的功能，让我们快速
reimplement Google, if we may.
重新实现 Google，如果可以的话。
So let me go ahead and create a new file here called search.html.
所以，让我在这里创建一个新的文件，叫做 search.html。
Let me copy paste some code to save time.
为了节省时间，我复制粘贴了一些代码。
Let me go ahead and get rid of all of these meta
让我删除所有这些元
tags to make a different point with this one.
标签，为这个例子说明一个不同的点。
Let me get rid of that comment.
让我删除那个注释。
Change this title to be, say, search instead.
把这个标题改成搜索，例如，search。
And inside of the body here, let's do this.
在 body 中，让我们做这个。
I'm going to introduce a form tag.
我将引入一个 form 标签。
And now in the form tag, I'm going to create an input, a text input.
现在在 form 标签中，我将创建一个输入框，一个文本输入框。
And let's go ahead and let's just say that.
让我们继续并说一下。
And now I'm going to have a button that has,
现在我将有一个按钮，上面有
let's say, button, that has a value of search, so super simple and not yet
例如，一个按钮，它的值是搜索，非常简单，还没有
complete.
完成。
But let me go to my directory index and back.
但让我回到我的目录索引。
Let me open up search.html.
让我打开 search.html。
And I actually have the beginnings of a search
我实际上有了搜索的雏形
form, an interactive form for the web.
表单，一个网页的交互式表单。
But it doesn't actually do anything useful yet.
但它还没有真正做任何有用的事情。
But let me do this.
但让我做这个。
Let me go to the actual google.com.
让我访问真正的 google.com。
Let me search for something like cats, C-A-T-S.
让我搜索一些东西，比如猫，C-A-T-S。
And of course, we're going to see a whole bunch of cats here.
当然，我们将会看到一堆猫。
And we're going to see that the search box was automatically
我们将会看到，搜索框自动
populated at the very top of the page.
填充到了页面顶部。
Now the URL that Google led me to, even though I
现在 Google 带我到的 URL，尽管我
started at the very simple google.com, is actually pretty long.
从最简单的 google.com 开始，实际上很长。
And I'm going to frankly just delete anything I don't understand.
坦白地说，我会删除任何我不理解的东西。
Because I'm going to distill this URL to just this one here.
因为我将把这个 URL 简化为这里这个。
It turns out that in URLs you can also put user input
事实证明，在 URL 中，你也可以加入用户输入
in the form of key value pairs.
以键值对的形式。
So in any URL, you can actually have not only a path
所以，在任何 URL 中，你实际上可以不只拥有路径
like we saw earlier, you can have a path with a key
就像我们之前看到的那样，你可以拥有一个带键的路径
and a value prefixed with a single question mark.
和一个带单问号前缀的值。
And in fact, if you want to have two keys and values,
实际上，如果你想拥有两个键值对，
you just interpose them with an ampersand instead.
你只需要用一个与号将它们隔开即可。
So this is to say there is a standard way in HTML
所以，也就是说，在 HTML 中有一种标准的方式
and really HTTP for sending input from a browser to a server.
以及 HTTP，用于将来自浏览器的输入发送到服务器。
And it's generally formatted like this.
它的格式通常是这样的。
What this means is actually this.
这实际上意味着这个。
Let me zoom out, close that tab, and open a brand new one.
让我缩小，关闭那个标签，然后打开一个全新的标签。
And let me manually go to-- and I'll zoom
让我手动去-- 我会放大
in-- https://wwww.google.com/search?q=dogs.
-- https://wwww.google.com/search?q=dogs。
Now it has to be q, because that's what Larry and Sergey of Google fame
它必须是 q，因为那是 Google 创始人 Larry 和 Sergey
decided two decades ago when they made Google itself.
二十年前在创建 Google 时决定的。
Q stands for query.
Q 代表查询。
But they could have called that key anything they want.
但他们本可以给那个键取任何他们想要的名字。
I'm going to hit Enter after zooming out.
我会缩小后按下回车键。
And what you'll see is that I don't need google.com to search for me.
你会看到，我不需要 google.com 来帮我搜索。
I can literally go to a URL of all of the dog search results manually.
我可以直接手动访问包含所有狗狗搜索结果的 URL。
Now no one's normally going to do that.
通常没有人会这样做。
That makes no sense.
那毫无意义。
But it does suggest how simple the mechanics of the web are.
但这的确表明了网页机制的简单性。
If you want to pass input to a server, you suffix the URL
如果你想向服务器传递输入，你需要在 URL 后面加上
with a question mark, key equals value.
问号，键等于值。
Key equals value may be separated you buy these ampersands, as I proposed.
键等于值可以通过与号隔开，正如我提出的那样。
So what does this mean?
所以，这意味着什么？
Well, Google really did the hard part, the back end, the database.
好吧，Google 做了最难的部分，后端，数据库。
They crawled the internet and found all of these cats and dogs.
他们爬取了互联网，找到了所有这些猫和狗。
But I can make the front end, that is the user
但我可以制作前端，也就是用户
interface that still works for it.
接口，它仍然可以使用。
And I'm going to do this.
我会这样做。
I'm going to add an attribute to my form tag that
我将添加一个属性到我的 form 标签，它
specifies an action attribute of https://www.google.com/search.
指定了 action 属性为 https://www.google.com/search。
And I'm going to specify that the method I want the browser to use
我将指定我想让浏览器使用的 method 为
is indeed get.
get。
This is inconsistent.
这与之前不一致。
I capitalized it as all caps before.
之前我把它写成了大写。
In HTML, you actually do it as lowercase.
在 HTML 中，你实际上应该写成小写。
But that's also the default. So strictly speaking, I
但这也是默认值。严格来说，我
don't even need to specify that.
甚至不需要指定它。
But I will, just to be pedantic.
但我还是会指定，只是为了严谨。
Inside of my input, my text box, which used
在我的输入框中，我的文本框，之前
to look like this, just a big white rectangle,
看起来像这样，只是一个大的白色矩形，
I'm going to actually give it a name of q, because I
我将给它一个名为 q 的名称，因为我
know that's what Google servers expect.
知道这是 Google 服务器所期望的。
And I'm also going to specify--
我还要指定——
eh, just that for now.
嗯，就现在这样。
Let me go back now and reload.
我现在回去重新加载。
And it's going to still look very simple.
它看起来仍然非常简单。
But notice this.
但是请注意。
If I type in cats and click Search, in just a moment,
如果我在里面输入 "cats" 然后点击 "搜索"，马上就会...
I'm going to be whisked away from my own Codespaces URL ending
我会从我自己的 Codespaces URL 结尾，
in search.html to, after zooming out and clicking Search, the actual google.com.
在搜索.html 中，缩小并点击搜索后，转向真正的 google.com。
Which prepopulates the URL with q equals cats up top,
它会预先填充 URL，q 等于 "cats" 放在最上面，
prepopulates this text box with the user's input,
预先填充这个文本框，内容是用户的输入，
which is to say, like, the front end of google.com is trivial,
也就是说，像 google.com 的前端非常简单，
as is most every website.
大多数网站都是如此。
It's as simple as these key value pairs and things like web forms like that.
它就像这些键值对，以及像这样的网页表单一样简单。
Now I can make this a little prettier.
现在我可以把它弄得漂亮一些。
And just so you've seen it, if I specified that the type of this input
为了让你看到，如果我指定这个输入的类型
isn't text, which is the default, but is search,
不是默认的文本，而是搜索，
I actually get some nice features.
我实际上会得到一些不错的功能。
Let me reload this now.
我现在重新加载它。
And if I start typing in, like, dogs, now I get this little x
如果我开始输入，比如 "dogs"，现在我会得到这个小 x
to click, which clears it.
来点击，它会清除它。
So a lot of websites have that.
所以很多网站都有这个。
It's a little bit of a nicety.
这算是有点小贴心。
If you don't know what you want the user to type in,
如果你不知道你想让用户输入什么，
you can actually be kind of explicit for them.
你可以为他们明确地说明。
And you can add a placeholder attribute that says query or keywords
你可以添加一个占位符属性，上面写着 "查询" 或 "关键词"
or whatever you want to show them.
或者你想让他们看到什么就写什么。
If I go back to the browser and reload, you'll
如果我回到浏览器并重新加载，你就会
see a grayed out text that's not actually there.
看到一个灰色的文本，但实际上并不存在。
It goes away if I type in bird, for instance.
例如，如果我输入 "bird"，它就会消失。
But it's explanatory, placeholder text for the user.
但这对用户来说是解释性的占位符文本。
You'll notice that it wants to autocomplete cats or bird or dog
你会注意到，它想要自动补全 "cats" 或 "bird" 或 "dog"
or anything I've typed before.
或者我之前输入的任何东西。
You can disable that.
你可以禁用它。
There is an attribute called autocomplete
有一个叫做 "autocomplete" 的属性
whose value can be either on, which is default, or off, which
它的值可以是 "on"，这是默认值，也可以是 "off"，
can be explicitly specified.
可以明确地指定。
And notice this, too.
还有要注意的。
When I reload the page, it's actually annoying in terms of user experience.
当我重新加载页面时，从用户体验的角度来说，这实际上很烦人。
Before I can search for anything, I have to move my cursor,
在我搜索任何东西之前，我必须移动鼠标，
I have to click in the text box.
我必须点击文本框。
And now it has focus, so to speak.
现在它获得了焦点，可以这么说。
It gets highlighted in some color, usually blue.
它会用某种颜色高亮显示，通常是蓝色。
That's not the best website.
这不是最好的网站。
Why are you making the users pick up their mouse or their trackpad just
为什么要让用户拿起他们的鼠标或触控板来
to click on the only thing they're going to do anyway?
点击他们本来就一定会做的事情？
So there's another attribute that's handy,
所以还有一个属性很方便，
Auto Focus, which will just move the cursor there for the user.
自动聚焦，它会直接将光标移动到那里，方便用户。
So this is to say, even though a lot of websites don't do this,
也就是说，尽管很多网站都没有这样做，
there's a lot of functionality that you can enable by just
但你只需了解这门语言，就能启用很多功能。
knowing the language all the more.
了解得更多。
So with that, we now have a pretty useful feature.
有了它，我们现在拥有了一个非常有用的功能。
In fact, heck, I can say this is Google Search,
实际上，我可以说这就是谷歌搜索，
change the value of that button, reload.
更改那个按钮的值，然后重新加载。
And now I'll go ahead and type in birds, Enter, and voila.
现在我会继续输入 "birds"，然后回车，然后瞧。
Now we have a whole bunch of birds as well.
现在我们也有一大堆鸟了。
So that's a lot.
所以很多。
I think it's definitely time for a snack.
我想是时候吃点零食了。
So let's take a 10-minute break for a snack.
所以让我们休息 10 分钟吃点零食。
And when we come back, we'll make all of this look prettier.
我们回来后，会让这一切看起来更漂亮。
All right.
好的。
So we are back.
所以我们回来了。
And it was brought to my attention during break
在休息的时候，有人提醒我，
that we were pretty darn close to clearing one of these rows.
我们离清空这些行中的一个已经非常接近了。
And I will concede that your classmates, Darwin and Jude,
我承认，你的同学达尔文和朱德，
socially engineered me into saying one of the remaining squares
用社会工程学技巧让我说出剩下方格中他们需要的那一个。
that they needed.
他们需要的那个。
And so I'm sad to say that bingo was declared during break, which Carter
所以我很遗憾地说，在休息的时候，宾果游戏被宣布成功，卡特已经确认了，因为我被骗着对一个简短的问题做出了长篇大论。
has already confirmed, because I was tricked into giving
因为我被骗着对一个简短的问题做出了长篇大论。
a long answer to a short question.
对一个简短的问题做出了长篇大论。
So congratulations to those two.
所以祝贺这两位。
I do dare say, too, that whole bit with safetyschool.org probably
我还要说，safetyschool.org 的那件事可能
isn't going over well in New Haven.
在新港并没有得到很好的反响。
So I'm pretty sure we can check off this box here.
所以我相当确定我们可以在这里打勾了。
However, as promised, in fairness, since we love them both equally,
但是，正如承诺，为了公平起见，因为我们同样爱他们俩，
I thought it only fair to resume now with a look at perhaps one of the best
我认为，现在继续看一看，也许是最好的
Harvard-Yale pranks that was actually on us,
哈佛-耶鲁恶作剧，实际上是我们被捉弄了，
with this 2.5-minute glimpse at how our classmates at Yale pranked Harvard some
通过这段 2 分 30 秒的视频，我们可以看到耶鲁的同学们是如何捉弄哈佛的。
years back.
几年前。
If we could dim the lights now for this.
如果现在可以调暗灯光。
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[视频播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[CHEERING]
[欢呼声]
[BAND MUSIC PLAYING]
[乐队音乐播放]
- All the way at the top and then you pass it down.
- 一直传到最上面，然后传下去。
[CROWD NOISE]
[人群噪音]
- [INAUDIBLE] this for you, Yale.
- [听不清] 献给你们，耶鲁。
We love you, Yale.
我们爱你，耶鲁。
- We're here to cheer for Harvard.
- 我们来为哈佛加油。
- Yeah!
- 耶！
Go Harvard!
哈佛加油！
- Go Harvard!
- 哈佛加油！
- [INAUDIBLE] one and pass it down?
- [听不清] 传一个，传下去？
- Pass them down.
- 传下去。
- Great.
- 太棒了。
- It says go Harvard.
- 上面写着 "哈佛加油"。
- We're nice.
- 我们很好。
- You see that [BLEEP]?
- 你看到那个 [哔] 了吗？
- Look at them.
- 看看他们。
They have the paper!
他们有纸！
- It's going to happen.
- 要开始了。
- It's actually gonna happen!
- 这真的要发生了！
- I can't [BLEEP] believe this!
- 我简直不敢相信！
- What do you think of Yale?
- 你觉得耶鲁怎么样？
- They don't think good.
- 他们不太会思考。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
- It may be a complete mess.
- 这可能是一团糟。
I don't know.
- 我不知道。
- Dude, does everyone have it?
- 老兄，大家都有吗？
Does everyone have their stuff?
- 大家都有他们的东西了吗？
- The probability that it's going to be legible it's very small, though.
- 不过，它能被辨认出来的概率非常小。
- I agree.
- 我同意。
- It's too complicated.
- 太复杂了。
- [INAUDIBLE].
- [听不清]
- I know.
- 我知道。
But it's too complicated.
- 但它太复杂了。
- What houses are you guys in?
- 你们住哪个宿舍？
- [INAUDIBLE].
- [听不清]
- That's not a real house.
- 那不是真宿舍。
- How many extra are there?
- 有多少个额外的？
- Ho-fo.
- Ho-fo。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- You guys aren't from Harvard, are you?
- 你们不是哈佛的吧？
- Fo-ho.
- Fo-ho。
- Pforzheimer.
- Pforzheimer。
- Yeah, but you said ho-fi.
- 是的，但你说的是ho-fi。
- Just make sure everyone has it.
- 确保每个人都有。
- Well, she's probably drunk.
- 她可能喝醉了。
- It looks like they're still passing.
- 看起来他们还在发牌。
Are all the cards distributed?
- 牌都发完了吗？
- [INAUDIBLE].
- [听不清]
- All right.
- 好吧。
Let's do it now.
- 现在就开始吧。
[CHEERING]
[欢呼声]
- Hold up your signs!
- 举起你们的牌子！
- [BLEEP].
- [消音]
[CHANTING]
[喊叫声]
- You suck.
- 你烂透了。
You suck.
You [BLEEP].
- 你 [消音]
- Did it.
- 做到了。
- [BLEEP].
- [消音]
- You suck.
- 你烂透了。
You suck.
- What do you think of Yale, sir?
- 先生，您觉得耶鲁怎么样？
- [INAUDIBLE].
- [听不清]
- One more time!
- 再来一次！
One more time!
- Oh, and there it goes again!
- 哦，又来了！
[CHANTING]
[喊叫声]
- Harvard sucks!
- 哈佛烂透了！
Harvard sucks!
[END PLAYBACK]
[结束播放]
DAVID MALAN: So fair is fair there.
DAVID MALAN:  所以那里公平就公平。
So now back to some HTML.
所以现在回到一些 HTML。
And we will transition momentarily then to this other language, CSS,
然后我们会过渡到另一种语言，CSS，
by which we can style things all the more.
通过这种语言，我们可以更加灵活地设置样式。
So there's this feature in HTML that's actually present in Python,
所以 HTML 中有一个特性，实际上也存在于 Python 中，
even though we didn't use it yet, and that's present in JavaScript
虽然我们还没有使用它，但它也存在于 JavaScript 中
and, really, most modern languages known as regular expressions.
以及，实际上，大多数现代语言都称为正则表达式。
Which is otherwise known as regexes, which
也称为正则表达式，它
is a way of using patterns to validate input
是一种使用模式来验证输入的方法
or to extract information from strings.
或者从字符串中提取信息。
And so by that I mean this.
我的意思是这个。
Let me go over to VS Code here.
让我看看 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and create a new file called register.html.
让我创建一个名为 register.html 的新文件。
I'm going to copy paste some code from earlier, just to save some keystrokes.
为了节省一些按键，我会复制粘贴之前的一些代码。
And in here, I'm going to go ahead and change my title to register.
在这里，我会将我的标题改为 register。
And in my code, I'm going to go ahead and create a very simple form
在代码中，我将创建一个非常简单的表单
representative of a registration form now.
来代表一个注册表单。
So in this body, I'm going to do a form tag.
所以在这个 body 中，我会使用一个 form 标签。
I'm not going to bother sending it to Google or to any server in particular
我不会费心把它发送到谷歌或任何特定的服务器
here.
这里。
I'm going to give it an input tag with autocomplete equals off, as before.
我会给它一个 input 标签，autocomplete 属性设置为 off，就像之前一样。
I'm going to have auto focus on as before.
我会像之前一样设置 autofocus 为 on。
I'm going to give this form field the name of email this time instead of q.
这次我会给这个表单域命名为 email，而不是 q。
I'm going to give it a placeholder of quote,
我会给它一个占位符，用引号括起来，
unquote "email," just so that the user knows what they're supposed to type.
“email”，这样用户就知道应该输入什么。
And it turns out that browsers have not only type text or search, but also
而且事实证明，浏览器不仅有 type text 或 search，还有
type email, whereby you can rely on the browser to ensure that the human has
type email，你可以依赖浏览器来确保用户输入的是
actually typed in an email address.
一个真正的电子邮件地址。
Now I'm going to go ahead and have a button
现在我将添加一个按钮
that this time will be called Register.
这次它将被命名为 Register。
And now let's go over to my other tab, reload my directory index.
现在让我们切换到另一个选项卡，重新加载我的目录索引。
There's register.html.
这里有 register.html。
And we'll see a relatively simple form field now.
现在，我们将看到一个相对简单的表单字段。
But it's prompting me to register with some email address.
但它提示我用一些电子邮件地址注册。
If I go ahead and sort of type in just my name and try Register,
如果我继续输入我的名字并尝试注册，
you'll notice that the browser sort of yells at me with the built-in error
你会注意到浏览器用内置错误信息对我大喊大叫。
message saying, oh, please include an at in the email address.
信息说，哦，请在电子邮件地址中包含一个@符号。
And it's pretty good in that if I do mail an at, but nothing more,
而且它很棒，因为如果我输入一个@符号，但没有其他内容，
which is also not valid, and try to register, it's telling me still
这也是无效的，我尝试注册，它仍然告诉我
that it's incomplete.
它是不完整的。
So built into browsers is some defense against incorrect user input
因此，浏览器内置了一些防御机制，来抵御用户输入错误。
in this way.
就这样。
If I finally do type in malan@harvard.edu and click Register,
如果我最终输入 malan@harvard.edu 并点击注册，
then the form would be submitted successfully to the server.
那么表单将成功提交到服务器。
If, though, I want to tolerate only .edu addresses because I'm making
但是，如果我只想容忍 .edu 地址，因为我正在制作
an education-themed website for students in the US,
一个面向美国学生的教育主题网站，
I can actually add another attribute here, which is actually quite useful,
我实际上可以在这里添加另一个属性，它实际上非常有用，
too.
也是。
I can add a pattern attribute.
我可以添加一个 pattern 属性。
And inside of its value, I can put one of these things called
在它的值里面，我可以放一个叫做
a regular expression, or a regex.
正则表达式或正则表达式的东西。
That is an actual pattern that the browser
这实际上是一个模式，浏览器
should match the user's input against and make sure it indeed matches.
应该与用户的输入进行匹配，并确保它确实匹配。
And this is going to look a little cryptic.
这看起来有点神秘。
But I'm going to go ahead and do this.
但我还是会这样做。
.+@.+ backslash dot edu.
.+@.+ 反斜杠点 edu。
Now this looks a little weird.
现在这看起来有点奇怪。
But it turns out I'm using certain building blocks that we'll just
但事实证明，我正在使用一些构建块，我们只是
scratch the surface of today.
今天触及表面。
But it's an incredibly useful and powerful feature in programming
但它在编程语言中是一个非常有用和强大的功能，
languages more generally.
更一般地说。
Because in the world of regular expressions,
因为在正则表达式的世界里，
there are certain patterns that mean something.
有一些模式是有意义的。
And here's a really good URL of some documentation
这里有一个关于文档的很好的 URL
they're for in the world of the web and JavaScript, specifically.
它们是关于 Web 和 JavaScript 世界的，特别是。
And here's kind of a short cheat sheet, some excerpts thereof.
这里有一个简短的速查表，里面有一些摘录。
It turns out in the world of regular expressions or patterns,
事实证明，在正则表达式或模式的世界里，
a dot represents any single character except line terminators,
一个点代表除换行符以外的任何单个字符，
like backslash n.
比如反斜杠 n。
A star or an asterisk represents 0 or more times.
一个星号或一个星号代表 0 次或更多次。
A plus means one or more times.
一个加号表示一次或多次。
A question mark means 0 or one time.
一个问号表示 0 次或 1 次。
A number inside of curly braces means n times, or n occurrences.
花括号中的数字表示 n 次或 n 次出现。
And then two numbers in curly braces, n comma n,
然后是花括号中的两个数字，n 逗号 n，
means at least n times, but at most, m times or occurrences.
表示至少 n 次，但最多 m 次或出现次数。
And then there's a few other, actually.
实际上还有几个其他的。
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, let me go over to VS Code again.
好吧，让我再回到 VS Code。
And let me zoom in on the pattern I used.
让我放大我使用的模式。
And it would seem that, in this case, a dot represents any character.
看起来，在这种情况下，一个点代表任何字符。
Plus means one or more.
加号表示一个或多个。
So one or more characters to the left of an sign, then literally the at sign.
因此，@符号左边的一个或多个字符，然后是@符号本身。
Then another dot plus means one or more characters to the right of the at sign.
然后另一个点加号表示@符号右边的一个或多个字符。
But the whole thing has to end in .edu.
但整个字符串必须以 .edu 结尾。
But there's this additional backslash before the last dot.
但最后一个点前面有一个额外的反斜杠。
And why might that be, intuitively?
直觉上，为什么可能是这样呢？
Even though I've not said?
即使我没有说过？
Because I want a literal dot, a literal period, not any one character there.
因为我想要一个字面上的点，一个字面上的句号，而不是那里的任何一个字符。
So I escape the period to make it have not
所以我对句号进行转义，使它没有
special significance per this cheat sheet, but rather a literal period.
根据这个速查表，特殊的意义，而是一个字面上的句号。
So what this means is if I go actually back to VS Code here
所以这意味着，如果我实际上回到这里的 VS Code
and I try to claim to work at like malan@harvard.com and click Register,
我尝试声称我在 malan@harvard.com 工作，然后点击注册，
that's a valid-looking email address.
这是一个看起来有效的电子邮件地址。
But when I click Register now.
但当我点击注册时。
Whoops!
哎呀！
Sorry.
抱歉。
It went through because I did not reload the page after making the change.
它成功了，因为我在更改后没有重新加载页面。
So I screwed up.
所以我搞砸了。
Let me go back to the register.html URL.
让我回到 register.html URL。
Let me reload the page and type in malan@harvard.com, for instance,
让我重新加载页面并输入 malan@harvard.com，例如，
and even-- sorry.
甚至 - 抱歉。
Let me type in malan@harvard.com.
让我输入 malan@harvard.com。
And even though it's a valid-looking URL, it does not in fact and in .edu.
即使它看起来是一个有效的 URL，它实际上并没有以 .edu 结尾。
So the browser can defend against that in this way.
所以浏览器可以这样防御这种情况。
But the more important takeaway for now is
但现在更重要的是
that as useful as this is, as user friendly as this,
虽然它很有用，也很人性化，
this is not generally the best technique for validating user input
但这通常不是验证用户输入的最佳方法
and protecting against invalid user input.
以及防止无效的用户输入。
Why?
为什么？
Browsers can't be trusted.
浏览器不可信。
Or more generally, clients can't be trusted.
或者更一般地说，客户端不可信。
Why?
为什么？
Because the way HTML works as we've seen it thus far
因为我们迄今为止所看到的 HTML 的工作方式
is that everything is happening on my own Mac, or your own PC,
是所有事情都发生在我的 Mac 或你的 PC 上，
or your own phone locally.
或者你的手机本地。
Per the envelope story we told earlier, your browser is downloading the HTML,
根据我们之前讲过的信封故事，你的浏览器正在下载 HTML，
reading it top to bottom, left to right, and then
从上到下、从左到右阅读它，然后
displaying it on your computer.
在你的电脑上显示它。
But we've already seen that my computer, for instance,
但我们已经看到，我的电脑，例如，
has built into it these developer tools.
内置了这些开发者工具。
And there among the tabs here, are not just that network tab,
并且在这里的选项卡中，不仅仅是那个网络选项卡，
let me actually go to the Elements tab, which we haven't seen previously.
让我实际去到 Elements 选项卡，我们之前没有看到它。
In the Elements tab, you actually will see a pretty, printed version
在 Elements 选项卡中，你实际上会看到一个漂亮、打印的版本
of the same HTML.
相同的 HTML。
But what that means is that you can not only see the HTML,
但这意味着，你不仅可以看到 HTML，
you can actually change it.
你实际上可以改变它。
Now you're not going to be able to change it on the server.
现在你无法在服务器上更改它。
But I can absolutely change my own copy thereof.
但我绝对可以更改我自己的副本。
So suppose I'm now a hacker in the story.
假设我现在是故事中的黑客。
And I really want to register for this website,
我真的很想注册这个网站，
but it's apparently restricted to people with .edu addresses.
但它似乎只允许使用 .edu 地址的人注册。
I don't have a .edu address, let me propose.
我没有 .edu 地址，让我来提议。
So that's fine.
没问题。
Let me actually go into the developer tools.
让我实际进入开发者工具。
Let me just double click on the attribute
让我双击一下这个属性
there, highlight it, and boom.
然后，选中它，然后砰的一声。
Now gone is that pattern entirely.
现在，这个模式完全消失了。
The web browser now will let me register with malan@harvard.com
现在，网页浏览器将允许我使用 malan@harvard.com 注册
because the developer tools give you full-fledged access to the underlying
因为开发者工具允许你完全访问底层的
HTML.
HTML。
So if I've changed the HTML, the defense is no longer in place.
因此，如果我修改了 HTML，防御措施就不再起作用了。
Now what's the takeaway then is client-side validation
那么，客户端验证的收获是什么呢？
is wonderfully user friendly.
它非常人性化。
But it's not secure.
但它不安全。
It's not safe.
它不安全。
So next week, we'll spend more time server-side
下周，我们将花更多时间在服务器端
at making sure that even if someone messes with my HTML or my website,
确保即使有人修改了我的 HTML 或我的网站，
they still can't actually get through and do anything bad on the server.
他们仍然无法真正突破并对服务器做任何坏事。
And this is true in general, too.
这在一般情况下也是如此。
Let me actually, just for fun, go to, maybe, let's say, harvard.edu.
让我实际去，只是为了好玩，去，也许，比方说，harvard.edu。
Let me open up my development tools.
让我打开我的开发工具。
And let's see where I might go here.
让我们看看我能去哪里。
Suppose that I want to hack into harvard.edu.
假设我想侵入 harvard.edu。
Well, notice that I'm on my elements tab and there's
注意，我正在我的元素选项卡上，并且有一个
a lot of HTML that composes this page.
很多构成此页面的 HTML。
And notice that these triangles indicate that most of it's been collapsed.
注意，这些三角形表示大多数内容都被折叠了。
But if I expanded them, I could see more and more of the tags and attributes.
但是，如果我展开它们，我就可以看到越来越多的标签和属性。
But suppose I'm now a hacker.
但假设我现在是黑客。
And I want to maybe delete this menu.
我想也许删除这个菜单。
Notice that you can also right click or Control
注意，你也可以右键单击或按住 Control
click on any element in a web page, typically.
单击网页上的任何元素，通常。
With these developer tools, click Inspect or some similarly named menu
使用这些开发者工具，单击“检查”或一些类似命名的菜单
option, and you can actually been whisked away to the actual HTML tags
选项，你实际上会被带到实现网页该功能的实际 HTML 标签
that implement that feature of the web page.
中。
One, it's wonderfully useful for learning how things work,
首先，它非常有用，可以学习事物的工作原理，
teaching yourself new tricks, and even fixing problems.
自学新技巧，甚至解决问题。
Here, though, I'm going to try to use it maliciously.
但是，在这里，我将尝试恶意地使用它。
And I'm going to highlight this tag here, div tag, as it's called.
我将在此处突出显示此标签，div 标签，就像它的名字一样。
I'm going to delete it.
我将删除它。
And watch what happens at top right.
看看右上角发生了什么。
Gone is the menu.
菜单不见了。
Now, of course, if you go to harvard.edu right now, the menu is still there.
现在，当然，如果你现在访问 harvard.edu，菜单仍然在那里。
If I reload harvard.edu the menu is back.
如果我重新加载 harvard.edu，菜单就回来了。
So it's only my own local copy.
所以这只是我自己的本地副本。
But this does speak to how you should not
但这也说明了你不应该
trust anything happening client side.
信任客户端发生的事情。
Because someone can be mutating that same code.
因为有人可能会修改相同的代码。
Now it turns out there's other patterns that you
现在事实证明，还有其他模式可以用来
can use in regular expressions.
在正则表达式中使用。
For instance, these are what are called character classes.
例如，这些被称为字符类。
You can, for instance, specify in square brackets
例如，你可以在方括号中指定
some number of digits or characters that you want to match against.
一些你想要匹配的数字或字符。
This is a range of characters, 0 through 9.
这是一个字符范围，从 0 到 9。
So it's effectively the same thing as that, but easier to type.
所以它实际上与那个相同，但更容易输入。
There are certain shortcuts, backslash lowercase d means any decimal digit.
有一些快捷方式，反斜杠小写 d 表示任何十进制数字。
Backslash capital d means anything that's not a decimal digit.
反斜杠大写 D 表示任何不是十进制数字的字符。
And dot dot dot, there's bunches of other patterns.
等等，还有很多其他模式。
You might use these to maybe validate a phone number in a web page,
你可能使用这些来验证网页中的电话号码，
if you want it to be formatted in a certain way, for better or for worse.
如果你希望它以某种特定的方式格式化，无论好坏。
But long story short, regular expressions will be,
但长话短说，正则表达式将是
someday, your friend as you try to solve certain problems with data.
有一天，你尝试用数据解决某些问题时的朋友。
As an aside, it does escalate quickly.
顺便说一句，它确实会迅速升级。
So this is typically the regular expression
所以，这通常是
that browsers nowadays use to validate email addresses.
如今浏览器用来验证电子邮件地址的正则表达式。
It is way more complicated than . +@.+.
它比 . +@.+ 复杂得多。
Why?
为什么？
Because you can't have @@@.edu.
因为你不能有 @@@.edu。
There's certain characters you don't want to allow.
有些字符你不想允许。
There are certain characters you do want to allow.
有些字符你确实想允许。
So long story short, this is a much larger regular expression
所以长话短说，这是一个更大的正则表达式
that is more correct when it comes to valid email addresses.
在验证有效电子邮件地址时，它更准确。
All right.
好的。
So with that said, there's one tool with which you should be familiar.
因此，有这样一个工具，你应该熟悉它。
And that is at this URL here, validator.w3.org.
它位于此 URL：validator.w3.org。
And this is a free web service from the World Wide Web Consortium,
这是一个来自万维网联盟的免费网络服务，
which is the group that essentially standardizes this HTML language.
它是一个基本标准化 HTML 语言的组织。
And if you go to their web page, there's a few different ways
如果你访问他们的网页，有几种不同的方法
to validate your own code.
来验证你自己的代码。
Essentially, check it for correctness by typing in its URL,
本质上，通过输入其 URL 来检查其正确性，
otherwise known more generally as a URI, by uploading a file or by direct input.
更广义地说，也就是 URI，通过上传文件或直接输入。
So just for kicks, for instance, I'm going to go into VS Code
所以，只是为了好玩，例如，我将进入 VS Code
and grab my HTML that I just made.
并获取我刚创建的 HTML。
I'm going to go back to validator.w3.org and paste it into the direct input box
我将返回 validator.w3.org 并将其粘贴到直接输入框中
and click Check.
然后点击“检查”。
And it's just a nice handy website that, if I scroll down, in green,
这是一个非常方便的网站，如果我向下滚动，用绿色显示，
you will hopefully see this, no errors or warnings to show.
你将有望看到，没有错误或警告显示。
So it's a handy feature just to make sure that at least syntactically
所以，它是一个方便的功能，可以确保至少语法上
your code is correct, even if it's not behaving the way that you might want.
你的代码是正确的，即使它没有按照你想要的方式运行。
All right.
好的。
With that said, the second of today's three languages,
话虽如此，今天的三种语言中的第二种，
and we'll just scratch the surface ultimately of JavaScript
我们最终只是触及了 JavaScript 的皮毛
to give you a sense of its capabilities, but CSS
让你了解它的功能，但 CSS
is something that's worth understanding some of the basic building blocks
是一些值得了解的基本构建块
thereof.
其中一些。
So let me propose that there are some additional terms to know.
所以让我建议一些额外的术语需要了解。
In the world of CSS, we're, again, going to have key value pairs.
在 CSS 的世界里，我们又要用到键值对。
In this world, they're called properties instead of attributes.
在这个世界里，它们被称为属性而不是属性。
Why?
为什么？
It was invented by different people, but it's the same kinds of ideas.
它是不同的人发明的，但它是一样的想法。
In the world of CSS, you're going to have
在 CSS 的世界里，你将拥有
ways of specifying different selectors, as they're called.
指定不同选择器的方式，如它们所称。
That is to say we're going to be able to specify
也就是说，我们将能够指定
the font size, the color, the margins and a lot of aesthetics
字体大小、颜色、边距和许多美学效果
when it relates to tags in our web page.
当它与我们网页中的标签相关时。
And there's going to be different ways to select those tags,
而且会有不同的方法来选择这些标签，
as we'll soon see.
我们很快就会看到。
In an HTML page like this, this is our super simple one with which we began,
在一个像这样的 HTML 页面中，这是我们开始使用的超级简单的页面，
it turns out that you can also include a style
事实证明，你也可以包含一个样式
tag in the head of the page that has some
标签在页面的头部，它有一些
of your stylistic decisions, font sizes, colors, margins,
你的风格选择，字体大小，颜色，边距，
and all of those kinds of aesthetics.
以及所有这些美学效果。
We'll also see another approach whereby you can relegate all of that stuff
我们还将看到另一种方法，你可以将所有这些东西
to a separate file, like styles.css, or something .css.
放到一个单独的文件中，比如 styles.css 或类似 .css 的文件。
And you can link to it in the head of the page.
你可以在页面的头部链接到它。
Link here does not mean A, like, ideally our anchor tag before
这里的链接并不意味着 A，比如，理想情况下，我们之前使用的锚标签
would have been called a link.
会被称为链接。
But it's not.
但它不是。
This just means that these two files are linked in some way conceptually.
这仅仅意味着这两个文件在某种程度上是概念上连接的。
All right.
好吧。
So that is to say we can use these kinds of tags now to enhance our own code.
也就是说，我们现在可以使用这些类型的标签来增强我们自己的代码。
So let me propose that we do this.
所以，让我建议我们这样做。
Let me go into VS Code here.
让我进入 VS Code。
Let me go ahead and create a very, very simple home
让我创建一个非常非常简单的首页
page for someone like John Harvard by running code of-- how about home.html?
为像 John Harvard 这样的人运行代码，比如 home.html？
And in home.html, I'm going to copy paste some of my starter HTML
在 home.html 中，我将复制粘贴一些我之前开始使用的 HTML
from before.
从之前。
And now in the body of this page, I'm going to do a few things.
现在在页面的正文中，我要做几件事。
I'm going to have a web page with a paragraph
我将有一个网页，里面有一段
up here that just says John Harvard as the title thereof.
上面的内容就是 John Harvard 作为标题。
Another paragraph that says something simple
另一段内容简单地说
like welcome to my home page exclamation point.
像欢迎来到我的主页！
And then, like, a footer at the bottom and a third paragraph
然后，就像一个页脚在底部，第三段
that's a copyright, say, John Harvard, for instance.
是版权，比如 John Harvard，例如。
So super simple, but representative of a header, a main part of the page,
所以超级简单，但代表了页眉、页面的主要部分，
and a footer thereof.
以及页脚。
If I go into my other tab and reload my directory listing,
如果我进入我的另一个标签，并重新加载我的目录列表，
I will see now home.html.
我将看到 home.html。
And it's going to be pretty bare bones, right?
它将是非常基础的，对吧？
It's the same text, same font size.
它是一样的文本，一样的字体大小。
It is three separate paragraphs.
它有三段独立的段落。
But let me start to stylize this a little bit differently.
但让我尝试以稍微不同的方式来美化它。
Let me make the top bigger and bolder, perhaps, or rather,
让我使顶部更大更粗体，也许，或者说，
the top bigger and centered and make this text shrink thereafter.
顶部更大并居中，然后使这段文本缩小。
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
所以我要继续这样做。
It turns out that you can have not necessarily a style tag,
事实证明，你并不一定需要一个 style 标签，
but even more simply, a style attribute on certain tags, like this.
但更简单的是，在某些标签上添加一个 style 属性，就像这样。
I'm going to add a style attribute that has a font size of maybe large.
我要添加一个 style 属性，它有一个字体大小，可能为 large。
And how about a style attribute here, a font size medium.
这里怎么样，style 属性，字体大小为 medium。
And then maybe down here-- oops, close quotes.
然后也许在这里—— 哦，闭合引号。
And then down here--
然后在这里——
whoops.
哎呀。
Thank you.
谢谢。
OK.
好的。
I owe you some cookies.
我欠你一些饼干。
All right, so style here of font size small, so relatively simple ideas.
好的，所以这里的 style 属性为 font-size 为 small，所以相对来说很简单。
And here is just another stupid syntax for key value pairs.
这仅仅是另一种愚蠢的键值对语法。
Again, left hand is not talking to right hand.
同样，左手和右手没有沟通。
In CSS, cascading style sheets, which is the language we're now talking about,
在 CSS 中，层叠样式表，是我们现在谈论的语言，
it's key colon value.
它是键冒号值。
In HTML, it's key equals quote unquote value.
在 HTML 中，它是键等于引号值引号。
It's just different techniques for the exact same dictionary-like idea.
这仅仅是针对完全相同字典式想法的不同技术。
All right.
好的。
If I go back to my other tab and reload, notice that it's a little subtle,
如果我返回到我的另一个标签并重新加载，你会注意到它有点微妙，
but it is large, medium, and small.
但它确实是 large、medium 和 small。
I didn't center things yet, so let me do that.
我还没有居中，所以让我来做。
It turns out that this thing collectively
事实证明，这个东西整体上
is what's called a property.
被称为属性。
And a property is defined by a key value pair.
一个属性是由一个键值对定义的。
If you want to have multiple properties for key value pairs,
如果你想为键值对有多个属性，
in CSS, you separate them with semicolons.
在 CSS 中，你需要用分号分隔它们。
So those are back.
所以这些都回来了。
And if I want to center the text, I can do text-align: center.
如果我想居中文本，我可以使用 text-align: center。
I could now end my thought with the semicolon.
我现在可以用分号结束我的想法。
It's not strictly necessary.
它不是严格必要的。
But I'll keep it just so that I'm consistent.
但我保留它，这样我就保持一致。
But it's only necessary if you have more than one.
但只有在你有多个属性时才需要。
I'm going to go ahead and center everything, though.
不过，我要继续将所有内容居中。
So I'm going to go down here and add a semicolon after medium, down here
所以我要在这里添加一个分号，在 medium 之后，在这里
and add a semicolon after small.
并在 small 之后添加一个分号。
So I align, text-align center, center, center for all three paragraphs.
所以，对于所有三段，我都使用 text-align: center 来居中。
If I go back to this other tab and I reload, voila.
如果我返回到另一个标签并重新加载，瞧。
Now it is, in fact, centered.
现在它确实居中了。
But here's where we can start to have a conversation about, maybe, design.
但在这里，我们可以开始谈论，也许，设计。
So I claim this is correct.
所以，我声称这是正确的。
But is this perhaps the best design?
但这也许不是最好的设计？
Well, maybe not.
好吧，也许不是。
I mean, these aren't really paragraphs, first of all, semantically.
我的意思是，首先，从语义上讲，这些并不是真正的段落。
It's not even complete sentences.
甚至不是完整的句子。
But there are three different divisions of the page,
但是页面有三个不同的部分，
right, like, the header up there, the main part in the middle, and then
比如，上面的标题，中间的主要部分，然后
the footer.
页脚。
So it turns out, and we saw a glimpse of this in Harvard's source code,
事实证明，我们在哈佛大学的源代码中看到了这一点，
there's another tag instead of p for paragraph called div, for division.
除了代表段落的“p”标签外，还有一个标签叫做“div”，代表“分隔”。
And even though this is actually not going
虽然这实际上并没有
to have much of a functional effect at first,
一开始会产生很多功能上的影响，
it's maybe semantically a bit better.
但从语义上讲可能好一些。
Because, again, these aren't really paragraphs.
因为，再说一次，这些并不是真正的段落。
So if I really want to nitpick, I do have three divisions of the page.
所以如果我真的想挑剔的话，我确实有三个页面分区。
So div is a very common way to give yourself just a rectangular region
所以，div 是一种非常常见的做法，它能为你提供一个矩形区域，
of the page to style as you see fit.
你可以根据自己的喜好对页面进行样式化。
If I go back now and reload, notice that it does tighten things up.
如果我现在回到页面并刷新，你会注意到它确实使内容变得紧凑。
The paragraph tag gave me some vertical whitespace for free.
段落标签免费给我提供了一些垂直空白。
So I've lost that.
所以我失去了那些空白。
But I could add it back if I really wanted to.
但如果我真的想要的话，我可以重新添加它们。
But now, let's come to this question of design.
但现在，让我们来谈谈设计问题。
What's redundant about what I've done thus far, even if you've never
到目前为止，我所做的事情有什么冗余之处，即使你以前从未
seen CSS before?
见过 CSS？
Yeah?
是吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
大卫·马兰：是的。
I mean, I had to center all three divs, which is just sort of stupid,
我的意思是，我不得不将所有三个 div 居中，这有点愚蠢，
it would seem.
看起来是这样的。
Copy paste has generally not been necessary.
通常不需要复制粘贴。
Even though I'm doing it to save time today in general,
尽管我今天这样做是为了节省时间，
when the results are copied and pasted, ultimately, this
但最终，复制粘贴的结果，这
has not been good practice in any of our languages.
在我们任何语言中都不是好的做法。
So it turns out I can do this.
事实证明我可以这样做。
Let me actually delete this one.
让我实际删除掉这个。
And I can keep or get rid of the semicolon, but I'll get rid of it
我可以保留或删除分号，但我将删除它，
for parity with our first version.
与我们的第一个版本保持一致。
I'm going to get rid of this one, too.
我也要删除掉这个。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
Here's the C in CSS cascading.
这就是 CSS 层叠样式表中的“C”。
It's more like a waterfall effect.
更像是一种瀑布效果。
And if I go up to a parent tag here, like, the body is
如果我向上移动到父标签，比如，body 是
the parent of all three divs, I could put the style attribute here
所有三个 div 的父标签，我可以在此放置 style 属性，
and say text-align: center there.
并说 text-align: center。
And that has the effect of cascading down onto all three
这将对所有三个嵌套在里面的
of the children that are nested inside of it.
子标签产生级联效果。
So now it's sort of better designed because I've only
所以现在设计好了一些，因为我只
said text-align: center once.
说了一次 text-align: center。
If I go back to the web page and reload, it has no functional impact visually.
如果我回到网页并刷新，从视觉上看它没有功能上的影响。
But it's better design.
但它是一个更好的设计。
Because if I want to align it left, or right, or center,
因为如果我想将其对齐到左边、右边或居中，
I can change it in one place and not three independent places.
我可以在一个地方更改它，而不是在三个独立的地方更改它。
All right.
好的。
What else might I change after this here?
接下来我还能改变什么？
Well, it turns out that I could do something a little clearer as well.
事实证明，我也可以做一些更清晰的事情。
This copyright symbol?
这个版权符号？
I mean, it's just sort of homemade with two parentheses and a C.
我的意思是，它只是用两个括号和一个 C 自制而成的。
It turns out that there are ways to get special symbols in HTML.
事实证明，在 HTML 中有一些方法可以获得特殊符号。
And you can use what are called HTML entities.
你可以使用被称为 HTML 实体的东西。
You would only know these by looking them up or memorizing the numbers.
你只有通过查找或记忆数字才能知道这些符号。
But it turns out that number 169 is the special HTML
但事实证明，数字 169 是特殊的 HTML
entity for an actual copyright symbol.
版权符号实体。
So let me zoom in here and then reload.
所以让我在这里放大，然后刷新。
And you'll see that the parenthetical C actually becomes the proper mark
你会看到括号中的 C 实际上变成了正确的标记，
for copyright, so marginally useful.
表示版权，所以有一点用。
Or you could copy paste it from some other website,
或者你可以从其他网站复制粘贴它，
for instance, if you didn't know how to type it on your own keyboard.
例如，如果你不知道如何在自己的键盘上输入它。
So that's an HTML entity, another feature with which to be familiar.
所以这就是一个 HTML 实体，另一个需要熟悉的特性。
But having three divs on a page isn't necessarily ideal nowadays,
但现在在一个页面上使用三个 div 不一定是理想的选择，
especially for search engine optimization, SEO,
特别是对于搜索引擎优化，SEO，
for screen readers for accessibility.
对于辅助功能的屏幕阅读器。
Because at a glance, I don't really know which of these divs
因为乍一看，我不知道这些 div 中的哪一个
is the most important.
是最重要的。
Arguably the footer is generally for the human reader,
可以说，页脚通常是为了人类读者，
like, the least information-bearing piece of content.
就像，信息量最少的内容部分。
So why don't I try to signal as much to the browser, to the screen reader,
那么为什么我不尝试向浏览器、屏幕阅读器发送更多信号呢？
to the search engine?
到搜索引擎？
So it turns out there are what are called semantic tags nowadays.
事实证明，现在有一些被称为语义标签的东西。
Indeed, we're up to version 5 of HTML.
确实，我们已经到了 HTML 的第 5 版。
And one of the relatively newer features is, instead of using generic divs,
其中一个比较新的特性是，不再使用泛型的 div，
you can actually use actual names of tags,
你实际上可以使用标签的真实名称，
like header and main and even footer.
比如 header、main 甚至 footer。
And here, too, the visual effect is not going
同样在这里，如果我去这里并刷新，视觉效果不会有任何不同。
to be any different if I go here and reload.
但它的引擎盖下有更多语义信息。
But there's more semantic information underneath the hood.
所以，再说一次，所有这些不同类型的
So that, again, all of those different types
服务，浏览器、屏幕阅读器等等
of services, the browser, the screen reader, and the like
只是对页面了解得更多一些。
just know a little more about the page.
也许现在屏幕阅读器会先关注页面的主要部分，
And maybe a screen reader now would focus on the main part of the page
然后再向人类朗读页脚中的所有细则，例如。
before reciting all of the fine print in the footer, for instance, to the human.
好的。
All right.
那么，我们还能在这里做什么呢？
Well, what else could we do here?
在某些时候，能够重复使用这些样式会很好。
Well, it would be nice at some point to be able to reuse these styles.
如果我发现自己制作的不是一个页面，而是两个页面，十个页面或一百个页面，
And if I find myself making not one page but two pages or 10 pages or 100 pages,
一遍又一遍地输入相同的样式就有点烦人。
it's kind of annoying to have to type out all of the same styles.
所以，如果能够把这些东西分解出来，是不是很不错？
So wouldn't it be nice to start to factor this stuff out?
我可以做到，
Well, I can do that, too.
让我实际做一下。
Let me actually go ahead and do this.
.
Let me get rid of this attribute and this attribute and this attribute.
让我去掉这个属性，还有这个属性，以及这个属性。
And honestly, too, as I do this, I would argue that the code
说实话，当我这样做的时候，我认为这段代码
looks just a little cleaner now.
现在看起来干净多了。
It's more obvious what is a tag and what the actual data of the page
现在很明显哪些是标签，哪些是页面的实际数据，
is, metadata and data, if you will.
也就是元数据和数据，如果你愿意的话。
But I've lost all of my styling.
但我的所有样式都消失了。
But wouldn't it be nice to preserve some of the styling
但保留一些样式不是很好吗？
by doing what I proposed earlier, which is using
通过之前提议的方法，也就是使用
not a style attribute, but a style tag.
不是样式属性，而是样式标签。
And indeed, you can put a style tag in the head of your web page
实际上，你可以在网页的头部放一个样式标签
where you can put all of those same properties.
在这里你可以放置所有相同的属性。
And you need a little more syntax, a few more keystrokes.
你只需要多一些语法，多按几个键。
But I can say this.
但是我可以说。
If I want to center the entire body of my page,
如果我想将整个页面的主体居中，
I can actually do so by specifying text-align: center;.
我可以通过指定 text-align: center; 来实现。
Here the semi-colons are going to be generally necessary,
这里分号通常是必需的，
especially have you multiple properties.
尤其是当你有多个属性的时候。
Next I'm going to say header.
接下来我会说标题。
And inside of these curly braces, font-size:
在这些花括号里面，font-size:
large, unlike C, where you could get away with no curly braces
large，不像C语言，你可以不使用花括号
if there's a single line, you do need them in CSS.
只有一行的时候，在CSS中你确实需要它们。
In the main tag, let's go ahead and style with font-size: medium.
在main标签中，让我们继续使用font-size: medium来设置样式。
And then in the footer tag, let's go ahead and style with font-size: small.
然后在footer标签中，让我们继续使用font-size: small来设置样式。
Now this looks a little worse.
现在看起来有点糟糕。
Because it just kind of blew up and it's a lot longer.
因为它只是爆炸了，而且长得多。
But it is a step toward factoring this out.
但这确实是在朝着将它分解的方向迈进。
And honestly, when it comes to web pages,
说实话，说到网页，
I'm not the best artist in the world.
我并不是世界上最好的艺术家。
I can make the data display.
我可以让数据显示出来。
But friends of mine are certainly better at making things really
但我的一些朋友肯定更擅长让东西看起来真的
pretty and pixel perfect, so to speak.
漂亮，像素完美，可以这么说。
So it's kind of nice if I can isolate all of the style to one part of my file
所以如果我能将所有样式隔离到文件中的一个部分，那就很好
and all of the content to another.
而所有内容都在另一个部分。
Because maybe I could now collaborate with someone else.
因为也许我现在可以与其他人合作。
So if I go back to now the other tab and reload,
所以如果我回到另一个标签并重新加载，
functionally, no different still.
功能上，仍然没有区别。
It still looks exactly the same.
它看起来仍然完全一样。
But I'm starting to make it a little better designed.
但我的设计正在变得更好。
And in fact, there's another way to do this.
事实上，还有另一种方法可以做到这一点。
Suppose that I find myself in the habit of very often centering text on a page.
假设我养成了在页面上经常居中文本的习惯。
And honestly, it's just a little annoying
说实话，这有点烦人
to have to type this out for every tag that I want centered.
每次都要为我想居中的标签输入这些内容。
Well, I could create what are called classes as well in CSS.
好吧，我也可以在CSS中创建所谓类。
It turns out you can make up your own words--
事实证明，你可以自己想词语--
but I'm going to choose some reasonably named ones--
但我将选择一些名字合理的名字--
by prefixing them with a dot or a period.
通过在它们前面加上一个点或句号。
And if I want to call this set of properties,
如果我想调用这组属性，
even though there's just one, centered, I can literally write .centered there
即使只有一个，居中，我也可以直接在这里写 .centered
instead.
代替。
I can write this .large.
我可以写这个 .large。
I can call this .medium.
我可以调用这个 .medium。
I can call this .small.
我可以调用这个 .small。
And what this means now is I have reusable sets of properties,
现在这意味着我拥有可重用的属性集，
kind of like containers whereby anywhere I use the word "centered,"
有点像容器，无论我在哪里使用“centered”这个词，
it's going to get that one text-align: center property applied.
它将应用于 text-align: center 这个属性。
Anywhere I use quote, unquote "large," it's going to be made large.
无论我在哪里使用“large”，它都将被放大。
And so if I scroll down now here, I do need to reintroduce another attribute--
所以如果我现在向下滚动，我确实需要重新引入另一个属性--
but it's a very common one in the world of HTML now-- that of class.
但它现在是HTML世界中非常常见的属性--class。
So class equals large.
所以class等于large。
Down here I'm going to do class equals medium.
在下面我将做class等于medium。
Down here I'm going to do class equals small.
在下面我将做class等于small。
And it's getting a little more verbose, but I'm not polluting all of my HTML
它变得更冗长了，但我没有污染我所有的HTML
with the actual styles.
用实际的样式。
I'm just kind of having this layer of indirection
我只是在这些非常具体的属性之上有一层间接
and of abstraction, if you will, on top of those very specific properties.
以及抽象，如果你愿意的话。
And then for the body, I can do the same idea.
然后对于主体，我可以使用相同的想法。
Class equals centered.
Class等于centered。
And if I go back to my web page here and reload, still looks exactly the same.
如果我回到我的网页并重新加载，看起来仍然完全一样。
But I've kind of centralized where I can do things.
但我已经将我可以做的事情集中起来了。
And frankly, I could do something like this, color: red;.
坦白说，我可以做这样的事情，color: red;。
I can package up multiple properties, go back to the page here, and reload.
我可以将多个属性打包起来，回到这个页面，然后重新加载。
And now that has applied to everything.
现在它已经应用于所有东西。
So I have a reusable set of properties.
所以我拥有一组可重用的属性。
Even though centered is maybe not the best name now,
即使centered现在可能不是最好的名字，
because it also makes things red.
因为它也使东西变红。
But I can come up with reusable sets of properties.
但我可以想出可重用的属性集。
And honestly, one final flourish here would
老实说，这里最后一次修饰会
be let's not assume that my buddy, whether it's
是让我们不要假设我的朋友，无论是
my project partner or a colleague in the real world,
我的项目合作伙伴还是现实世界中的同事，
it's kind of stupid to try to edit the same file.
尝试编辑同一个文件有点愚蠢。
Because invariably we're going to break things on each other.
因为我们总是会互相破坏东西。
So I could actually do this.
所以我可以这样做。
Let me take all of this.
让我把所有这些都拿走。
And I'll get rid of the red.
我会去掉红色。
Let me go ahead and highlight everything I just did and cut it to my clipboard.
让我继续选择我刚刚做的一切，并将它剪切到我的剪贴板。
I'm going to get rid of the style tag altogether.
我会完全去掉style标签。
But I am going to go into VS Code and create-- how about a file called
但我会进入VS Code，然后创建一个--怎么样，一个名为
home.css, just so I know what's what.
home.css的文件，这样我就能知道是什么东西。
And in this file, I'm just going to literally paste everything I just made.
在这个文件里，我只是要将我刚刚创建的所有东西粘贴进去。
But I'm going to go back to my home page here.
但我将回到我的主页。
And I'm going to add that other tag I proposed earlier, link href="home.css",
然后我会添加我之前提出的另一个标签，link href="home.css"，
and I need one weird attribute, too.
我还需要一个奇怪的属性。
The relationship of this link is that of quote, unquote "style sheets."
这个链接的关系是“样式表”。
And that's just the way it is according to the tag.
这就是标签所指示的方式。
And now one last time, if I reload this page, the red is going to go away.
现在最后一次，如果我重新加载此页面，红色将会消失。
Because I deleted that.
因为我删除了它。
But the font sizes and centering are still there.
但是字体大小和居中仍然存在。
But what I've done was introduce some basic building
但我已经引入了某些基本的构建
blocks in this language I claim is called CSS that's
模块，用我声称名为 CSS 的语言来实现，也就是
going to allow me to now centralize all of the styling, the aesthetics now
将允许我集中所有样式，即现在所有的美学
of my web page.
我的网页。
All right.
好的。
Let me pause here and see if there are any questions on these techniques
让我在这里暂停一下，看看这些技术方面是否有任何问题
thus far.
到目前为止。
It's just more key value pairs.
它只是更多键值对。
Questions on this?
对此有任何问题吗？
No?
没有？
All right.
好的。
So here's where things can get prettier quickly.
所以，这里就是事物可以快速变得更漂亮的地方。
Let me go ahead now and close these two tabs.
现在让我关闭这两个标签。
Let me go into a file we created earlier called link.html, which you'll recall
让我进入我们之前创建的一个名为 link.html 的文件，你应该记得
looked a little something like this.
看起来有点像这样。
And now we can make this web page behave a little more like the real world.
现在我们可以让这个网页的行为更像现实世界。
Let me undo the phishing attack and just literally say Harvard down here.
让我撤销钓鱼攻击，并且只是在这里说哈佛。
But let me go ahead and start to style the anchor tag as follows.
但是让我继续按照如下方式对锚点标签进行样式设置。
Previously, this page looked a little boring like this.
以前，这个页面看起来有点像这样，很无聊。
The link was blue originally.
链接最初是蓝色的。
But because I visited harvard.edu, by default, the browser changes to purple.
但因为我访问了 harvard.edu，默认情况下，浏览器会变为紫色。
Which is fine, but maybe you don't want that.
这很好，但也许你并不想要这样。
Maybe we want something that's a little more crimson, for instance.
例如，也许我们想要一些更深红色的东西。
So let me do this.
所以让我做这个。
Let me go into the head of this link.html page.
让我进入这个 link.html 页面的头部。
Let me add a style tag herein.
让我在这里添加一个 style 标签。
And in there, let me style the anchor tag as follows.
在里面，让我按照如下方式设置锚点标签的样式。
Inside of this anchor tag, I'm going to do color: red.
在这个锚点标签内，我将执行 color: red。
And let's go ahead and leave it as such for now.
现在让我们先这样，先保持这样。
Let me go back to the link page and reload.
让我回到链接页面，重新加载。
And it's going to be a little subtle.
它会有点微妙。
But right now it's purple.
但现在它是紫色的。
And now it's definitely red.
现在它绝对是红色的。
So I've modified that.
所以我已经修改了它。
Now underlining links is good for accessibility.
现在，给链接加下划线对于可访问性来说是好的。
But a lot of websites choose to not underline them and instead
但许多网站选择不给它们加下划线，而是
underline them when you hover over them.
当你的鼠标悬停在它们上面时，给它们加下划线。
So that is an effect we can achieve, even though it might not be ideal.
所以，这是我们可以实现的效果，即使它可能不理想。
But let's at least demonstrate how websites are doing that.
但至少让我们演示一下网站是如何做到这一点的。
I can specify that this link should have text decoration of none.
我可以指定这个链接应该没有文本装饰。
Now I would only know that by having taken a class, read a book,
现在我只有通过上过课、读过书，
looked at an online reference.
或者查看过在线参考才能知道。
The default is underline.
默认情况下是加下划线。
But I can override that by saying none.
但我可以说 none 来覆盖它。
So if I now go back to my page, reload, it's still going to be red.
所以，如果我现在回到我的页面，重新加载，它仍然会是红色的。
But it's now not going to be underlined.
但现在它不会再加下划线了。
But notice if I hover over it, it changes to a little pointer finger
但是请注意，如果我把鼠标悬停在它上面，它会变成一个小的指针手指
if I zoom in here.
如果我在这里放大。
But it's clearly not underlining, so that's OK.
但它显然没有加下划线，所以没关系。
Because there's another way of selecting tags here.
因为这里还有另一种选择标签的方法。
I can say a:hover.
我可以说 a:hover。
And then inside of this CSS, I can say text-decoration:
然后在这个 CSS 里，我可以说 text-decoration:
underline when the anchor tag is being hovered over with the cursor.
当鼠标悬停在锚点标签上时，加下划线。
If I go back to my tab here and reload, still looks the same.
如果我回到我的标签页，重新加载，它看起来还是一样的。
But watch as my mouse gets close.
但请注意我的鼠标靠近它。
It now underlines, as a lot of websites do.
现在它加了下划线，就像许多网站一样。
So it's a relatively simple idea.
所以这是一个相对简单的想法。
It's not as compelling on mobile, especially,
它在手机上并不那么引人注目，尤其是
because it doesn't do anything if you hover your finger
因为如果你用手指悬停在手机屏幕上
over the glass of your phone.
它什么也不会做。
But it does work on laptops and desktops in this way,
但它在笔记本电脑和台式机上确实可以通过这种方式工作，
even though it's perhaps a little passé now to do this kind of technique.
即使现在使用这种技术也许有点过时了。
But there's other ways to select tags on a page.
但还有其他方法可以选中页面上的标签。
And in fact, let me go back to this one here.
事实上，让我回到这里。
And in this page, let me propose that you can go in one of two places.
在这个页面上，我建议你可以去两个地方之一。
Visit Harvard or a href = https://www.yale.edu/ and then
访问哈佛或 a href = https://www.yale.edu/，然后
Yale's website.
耶鲁的网站。
So it's getting a little long.
所以它变得有点长了。
So I'm going to hit Enter.
所以我将按回车键。
Because the browser won't care that there's some whitespace.
因为浏览器不在乎那里是否有空格。
But at least, now I have two links on the page.
但至少，现在我在页面上有了两个链接。
If I reload this, you'll see that both of them
如果我重新加载这个，你会看到这两个
are red or crimson, which isn't quite right.
都是红色或深红色，这不太对。
But that's OK.
但没关系。
I can actually distinguish these two somehow.
我实际上可以以某种方式区分这两个。
One way to do this would actually be to add one more HTML
一种方法是添加另一个 HTML
attribute that we haven't needed or used before, that of ID.
属性，我们以前没有需要或使用过，那就是 ID。
I can use almost any name for this ID that I want.
我可以使用任何我想使用的名称作为这个 ID。
And I'm going to say, quote, unquote, "Harvard"
我要说，引号，引号，“哈佛”
is the unique ID of this link.
是这个链接的唯一 ID。
And the unique ID of this link is quote, unquote, "Yale," for instance.
例如，这个链接的唯一 ID 是引号，引号，“耶鲁”。
And what I can now do up here is I'm going to get rid of this color red.
我现在可以在上面做的是，我要去掉这个红色。
Because I don't want all anchor tags to be red, but I do
因为我不希望所有锚点标签都是红色的，但我确实
want Harvard tags to be red.
希望哈佛标签是红色的。
So I can say #harvard and then color: red;, and then I can do #Yale
所以我可以说 #harvard 然后 color: red;，然后我可以做 #Yale
and I can say color: blue;, for instance.
我可以说 color: blue;，例如。
The hash symbol here represents an ID.
这里的井号代表一个 ID。
The dot we saw earlier represents a class.
我们之前看到的点代表一个类。
And when you don't have a symbol before it,
当它前面没有符号时，
it represents literally the name of the tag.
它代表标签的名称。
So when I mentioned these various selectors earlier,
所以，当我之前提到这些各种选择器时，
type selector is just the name of the tag.
类型选择器就是标签的名称。
Class selector is the dot.
类选择器是点。
ID selector is the hash.
ID 选择器是哈希。
And there's also ways to select attributes specifically.
还有方法可以专门选择属性。
So if I go back here in VS Code now, I've added a bunch of CSS here,
所以，现在如果我在 VS Code 中回到这里，我已经添加了一些 CSS 代码，
properties.
属性。
But if I reload now, one of these should be red and the other is in fact blue.
但是，如果我现在重新加载，其中一个应该是红色，另一个实际上是蓝色。
So in short, just by way of these style attributes and these style tags,
简而言之，仅仅通过这些样式属性和样式标签，
we have a lot more control over how we can actually stylize our pages.
我们对如何实际美化页面有了更多控制权。
And here's now where this gets interesting.
现在，这就是有趣的地方。
And you asked about Bootstrap, a popular framework or library.
你问了 Bootstrap，一个流行的框架或库。
There do, indeed, in the real world exist a lot of third party frameworks
实际上，在现实世界中，确实存在很多第三方框架
that a lot of smart people have just figured out what
很多聪明人已经弄清楚了
would make our web pages look prettier.
会让我们的网页看起来更漂亮。
And they've come up with design patterns for us that
他们为我们想出了设计模式，这些模式
make it way easier and way faster to make pretty looking forms,
使制作漂亮的表单变得容易得多，速度也快得多，
pretty looking tables, and the like.
漂亮的表格等等。
And one of these products is indeed called Bootstrap.
其中一个产品实际上叫做 Bootstrap。
It's freely available.
它是免费提供的。
And you can see its own documentation at getbootstrap.com.
你可以在 getbootstrap.com 上查看它自己的文档。
And what I've done in advance is I've actually prepared some of our past data
我已经提前准备了一些过去的数据
to actually be formatted a little more prettily.
以便更漂亮地格式化。
So let me actually go back to VS Code here.
所以，让我回到这里的 VS Code。
And I'm going to open up a terminal.
我将打开一个终端。
And I'm going to cheat and copy a file I brought with me called phonebook0.html.
我将作弊，复制一个我随身携带的文件，名为 phonebook0.html。
And if I open this file, you'll see that it looks like this.
如果我打开此文件，你会看到它看起来像这样。
It's a big table that has two columns now called name and number.
这是一个大表格，现在有两个列，名为 name 和 number。
And I've added some other tags which are not that interesting,
我还添加了一些其他标签，这些标签并不那么有趣，
but I didn't need them before.
但我之前不需要它们。
But in this table, there's a table head and there's a table body.
但是在这个表格中，有一个表头和一个表体。
So there's, like, a special row at the top
所以，就像，顶部有一个特殊的行
and then all of the rest of the data in a CSV or a spreadsheet.
然后是 CSV 或电子表格中的所有其他数据。
And you can probably infer from this table row, from this table row,
你可能可以从这个表格行，从这个表格行中推断出，
from this table row, it kind of looks like, indeed, a phone book.
从这个表格行来看，它确实像一本电话簿。
So if I go back to my browser here, go into my directory listing
所以，如果我回到这里的浏览器，进入我的目录列表
and open up phonebook0.html, it's not the prettiest thing.
并打开 phonebook0.html，它不是最漂亮的东西。
But it is tabular.
但它是表格形式的。
And notice that the browser has automatically put in bold the name,
请注意，浏览器已自动将名称加粗，
and the number, and everything's in columns.
以及数字，所有内容都按列排列。
But it's not very pretty.
但它并不漂亮。
But what if I do this?
但如果我这样做呢？
Let me actually go into VS Code here.
让我进入这里的 VS Code。
And let me borrow another file I came with called phonebook1.html.
让我借用另一个我随身携带的文件，名为 phonebook1.html。
And that file is going to look a little bit
该文件看起来会有点
different than the [INAUDIBLE] in that I've included a link tag in the header.
与 [不可识别] 不同，因为我在标题中包含了一个链接标签。
Now I'm not linking to my own CSS.
现在我不链接到我自己的 CSS。
I actually went to getbootstrap.com.
我实际上去了 getbootstrap.com。
I read some of their documentation.
我读了他们的一些文档。
And I'm linking now to Bootstrap's CSS file, which is actually really,
我现在链接到 Bootstrap 的 CSS 文件，它实际上非常
really big.
非常大。
And in fact, if I open this file here, let me actually open this up in a tab,
事实上，如果我打开此文件，让我在一个标签页中打开它，
and visit this URL here, the folks at Bootstrap
并访问这里的 URL，Bootstrap 的人
have written a crazy amount of properties
写了大量的属性
by defining their own classes and other such keywords.
通过定义他们自己的类和其他这样的关键字。
And you and I and really anyone on the internet
你和我和互联网上的任何人
is welcome to use all of this CSS.
都可以使用所有这些 CSS。
And the documentation makes clear what all of this does.
文档清楚地说明了所有这些的作用。
A normal person would not need to read through any of this in that way.
正常人不需要以这种方式阅读所有这些。
But I've included this file called bootstrap.min.css.
但是，我包含了这个名为 bootstrap.min.css 的文件。
And min just means they got rid of most of the whitespace.
min 只是意味着他们去掉了大部分空白。
And if I now go back to my other tab and go back to phonebook1.html,
如果我现在回到我的另一个标签页，并回到 phonebook1.html，
it's the exact same data.
数据完全一样。
But thanks to that link tag, it now looks much prettier.
但由于那个链接标签，它现在看起来漂亮多了。
And I didn't have to figure out how to move things over to the right.
我不必弄清楚如何将东西移到右边。
I didn't have to figure out how to draw these gray lines.
我不必弄清楚如何绘制这些灰色线条。
I didn't have to figure out how to format things in precisely this way.
我不必弄清楚如何以这种精确的方式格式化事物。
Bootstrap, wonderfully, did most of that for me.
Bootstrap 很好地为我做了大部分工作。
Now this is still a very static table.
现在这仍然是一个非常静态的表格。
It's not interactive.
它不是交互式的。
I can't sort by names or columns or the like.
我不能按名称或列进行排序等等。
So let's revisit one other program that we made in advance together.
所以，让我们回顾一下我们之前一起编写的另一个程序。
And this one is actually a new version of the search program.
而这实际上是一个新版本的搜索程序。
So if I open up this program, search2.html, and close my terminal
所以，如果我打开这个程序，search2.html，并关闭我的终端
window, you'll see that I've borrowed some of the same content before.
窗口，你会看到我之前借用了一些相同的内容。
Let me go to the essence of it.
让我看看它的本质。
Here is the form and the action that I used earlier.
这是我之前使用的表单和操作。
But I've added a whole bunch of classes to it.
但我给它添加了一堆类。
And this is the essence of these third party frameworks.
这就是这些第三方框架的本质。
They generally create a whole bunch of classes that you can use and reuse.
它们通常会创建一堆你可以使用和重用的类。
But they figured out all of the relevant properties.
但是他们弄清楚了所有相关的属性。
So for instance, for my Google search button,
例如，对于我的 Google 搜索按钮，
I've given it two classes, a class of button, BTN for short,
我给了它两个类，一个是 button 类，简称为 BTN，
and button-light.
另一个是 button-light。
These are not standard HTML or CSS things.
这些不是标准的 HTML 或 CSS 东西。
These are Bootstrap names that they invented, just like I invented center
这些是 Bootstrap 创造的名字，就像我创造 center 一样
and large and medium and small.
还有 large、medium 和 small。
I've also specified that there are a whole bunch of other classes associated
我还指定了，还有很多其他类与之相关联
with pretty much every tag in this file.
与这个文件中的几乎每个标签相关联。
So if I zoom out here and go back to my directory index
所以，如果我在这里缩小，并回到我的目录索引
and open this, the first version of search.
并打开它，第一个版本的 search。
It was super, super simple because it only contained the HTML form.
它超级简单，因为它只包含 HTML 表单。
Let me go ahead and open up search2.html.
让我打开 search2.html。
And the essence of the form is exactly the same.
表单的本质完全一样。
Therein is the query at the bottom of the page.
页面底部就是查询。
But thanks to CSS, I now have a button that looks a little more interesting.
但由于 CSS，我现在有一个看起来更有趣的按钮。
It's gray and it's rounded.
它是灰色的，而且是圆形的。
I also have an I'm feeling lucky button, which will send a different request
我还有一个“我感觉很幸运”按钮，它会发送不同的请求
and show me by default the very first search result.
并默认显示给我第一个搜索结果。
So in short, the file that I just opened, even though I made it
简而言之，我刚刚打开的文件，即使是我事先创建的
in advance, it's only 55 lines.
它也只有 55 行。
And most of that is whitespace.
而且大部分是空白。
And it did take me a little bit of time to figure out the classes
而且我确实花了一点时间来弄清楚这些类
and read the documentation.
并阅读了文档。
But most of the work is done by this third party framework
但是大部分工作都是由这个第三方框架完成的
or library of CSS classes and properties that someone else made for me.
或者说，是其他人为我创建的 CSS 类和属性库。
And so as CSS goes, that's kind of it for the basics.
所以关于 CSS 的基础知识就是这样了。
It's just a bunch of more key value pairs in the form of these properties,
它只是一堆以这些属性形式出现的键值对，
whereby you can select elements of a web page by way of their ID,
通过这些键值对，你可以根据网页元素的 ID，
or classes, or even the names thereof.
或者类，甚至它们的名称来选择它们。
And here's something that's kind of neat, too.
这里还有一件很酷的事情。
Let me go to harvard.edu again.
让我再次访问 harvard.edu。
Let me go ahead and open up the inspector, as before,
像之前一样，让我打开检查器，
and draw your attention to one final feature of these developer tools
并提醒你注意这些开发者工具的最后一个功能
under the Elements tab.
在 Elements 选项卡中。
So under the Elements tab here is all of the HTML
所以在这里的 Elements 选项卡下是所有组成
that composes harvard.edu as of today.
harvard.edu 的 HTML，截至今天。
But let me go ahead and expand this right-hand portion.
但是让我展开一下右侧部分。
It turns out you can also see all of the CSS
事实证明你也可以看到所有正在应用于
that is being applied to the website as of now.
网站的 CSS，截至目前。
So for instance, if I go to a page here-- let's go to Give Now.
例如，如果我访问这里的页面，让我们访问 Give Now。
Might as well.
不妨。
Let's give them a plug here.
让我们在这里给他们一个宣传。
Under Give Now, let's see if this is going to go well.
在 Give Now 下，让我们看看它是否会顺利进行。
Let's go ahead and highlight this part.
让我们来突出显示这部分。
Suppose they really want to draw attention to give online.
假设他们真的想让人注意到在线捐赠。
And I right click on that.
我右键单击它。
I choose inspect, as before.
我像之前一样选择检查。
And here now, notice that the developer tools
现在请注意，开发者工具
jumped right to the HTML tag that represents
直接跳到了代表
that particular line of text.
那段特定文字的 HTML 标签。
If I zoom in, it turns out it's an H1 tag.
如果我放大，它是一个 H1 标签。
It's big and bold.
它很大而且是粗体。
Suppose, though, I want to change its color.
假设我想改变它的颜色。
Well, if I go over on the right here, you can see all of the CSS properties
好吧，如果我移到右侧这里，你可以看到所有当前应用于
that currently apply to that specific tag.
该特定标签的 CSS 属性。
And most of these we haven't even talked about line, height, margin bottom,
而其中大多数我们还没有讨论过，比如 line、height、margin-bottom、
font, weight, margin top, and a bunch of other fairly self-explanatory things.
font、weight、margin-top，以及一堆其他相当不言自明的属性。
But if I want to experiment, I can go up here in top and say color: red.
但是如果我想尝试一下，我可以在这里的顶部输入 color: red。
And I can literally change that on the web page live to see how it looks.
我实际上可以实时更改网页上的内容，看看它是什么样子。
It's not changing the server.
它并没有改变服务器。
It's just changing my copy.
它只是改变了我的副本。
But I can at least make that change.
但我至少可以进行这个更改。
You can do even fancier things where, if you click computed,
你可以做更多有趣的事情，例如，如果你点击 computed，
you can scroll down and figure out, OK, wait a minute.
你可以向下滚动，然后弄明白，等等。
It's white right now.
现在它是白色的。
That's the same thing as this, rgb(255, 255, 255).
这和 rgb(255, 255, 255) 一样。
That's the same thing as ffffff from weeks prior.
这和几周前使用的 ffffff 一样。
But I can click this little arrow and it will even show me where in Harvard CSS
但我可以点击这个小箭头，它甚至会显示给我在 Harvard CSS 中
that white color comes from.
白色来自哪里。
So if it's actually my site I can actually figure things out
所以如果它实际上是我的网站，我可以实际弄清楚
and make changes as well.
并进行更改。
So in short, if you find that you like the world of web development,
简而言之，如果你发现你喜欢 web 开发的世界，
in your own browser that you've had all this time,
在你一直使用的浏览器中，
there's so much darn functionality built in.
内置了如此多的功能。
And it's just up to you now to start experimenting with it,
现在就取决于你去尝试它，
exploring what you can actually do with it.
探索你实际上可以用它做什么。
But let us use our final moments today to introduce you to a final language
但让我们利用今天最后的时刻向你介绍一门最后的语言
called JavaScript, which is itself a proper programming language.
叫做 JavaScript，它本身是一门真正的编程语言。
And you're about to see a bunch of syntax that's
你将看到一堆语法，这些语法
kind of new, but kind of familiar.
有点新，但又有点熟悉。
And the goal here is not to teach you JavaScript per se,
这里我们的目标不是教你 JavaScript 本身，
but to begin to lay the foundation for you yourselves
而是为你自己开始打下学习一门新语言的基础。
learning a new language on your own.
自己学习一门新语言。
By the end of CS50, you will not have learned
在 CS50 课程结束时，你不会学到
all that is out there, certainly.
所有内容，当然。
And the goal here ultimately is to help you
这里的最终目标是帮助你
have a sense with a support structure in place, be it the humans
拥有一个有支撑结构的意识，无论是人类
or the [INAUDIBLE] involved that you can ask questions of along the way.
还是你一路上可以询问的 [INAUDIBLE]。
Let's go ahead and do this.
让我们继续做这件事。
In my directory index, I'm going to go into the source 8 directory
在我的目录索引中，我将进入 source 8 目录
where I've got all of today's examples ready to go.
这里我准备了今天的所有示例。
I'm going to go into VS Code's Explorer, where I can see all of those files.
我将进入 VS Code 的资源管理器，在这里我可以看到所有这些文件。
And in my source 8 directory, let me go ahead and open up
在我的 source 8 目录中，让我打开
hello version 1 dot HTML.
hello version 1.html。
Recall that the last time we played with hello.html, it was literally just HTML.
回想一下，我们上次使用 hello.html 时，它实际上只是 HTML。
But here's an example of a language called JavaScript.
但这里是一个叫做 JavaScript 的语言的例子。
And at this page, it's going to work as follows.
在这个页面上，它的工作原理如下。
If I open hello 1 dot html in my page, I have a very simple form.
如果我在页面中打开 hello 1.html，我有一个非常简单的表单。
Let me zoom in.
让我放大。
Let me type in my name, for instance, D-A-V-I-D, and hit Enter.
例如，让我输入我的名字，D-A-V-I-D，然后按回车键。
And voila!
然后，瞧！
This is not a very good user interface.
这不是一个很好的用户界面。
But you can see that this web page says, quote, unquote, hello, David.
但你可以看到这个网页上写着，“你好，David”。
So how did I get this form to trigger a pop up?
那么我怎样才能让这个表单触发弹出窗口呢？
Well, if I go into VS Code here, you'll see a web form.
好吧，如果我进入 VS Code，你会看到一个网页表单。
But I've added another attribute, namely an onsubmit attribute.
但我添加了另一个属性，即 onsubmit 属性。
And in the world of HTML, onsubmit allows
在 HTML 世界中，onsubmit 允许
you to write a tiny bit of JavaScript code inside of the quotes
你在引号内编写一小段 JavaScript 代码
that will be executed whenever the user submits this form.
这段代码将在用户提交表单时执行。
So what this is saying is call a function called greet
所以这句话的意思是调用一个名为 greet 的函数
and then return false.
然后返回 false。
And what return false means is that don't actually
而返回 false 的意思是不要实际
submit this form to the server, like keep the user on this page
将此表单提交到服务器，就像让用户留在当前页面
so we can just see a pop up.
这样我们就可以看到一个弹出窗口。
So what is this greet function?
那么这个 greet 函数是什么呢？
Well, it turns out, in the world of HTML,
事实证明，在 HTML 世界中，
there's not only a style tag you can put in your head of your page,
你不仅可以在页面头部添加一个 style 标签，
but also a script tag, inside of which is JavaScript code.
还可以添加一个 script 标签，其中包含 JavaScript 代码。
The syntax is a little different from Python and from C.
语法与 Python 和 C 略有不同。
But it's maybe a little closer to Python.
但可能与 Python 更接近一些。
Instead of def last week or two weeks ago,
与之前几周使用的 def 不同，
we'll now use function, literally, to begin the definition of a function.
我们现在使用 function，字面意思，来开始定义函数。
And if I want to call this function greet, so be it.
如果我想调用这个名为 greet 的函数，那就这样。
JavaScript comes with a function called alert.
JavaScript 带有一个名为 alert 的函数。
And so if I literally do alert, hello, quote, unquote, and then
所以如果我直接写 alert，hello，引号，引号，然后
plus something else, just like in Python, that's going to concatenate,
再加上其他东西，就像 Python 一样，它会连接
or join the two things left and right.
或将左右两边的两个东西拼接在一起。
But here's some functionality that comes with your browser, too.
但你的浏览器也提供了一些功能。
It turns out, per the notion of this whole page being a document,
事实证明，根据整个页面是文档的理念，
you can call document.queryselector, which
你可以调用 document.queryselector，它
allows you to select any of the tags or elements in the page,
允许你在页面中选择任何标签或元素，
specifically you can select the tag that has an ID of name.
具体来说，你可以选择 ID 为 name 的标签。
So CSS and JavaScript use the same syntax.
所以 CSS 和 JavaScript 使用相同的语法。
If you see hash something, that is referring to the ID of a tag
如果你看到井号加一些东西，那就是指你创建的标签的 ID
that you created.
。
If you then, after selecting the element of HTML with that unique ID,
如果你接着，在选择具有这个唯一 ID 的 HTML 元素后，
want its value, you just do dot value.
想要获取它的值，你只需使用点 value。
So we saw dots a lot in Python and in C to go inside of structures.
我们在 Python 和 C 中经常看到点，用来访问结构内部。
You can go inside of that text box and get its value.
你可以进入文本框并获取它的值。
So notice here if I scroll down, not only
所以注意，如果我向下滚动，不仅
am I using autocomplete and autofocus and so forth,
我使用了自动完成和自动聚焦等功能，
I also, for convenience, gave my input box a unique ID of name.
我还为了方便，给我的输入框添加了一个唯一的 ID，名为 name。
So what's effectively happening is, when I click Submit,
所以实际上发生的是，当我点击 Submit 时，
my JavaScript's greet function is called, it queries for that text box,
我的 JavaScript 的 greet 函数被调用，它会查询那个文本框，
goes inside of it and gets its value.
进入文本框并获取它的值。
And then, using this plus operator, just like in Python,
然后，使用这个加号运算符，就像 Python 一样，
concatenates the two together and passes them
将两者连接起来并传递
to this alert function for an underwhelming, but functional alert
给这个 alert 函数，它会弹出乏善可陈，但功能完整的警告
in the window.
窗口。
All right.
好的。
How else can we do this?
我们还能怎么做呢？
This is generally frowned upon to use onsubmit in this way.
这种使用 onsubmit 的方式通常不被推荐。
Generally speaking, the world does not like
一般来说，人们不喜欢
mixing attributes, rather JavaScript code with HTML so closely as this.
将属性，更确切地说 JavaScript 代码与 HTML 代码像这样紧密地混合在一起。
So let me show you another variant of this,
所以让我向你展示另一种变体，
even though it's going to look a little bit cryptic.
尽管它看起来有点神秘。
But at least it will be representative of how else you can solve this problem.
但至少它将代表你如何解决这个问题的其他方法。
In hello2.html, we have this code.
在 hello2.html 中，我们有这段代码。
Notice that at the top of my body now is the form.
请注意，现在我的 body 的顶部是表单。
But at the bottom of the body is this script tag.
但是，body 的底部是这个 script 标签。
So I've just moved it from head to the body of the page.
所以我只是把它从 head 移动到了 body 的底部。
Because I'm going to then instead do this.
因为我接下来要这样做。
If I want to tell the browser to listen for submissions of that form,
如果我想告诉浏览器监听那个表单的提交事件，
I can use this fairly cryptic syntax, but you'll see it again and again
我可以使用这种相当神秘的语法，但你将会反复看到它
over time as follows.
随着时间的推移，如下所示。
Go into the document.
进入文档。
Select with this query the form tag.
使用这个查询选择 form 标签。
And then call this special function that comes with the browser called
然后调用浏览器自带的这个特殊函数，称为
addEventListener.
addEventListener。
So tell the browser to listen for a certain type of event for this form.
所以告诉浏览器监听这个表单的特定事件类型。
What event do you want to listen for?
你想监听什么事件？
The submission of the form, so quote, unquote submit.
表单的提交，所以引号，引号 submit。
What do you want to have happen whenever that event is heard?
当听到那个事件时，你想让什么发生？
You want to call this function here.
你想调用这里定义的这个函数。
So this is what's known as an anonymous function.
所以这就是所谓的匿名函数。
The syntax is a little weird, but I've not given the function a name.
语法有点奇怪，但我没有给函数起名字。
It apparently takes an argument as input called event,
它显然接收一个名为 event 的参数作为输入，
but that's per the documentation.
但这属于文档规范。
And what these two lines of code do essentially
这两行代码本质上做的就是
is they still call the alert function.
仍然调用 alert 函数。
They still output hello comma space.
仍然输出 hello 逗号 空格。
And they still query the HTML for the ID name
并且仍然查询 HTML 的 ID name
to get the value that the humans typed in.
来获取用户输入的值。
And then just for good measure, we prevent the default behavior
然后为了保险起见，我们阻止了默认行为
for any form with this line of code, just so that it doesn't actually
对于使用这段代码的任何表单，以确保它不会实际
submit anything to the server.
提交任何内容到服务器。
It keeps the user actually here.
它实际上让用户停留在当前页面。
This will be a little scarier, too, but just so you've seen it.
这也会有点吓人，但这只是为了让你看到它。
In hello3.html, this is actually a more common technique.
在 hello3.html 中，这实际上是一种更常见的技术。
Whereby you can listen for one other special event.
它可以监听另一个特殊事件。
It turns out when you load a web page, lots of stuff has to happen.
事实证明，当你加载网页时，很多事情必须发生。
It's got to be read top to bottom, left to right.
它必须从上到下，从左到右读取。
It's got to download other files, the images, the sounds, the videos, and so
它必须下载其他文件，图片、声音、视频等等
forth.
。
If you want to wait until the whole page has been read into memory essentially,
如果你想等到整个页面被读入内存，
you can use this event as well, DOMContentLoaded.
你也可以使用这个事件，DOMContentLoaded。
That tree we drew earlier is what's called a DOM, document object model,
我们之前绘制的树被称为 DOM，文档对象模型，
which is just a fancy way of saying a tree in the computer's memory
这只是计算机内存中树的一种花哨的说法。
that represents the web page.
它代表着网页。
So this is the syntax that you'll find that people
所以，这是你将会发现人们
use to tell the browser once the whole DOM, the whole tree has been loaded,
用来告诉浏览器，一旦整个 DOM，整棵树加载完毕，
then go ahead and execute this code.
就继续执行这段代码。
And it means that no matter what, the whole web page will be ready in order
这意味着，无论如何，整个网页都会准备好，以
before this code is actually executed.
在这段代码实际执行之前。
And this ensures, for instance, that even
这确保了，例如，即使
though this script is at the top of my file
尽管这个脚本在我的文件顶部
and my form is at the bottom of my file, none of this code
而我的表单在我的文件底部，所有这些代码
will get executed until the whole DOM is ready, all of the HTML
都不会执行，直到整个 DOM 准备好，所有的 HTML
has been read top to bottom, left to right.
都已从上到下，从左到右读取完毕。
All right.
好的。
Well, let's go ahead and make this a little more interesting,
好吧，让我们继续让这个更有意思一点，
just to show you some of the capabilities of JavaScript
只是为了向你展示一些 JavaScript 的功能
within a browser nowadays.
在如今的浏览器中。
So if I open up maybe this one here, background.html.
所以，如果我打开这里，background.html。
And let me open it up in the browser.
让我在浏览器中打开它。
And this is going to be super simple in terms of user interface.
从用户界面来说，这将非常简单。
But here's a big white viewport, big body that's just white in color
但这里有一个大的白色视窗，一个大的主体，默认情况下是白色。
by default.
默认情况下。
But there's three buttons at top left.
但左上角有三个按钮。
And if I click R, it makes the background red.
如果我点击 R，它会将背景变成红色。
G makes the background green.
G 会将背景变成绿色。
And B makes the background blue.
而 B 会将背景变成蓝色。
What's interesting about this demo, sort of underwhelming
这个演示的有趣之处在于，从用户界面来看，它有点平淡无奇，因为它证明了你可以
as the user interface is, is it demonstrates that you
使用 JavaScript 修改 CSS。
can modify CSS using JavaScript.
HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 在浏览器环境中因此
And HTML, CSS, and JavaScript are therefore
非常交织在一起。
very intertwined in the context of a browser.
怎么做？
How?
这里是原始的 HTML 代码。
Here's the raw HTML.
这是三个按钮。
Here are the three buttons.
我给他们分别设置了三个 ID，red、green 和 blue，
And I've given them three separate IDs red, green, and blue,
以便我可以引用特定的按钮。
just so I can refer to the specific button.
注意我在这里做了什么。
And notice what I've done here.
我在 JavaScript 中声明了一个变量，它
I've declared a variable in JavaScript, which
使用了稍微不同的语法，let 作为关键字。
uses slightly different syntax of let as the keyword.
而不是 int 或 char 或 string，你可以
Instead of int or char or string, you can
使用 let 关键字，它本质上意味着让我
use the keyword let, which essentially means let
创建一个名为 body 的变量。
me create this variable called body.
这只是如何使用查询选择器
And this is just how, using query selector,
从网页中选择 body 元素。
I can select the body element from the web page.
因为我将它分别使用三次。
Because I'm going to use it three separate times.
我想分别做三次什么？
What do I want to do three separate times?
例如，这个。
For instance, this.
我想进入文档，并选择具有唯一 ID "red" 的元素。
I want to go into the document and select whatever
我想告诉浏览器监听这个事件，点击。
element has the unique ID of red.
我们之前看到了提交。
I want to tell the browser to listen for this event, click.
你也可以监听点击事件。
So we saw submit before.
当在这个按钮上发生点击事件时，我希望这个函数被调用。
You can listen for clicks as well.
这个函数做了什么？
When the click happens on this button, I want this function to be called.
它做了非常非常简单的事情 -
What does this function do?
它只是将 body 的样式，背景颜色
Something super, super simple--
更改为 "红色"。
all it does is it changes the body's styles, background color
所以这里发生了什么？
to be, quote, unquote red instead.
我们之前没有看到这个。
So what's going on here?
但事实证明，在 CSS 中，确实
We didn't see this earlier.
有一个叫做 background-color 的 CSS 属性。
But it turns out in CSS there is actually
我可以看到如下。
a CSS property called background-color.
让我重新加载这个页面。
And I can see it as follows.
打开浏览器的检查器。
Let me reload this page.
打开元素。
Open the browser's inspector.
如果我把鼠标悬停在 body 上，注意
Open up elements.
默认情况下没有背景颜色。
And if I hover over the body here, notice
但如果我在里面做，比如，小写，background color: yellow，
that there's no background color by default.
它会立即将背景更改为黄色。
But if I do in, say, lowercase, background color colon yellow,
不幸的是，在 JavaScript 中，你不能使用 background-color。
it immediately changes the background to yellow.
这可能是为什么？
Unfortunately, in JavaScript, you can't do background dash color.
是的？
Why might this be?
观众：[听不清]。
Yeah?
大卫·马兰：它认为是减号或减法。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
对吧？
DAVID MALAN: It thinks it's minus or subtraction.
所以，我敢打赌，在某个时候，设计 JavaScript 的人意识到，该死。
Right?
我们不应该在 CSS 中使用连字符。
So I would wager there was a human at some point in the room designing
因为它现在将被错误地解释为 JavaScript 中的减法运算符。
JavaScript where they realized like, damn it.
所以，JavaScript 世界解决这个问题的方法是，任何在 CSS 中使用连字符的属性
We shouldn't have used a hyphen in CSS.
比如 background-color，你把它在 JavaScript 版本中
Because it's now going to be misinterpreted as a subtraction
更改为驼峰式命名法，可以这么说，在中间有一个驼峰
operator in JavaScript.
它是一个大写 C，没有连字符，而不是小写 C。
So the way the JavaScript world solved this was whatever has a hyphen in it
我在此处做到了，我也在此处做到了，以便
as background dash color, you change it in the JavaScript version
本质上监听三个按钮中的任何一个的点击事件，
thereof to be camelcase, so to speak, whereby there's this hump in the middle
这样，最终的结果就是它会根据我的点击，将颜色从红色更改为绿色，再更改为蓝色。
with it's a capital C, no hyphen, instead of a lowercase C instead.
这就是开发者工具变得很酷的地方。
And I do this here, and I do this here so
注意，在右下角，当我点击它时，
as to essentially listen for a click on any of those three buttons
页面右下角的 CSS 会发生变化，
so that the end result is that it changes it from red to green to blue
以匹配正在发生的事情。
based on what I'm clicking.
所以你真的可以看到并理解它内部发生了什么。
And here's where the developer tools get kind of cool.
好的。
Notice at bottom right here, notice that as I click on this,
我们还有时间进行一些其他演示。
the CSS of the page at bottom right is changing
在我学 HTML 的时候，有很多很丑陋的标签
to match whatever is happening.
仍然在流通。
So you can really see and understand what's going on underneath that hood
其中之一是 blink 标签，它实际上
there.
如果你使用 blink 并将文字放在它的开始标签和结束标签之间，
All right.
你就会在屏幕上看到文字在这样闪烁。
We have time for a few other demonstrations.
更丑陋的是所谓的 marquee 标签，它实际上
Back in my day when I learned HTML, there was a bunch of hideous tags
会
still in circulation.
Among them was a blink tag, which literally,
if you used blink and put words in between its open tag and close tag,
you would get text on your screen just kind of doing this.
Even uglier was what was called the marquee tab, which would actually
scroll text across the screen like this.
像这样在屏幕上滚动文字。
And no self-respecting website tends to have blinking text or scrolling
任何有自尊的网站都不会有闪烁的文字或滚动的
text in this way.
文字。
Because it's just tends to be ugly.
因为这通常很丑。
However, even though the blink tag is among the few tags that's
然而，即使 blink 标签是为数不多的几个从语言中删除的标签之一，你仍然可以
ever been removed from the language, you can bring it back
把它带回来
with a bit of JavaScript.
用一些 JavaScript。
So here, for instance, is an example in blink.html.
所以这里，例如，是 blink.html 中的一个例子。
Here's a super simple page.
这是一个超级简单的页面。
The only thing in the body is hello, world.
主体中唯一的文字是 hello, world。
But there is a script tag up in my head of my page here.
但是这里我的页面头部有一个 script 标签。
And let's see what's inside of this script tag.
我们来看看这个 script 标签里面是什么。
Well, I've defined on line 8 downward, a function called blink.
好吧，我在第 8 行以下定义了一个名为 blink 的函数。
What does it do?
它做什么？
Well.
好吧。
I first declare a variable called body.
我首先声明一个名为 body 的变量。
And I get the body element using queryselector.
然后我使用 queryselector 获取 body 元素。
I then ask this question.
然后我问这个问题。
If the body's styles visibility property,
如果 body 的样式可见性属性，
which we haven't talked about yet is quote,
我们还没有讨论过，是引号，
unquote, hidden, then change the body's styles visibility property
引号，隐藏，那么更改 body 的样式可见性属性
to be, quote, unquote, visible.
为，引号，引号，可见。
Else, if it's not hidden, that is it's visible, change it to hidden instead.
否则，如果它没有隐藏，也就是说它是可见的，改为隐藏。
And here, too, this is another one of these left-hand, right-hand situations.
这里也是，这也是另一种左手、右手的情况。
I do not know why the opposite of visible is not invisible.
我不知道为什么可见的反义词不是不可见。
It is, instead, hidden.
而是隐藏。
So, again, arguably poor design, but this is what we have.
所以，再次，可以说设计很糟糕，但这就是我们拥有的。
How is this useful?
这有什么用？
Well, there turns out.
好吧，事实证明。
In your browser, there's a JavaScript function
在你的浏览器中，有一个 JavaScript 函数
called setinterval that's associated not with the document per se,
叫做 setinterval，它与文档本身无关，
but the window, which is another global variable that you just
而是窗口，它是另一个全局变量，你只需
get automatic access to in the browser that
在浏览器中自动访问它，它
allows you to call a function, any number of milliseconds, again
允许你调用一个函数，任何毫秒数，再次
and again and again.
一次又一次。
So if I want my text to blink every half a second or 500 milliseconds,
所以如果我想让我的文字每半秒或 500 毫秒闪烁一次，
I just use window.setinterval to call blink every 500 milliseconds.
我只需要使用 window.setinterval 每 500 毫秒调用 blink 一次。
And notice, it's very important not to call blink here, as with parentheses,
请注意，这里不要使用括号调用 blink，
like in C or Python.
就像在 C 或 Python 中一样。
Because I don't want to call blink at this moment in time.
因为我不想在此时调用 blink。
I just want to inform the setinterval function
我只想通知 setinterval 函数
of the name of the blink function.
blink 函数的名称。
So I just pass in the name blink.
所以我只传递 blink 的名称。
And if I go back to my directory listing, I open up blink.html,
如果我回到我的目录列表，打开 blink.html，
you'll see what I used to see in the late '90s, when HTML 1 was
你会看到我在 90 年代后期看到的东西，当时 HTML 1 是
all the rage, like at the beginnings of a ugly websites,
最流行的，就像丑陋网站的开始一样，
including my own personal home page at the time.
包括我自己当时的主页。
My own personal home page, too, at the time,
我自己当时的主页也是，
which is probably findable somewhere online in the archives,
可能可以在网上某个地方的档案中找到，
it was back in the days where you wouldn't just
那是在你不会只是
show people the content of your page.
向人们展示你页面的内容的时代。
You had to click a Enter button to enter the web
你必须点击一个 Enter 按钮才能进入网页
page and just really ridiculous.
页面，真是太荒谬了。
There's a lot of things in tech that you can do, but should not do.
技术中有许多事情你可以做，但你不应该做。
And the world has learned this as have I, the hard way.
世界已经认识到这一点，我也是，而且付出了惨痛的代价。
All right.
好的。
Let's do a couple of final examples that are now
让我们做几个最后的例子，它们现在
representative of what modern websites do
代表了现代网站所做的事情
and what you and I take for granted on web apps and mobile apps alike.
以及你和我在网络应用和移动应用上都习以为常的事情。
For instance, this feature of autocomplete.
例如，自动完成这个功能。
Case in point, when I went to google.com before
举个例子，当我以前去 google.com 的时候
and I started searching for cats or dogs or birds,
我开始搜索猫、狗或鸟，
it was trying to finish my thought and populating a dropdown
它试图完成我的想法，并填充一个下拉菜单
with a bunch of different suggestions.
提供了一堆不同的建议。
I can actually do that myself in JavaScript as follows.
我实际上可以使用 JavaScript 如下操作。
Let me open up a file called large.js, which
让我打开一个名为 large.js 的文件，它
is a file that I made based on speller's own dictionary.
是一个基于拼写器自己的字典创建的文件。
Recall that we gave you a big list of words, like 100,000 plus words.
请回忆，我们给你一个很大的单词列表，大约有 10 万个单词。
I copied those into this JavaScript file.
我把它们复制到这个 JavaScript 文件中。
But I formatted them in what's called the JavaScript array.
但我用 JavaScript 数组的格式对它们进行了格式化。
So JavaScript has arrays.
所以 JavaScript 有数组。
They're more like Python lists than they are like C arrays.
它们更像 Python 列表，而不是 C 数组。
The syntax is square brackets.
语法是方括号。
Let is my keyword to say give me a variable called
let 是我的关键字，意思是给我一个名为
WORDS, which is all caps because I'm going to use it globally.
WORDS 的变量，它全部大写，因为我将在全局范围内使用它。
And here is a 100,000 words from that dictionary in this file.
这里就是这个文件中来自该字典的 10 万个单词。
All right?
好的？
Now let me close this file and open up the actual HTML
现在让我关闭这个文件，打开真正的 HTML
file, autocomplete.html.
文件，autocomplete.html。
Let me scroll down to the bottom.
让我滚动到最底部。
And you'll see that in this page in the body are two things.
你会看到，在这个页面的主体中，有两样东西。
One, an input, so a text box so I can start typing words.
一个是输入框，所以我可以开始输入文字。
And then, two, an unordered list that's empty.
然后，第二个，一个空的无序列表。
So there's no actual list items in that unordered list initially,
所以最初在这个无序列表中没有实际的列表项，
but there is a lot of JavaScript.
但是有很多 JavaScript。
Here's how I'm including the large dictionary.
这是我包含大型字典的方式。
And here's how I'm implementing autocomplete.
这是我实现自动完成的方式。
So let me first show you what this does.
所以让我先给你看看它做了什么。
Let me go back to my directory index, click on autocomplete.html.
让我回到我的目录索引，点击 autocomplete.html。
I'll zoom in.
我会放大。
And if I type in C, I immediately get an unordered list of all words
如果我输入 C，我会立即得到一个以 C 开头的所有单词的无序列表。
starting with C.
以 C 开头。
If I type CA, it gets filtered further.
如果我输入 CA，它会进一步过滤。
But we can't see the difference because there's so many words starting with CA.
但我们看不到区别，因为以 CA 开头的单词太多了。
CAT, the list is changing.
CAT，列表正在改变。
CATS, the list is changing.
CATS，列表正在改变。
And notice that if I were to open my developer tools, what
请注意，如果我打开我的开发者工具，
gets really interesting is you can see this list being made in real time.
真正有趣的地方在于，你可以看到这个列表是实时生成的。
Let me delete it.
让我删除它。
Notice that the UL at bottom left is now empty.
请注意，左下角的 UL 现在是空的。
But if I type in suddenly CATS, notice that the triangle appears and there
但是，如果我突然输入 CATS，你会注意到三角形出现了，而且
are all of the list items that my JavaScript code is apparently
都是我的 JavaScript 代码显然
dynamically creating.
动态创建的。
And indeed, how do I do this?
确实，我是如何做到的？
Well, this one's more of a mouthful, but here's the idea.
好吧，这个有点难说，但这是想法。
I used a queryselector function to get that input text box.
我使用了一个 queryselector 函数来获取那个输入文本框。
I then add a listener to that input, listening for what's called key up.
然后，我在那个输入框上添加一个监听器，监听一个称为 key up 的事件。
It turns out you can listen for the finger going down
事实证明，你可以监听手指按下
or the finger going up.
或者手指抬起。
So I'm waiting until the user lifts their finger off the keyboard, AKA,
所以，我等待用户将手指从键盘上抬起，也就是
key up.
key up。
When it hears that event, it should do the following.
当它听到该事件时，它应该执行以下操作。
It's going to create a variable, a temp variable called HTML equal to quote,
它将创建一个变量，一个名为 HTML 的临时变量，它等于引号，
unquote nothing.
引号内什么也没有。
In JavaScript, as an aside, you can use single quotes
顺便说一下，在 JavaScript 中，你可以使用单引号
or double quotes for whatever reasons stylistically, JavaScript programmers
或双引号，无论出于何种样式原因，JavaScript 程序员
tend to use single quotes.
倾向于使用单引号。
I can then say if that input has a value, because the humans typed
然后，我可以说，如果该输入框有值，因为人类输入了
in one or more letters, then iterate over
一个或多个字母，那么迭代
all of the words in the dictionary.
字典中的所有单词。
And we've not seen of before, but it's Javascript's equivalent
我们以前没见过，但它是 JavaScript 等同于
of Python's for loop.
Python 中的 for 循环。
If that word starts with whatever the input value is, go ahead and add--
如果那个单词以输入框的值开头，就继续添加 -
that is concatenate to the HTML variable and open tag LI.
也就是说，将它连接到 HTML 变量，并打开 LI 标签。
Then, whatever the word is, using this JavaScript specific syntax, and then
然后，无论单词是什么，使用这种 JavaScript 特定的语法，然后
close the tag.
关闭标签。
And then lastly, using queryselector, grab the UL tag,
最后，使用 queryselector，获取 UL 标签，
go into its inner HTML, so to speak, inside of it,
进入它的内部 HTML，可以这么说，在它内部，
and change it to be this HTML I just created.
并将其更改为我刚刚创建的这个 HTML。
And so in this way, using JavaScript, I can dynamically add to
因此，通过这种方式，使用 JavaScript，我可以动态地添加到
and subtract from the HTML in the page.
并从页面中的 HTML 中减去。
There are so many other events here, too, clicking, submitting, key up,
这里还有很多其他事件，比如点击、提交、key up、
dragging, and dropping, and so forth.
拖放等等。
This is just some of the events that web pages and mobile apps can listen for.
这仅仅是网页和移动应用程序可以监听的部分事件。
But we'll do one final one, which speaks to the power of browsers nowadays
但我们将演示最后一个，它说明了如今浏览器的强大功能
and even the implications for privacy.
甚至对隐私的影响。
If I go into geolocation.html, it turns out
如果我进入 geolocation.html，事实证明
you can figure out where in the world a user is with, like, three lines of code
你可以用大约三行代码找出用户在世界上的位置
nowadays, assuming they've turned on location services
现在，假设他们已开启位置服务
and opted in on their device.
并同意在他们的设备上使用。
Here, albeit cryptically, is a final global variable
这里，虽然比较隐晦，但有一个最终的全局变量
that comes with browsers today called navigator.
它随今天的浏览器一起提供，叫做 navigator。
It has a geolocation object associated with it,
它关联了一个 geolocation 对象，
which comes with a function called getCurrentPosition.
它带有一个名为 getCurrentPosition 的函数。
You can then specify or figure out the user's latitude and the user's
然后，你可以指定或找出用户的纬度和用户的
longitude.
经度。
And all I'm going to do is write these to the screen
我要做的就是将这些写入屏幕
so I can see this demonstration live.
这样我就可以看到这个实时演示。
So our very final demonstration here of JavaScript
所以，我们对 JavaScript 的最后一个演示将是这里
is going to be this one here for geolocation to show you how easy
关于地理位置的演示，向你展示它有多容易
and how invasive even code can be if I click on geolocation and wait.
即使代码也可以很侵入性，如果我点击地理位置并等待。
There are my GPS coordinates, latitude and longitude.
那就是我的 GPS 坐标，纬度和经度。
And to confirm as much roughly, let's go ahead and open up a browser,
为了大致确认这一点，让我们打开一个浏览器，
paste in those coordinates, click on the Google Maps result that comes up first.
粘贴那些坐标，点击第一个出现的 Google 地图结果。
Zoom in, in, turn on satellite mode.
放大，放大，打开卫星模式。
And in-- and I'm not quite in that corner of the building.
然后，我并不完全在那栋楼的角落里。
But I'm presumably close to an access point that Google has known about
但我可能靠近 Google 知道的某个接入点
and associates with my GPS coordinates.
并与我的 GPS 坐标相关联。
It's that easy when you actually use something like Uber or Lyft or the like
当你实际使用 Uber、Lyft 或类似的应用程序时，就那么容易
to figure out where the user is by just asking their browser via code
通过代码询问他们的浏览器来确定用户的位置
like this.
就像这样。
So that's it for HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
所以，关于 HTML、CSS 和 JavaScript 就介绍到这里。
In the problem set, you'll explore all of these.
在作业中，你将探索所有这些。
One more lecture to go in which we'll combine all of these.
还有一节课，我们将把所有这些结合起来。
But until then we'll see you next time.
但在此之前，我们下期再见。
[MUSIC PLAYING] Buffering, OK.
[音乐播放] 正在缓冲，好了。
Josh, nice.
乔希，不错。
[INAUDIBLE], oh!
[听不清]，哦！
[LAUGHING]
[笑声]
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
No, oh, wait.
不，哦，等等。
That was amazing, Josh.
太棒了，乔希。
Sophie!
索菲！
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Amazing.
太棒了。
That was perfect.
太完美了。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I think I--
我想我 -
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众： [听不清]。
DAVID MALAN: Guy.
大卫·马兰： 伙计。
That was amazing.
太棒了。
Thank you all.
谢谢大家。
AUDIENCE: Good.
观众： 好。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]